python is the world's most popular programming language and that is for a
python是世界上最流行的编程语言，这是一个
reason you can use it to make games and apps run databases build robots and
你可以用它来制作游戏的原因应用程序运行数据库构建机器人
create artificial intelligence with ease the example you see right now is an ai
轻松创造人工智能你现在看到的例子是一个人工智能
program that tracks my face it took me about five minutes to write
追踪我脸部的程序大约五分钟写
and that is a general theme for python it is incredibly easy to learn while
这是 python 的一般主题它非常容易学习，同时
also giving you a ton of power for more advanced functionalities and all of this
还为您提供更多动力先进的功能和所有这一切
you're going to learn in this video starting from scratch
你将在这个视频中学到从头开始
i am assuming that you have never used any kind of programming language before
我假设你从未使用过之前任何一种编程语言
so we are starting all the way from the bottom and over the next 10 or so hours
所以我们一路从底部以及接下来的 10 个小时左右
you are going to learn basically everything you need to know about python
你基本上会学到关于 python 你需要知道的一切
and after that you can learn pretty much whatever you want in the language and it
之后你可以学到很多东西无论你想要什么语言和它
should be fairly straightforward as a matter of fact this video is part
应该相当简单事实上这个视频是一部分
of a larger paid course and this one is going to use all of the stuff you're
一个更大的付费课程，这个是将使用你所有的东西
learning about python and uses it to make four games and that way you are
学习Python并使用它制作四款游戏，这样你就可以了
learning in much more detail how to actually use all of this in practice
更详细地学习如何在实践中实际使用所有这些
so check this one out if you're interested although this entire video
所以如果你是的话，请检查一下这个虽然整个视频很感兴趣
works by itself and you can use it for any other non-gaming purpose as well
可以单独工作，您可以将其用于以及任何其他非游戏目的
it's a general introduction to python before we start the program we need to
这是对 python 的一般介绍在我们开始程序之前我们需要
cover some fundamentals first of all if you are just getting into programming
首先涵盖一些基础知识如果你刚刚开始编程
you are probably overwhelmed by choice besides python you could learn a few
你可能对选择不知所措除了python之外你还可以学一些
hundred other programming languages some have clear names like html5 or java
一百种其他编程语言 一些有明确的名称，例如 html5 或 java
while others are much more difficult to separate like c c sharp and c plus plus
而其他的则困难得多像 c c Sharp 和 c plus plus 一样分开
so what makes each language different and where should you start
那么是什么让每种语言有所不同你应该从哪里开始
also how does python compare to these other languages
python 与这些相比如何其他语言
one good way to separate these languages is by using two axes
分离这些语言的一种好方法是通过使用两个轴
the first one is about the language being made for a specific purpose or if
第一个是关于语言的是为了特定目的而制造的，或者如果
it is more open-ended for example sql and r are programming languages for
它更加开放，例如 sql和 r 是编程语言
highly specific purposes databases and data analysis respectively
高度特定的目的分别是数据库和数据分析
on the other side you have languages like python that can also analyze data
另一边你有语言像python一样也可以分析数据
and run databases but can do a lot more besides that
并运行数据库，但可以做更多的事情除此之外
this flexibility is one of the reasons why python is so popular it just can do
这种灵活性是原因之一为什么Python如此受欢迎，它就可以做到
a ton of different things although this line is not static the
有很多不同的东西虽然这条线不是静态的
best example for that is html initially it was purely a language to make
最好的例子最初是 html它纯粹是一种语言
websites it was very much designed for a single purpose however over time people
它的网站很大程度上是为目的单一但随着时间的推移人们
kept on adding more to it and nowadays you can make apps and games with html
不断添加更多内容，如今你可以用 html 制作应用程序和游戏
it became much more flexible and that is the main reason why modern websites are
它变得更加灵活，那就是现代网站的主要原因
as powerful as they are the other axis is the level of
和他们一样强大另一个轴是水平
abstraction now when i say a language is more
抽象现在当我说语言更重要时
abstract than another i don't mean to say it's more complex instead
比另一个抽象，我不是故意的说它更复杂
abstraction refers to how far removed a language is from physical computer
抽象指的是距离多远语言来自物理计算机
hardware let's use html again
硬件让我们再次使用 html
to see a website written in html5 you first need a browser like chrome or
看到一个用 html5 编写的网站首先需要一个浏览器，例如 chrome 或
safari that browser in turn runs on an operating system and only that operating
Safari 浏览器又运行在操作系统并且仅该操作系统
system has access to actual physical computer hardware there is a huge
系统可以访问实际物理计算机硬件有一个巨大的
distance between the html code and the computer it runs on
html 代码与 html 代码之间的距离它运行的计算机
that means html is a very abstract language
这意味着 html 是一个非常抽象的语言
this however does not mean that html is more difficult than a less abstract
但这并不意味着 html 是比不那么抽象的更困难
language quite the opposite actually in broad terms the more abstract a language
语言实际上恰恰相反语言越抽象，术语就越宽泛
is the easier it is to use that is because a less abstract language
是越容易使用那是因为一种不太抽象的语言
needs to work with computer hardware it needs to be very specific about memory
需要与计算机硬件配合使用需要非常具体地了解记忆
management you sometimes have to write for different kinds of computer hardware
管理你有时必须写适用于不同类型的计算机硬件
and generally it is very easy to break things
而且一般很容易坏事物
now in this axis python like html is a very abstract language in fact python
现在在这个轴上 python 像 html 是实际上是非常抽象的语言 python
itself was created using another programming languages that one is called
本身是使用另一个创建的一种称为的编程语言
c and this language is much less abstract
C这种语言不那么抽象
generally in the bottom right of this graph you have all of the c languages
一般在这个的右下角图表你拥有所有的c语言
like c c sharp and c plus plus you also have java down there the differences
像 c c Sharp 和 c plus plus 你也有java下面的差异
between them are mostly technical and you don't really have to worry about
他们之间主要是技术性的你真的不必担心
them at least for now that being said c-sharp was only created because
至少目前来说c-sharp 的创建只是因为
microsoft didn't want to pay license fees to the creators of java these two
微软不想支付许可费向 java 这两个的创建者收费
languages are very similar so there can be a ton of overlap between these
语言非常相似，所以可以这些之间有很多重叠
different languages they are not entirely unique
它们不是不同的语言完全独特
now when you are just getting started you want to begin in the top right of
现在当你刚刚开始时你想从右上角开始
this graph with more abstract general purpose languages
该图具有更抽象的一般性目的语言
these are easy to learn work everywhere there's a huge community for support and
这些都是很容易学习的工作，随处可见有一个庞大的社区提供支持和
resources and you can use them for a huge variety
资源你可以将它们用于各种各样的用途
of projects what you also want to be aware of is
项目数你还想知道的是
that all programming languages are somewhat similar if you know python for
所有编程语言都是如果你了解 python 的话有点类似
example you can learn c or sql much more easily
例如，您可以学习更多 c 或 sql容易地
this is actually a really common pattern people start programming in python and
这实际上是一种非常常见的模式人们开始用 python 编程
then migrate to another language python was actually designed to be a
然后迁移到另一种语言python 实际上被设计成
tool to learn programming itself and it just happened to expand over time to
学习编程本身及其的工具只是随着时间的推移而扩大到
become a really popular languages by itself
成为一种真正流行的语言本身
although that doesn't mean that you couldn't stick with python
虽然这并不意味着你无法坚持使用Python
especially for data science think of artificial intelligence databases and
特别是对于数据科学来说人工智能数据库和
data analysis python very often is the default choice and these are fields
数据分析Python经常是默认选择，这些是字段
where you can earn a lot of money it is totally fine to stick with python by
在那里你可以赚很多钱完全可以坚持使用 python
itself entirely for your entire career lots of people do that
完全为了你的整个职业生涯很多人都这么做
but generally if you are not sure yet what language you want to go for don't
但一般来说如果你还不确定你想选择什么语言而不是
worry about it what you're learning in python can very easily be migrated to
担心你正在学什么python 可以很容易地迁移到
another language what you want to do is just get started
另一种语言你想做的只是开始
somewhere and work on projects you like and see how far you get
在某个地方从事你喜欢的项目看看你能走多远
and if you feel like changing you can totally do that and not start from
如果你想改变你可以完全这样做而不是从
scratch a lot of things you are going to learn you can use in other languages as
刮掉很多你要去的东西学习您可以使用其他语言作为
well you are always going to make some
出色地你总是会做一些
progress even if you are switching alright in this video we are going to
即使您正在切换，也会取得进展好吧，在这个视频中我们将
install python and the main target of this session is to write hello world
安装 python 和主要目标这次会话是写hello world
using python now this task you can approach in two
使用Python现在这个任务你可以分两次完成
ways number one you can do all of this on
方法第一，你可以做这一切
your computer and this is going to be the main way if you want to use python
你的电脑，这将是如果你想使用 python 的主要方法
normally you want it to be installed on your computer now that being said you
通常你希望它安装在话虽这么说，你的电脑
can also run python online and for that you don't have to install anything
还可以在线运行 python你不需要安装任何东西
if you just want to have a quick look at python and check if you like it i would
如果您只是想快速浏览一下python 并检查你是否喜欢它我会
recommend to just run python online for now and then if you decide that you do
建议在线运行 python时不时如果你决定这样做
like it you can install it properly so let's start with some websites that let
喜欢它就可以正确安装它让我们从一些网站开始
you run python code there are quite a few actually
你运行 python 代码有相当多的实际上很少
here for example we have one website called programmist.com and this one lets
例如，我们有一个网站叫做programmist.com，这个让
you run python code online besides that you could also use other languages like
除此之外，你还可以在线运行 python 代码您还可以使用其他语言，例如
c c plus javascript and quite a few more but in our case i want to get rid of all
c c 加上 javascript 以及更多但在我们的例子中我想摆脱所有
the code in here and to print anything in python
代码在这里并用 python 打印任何内容
remember we want to write the word hello world
记住我们要写“你好”这个词世界
and to print this you have to do a couple of things first of all you have
要打印这个你必须做首先你有几件事
to put this entire phrase into quotation marks could either
把这整个短语放入引号可以
be single or double quotation marks and for now just follow along i will explain
是单引号或双引号并且现在就跟着我来解释一下
all of this in much more detail later on but now that you have this word it
稍后将详细介绍所有这些内容但现在你有了这个词
should be green and what you have to do now is write
应该是绿色的你现在要做的就是写
print and then put the quotation mark phrase
打印然后将短语放在引号中
inside of brackets which means we first of all have the word print then we have
括号内这意味着我们首先全部都有印刷字，那么我们就有
a bracket then we have hello world in quotation
一个括号然后我们在引用中有 hello world
marks and then we have a closing bracket
标记然后我们有一个右括号
and if you have all of this you can click on run
如果你拥有这一切你就可以单击运行
and now you get hello world if you could follow along so far you have written
现在你会得到 hello world 如果可以的话到目前为止你已经写了
your first python code and if you don't want to install anything on your
你的第一个 python 代码，如果你不这样做想要在你的电脑上安装任何东西
computer or register for anything this website here would be really really good
计算机或注册任何东西这里的网站真的非常好
so this is definitely something i would recommend you can also make it a bit
所以这绝对是我想要的建议你也可以做一点
larger that's a bit easier to read besides that there is also a website
更大一点更容易阅读除此之外还有一个网站
called rapple.8 or replit i'm never sure how to pronounce it
叫 rapple.8 或 replit 我不确定怎么发音
in here you also have an online editor that you can use for python here we
在这里你还有一个在线编辑器你可以在这里使用 python
already have print hello world if i run this we get hello world for this one to
如果我运行，已经打印出 hello world这是我们为这个人打招呼的世界
use it properly you do have to register although it is a bit more powerful but
正确使用它你必须注册虽然它的威力有点大但是
both of these are really good to get started using python although keep in
这两个都非常好得到开始使用 python，尽管保持在
mind you are running all of this in a browser which is somewhat limiting what
请注意，您正在运行所有这些浏览器这在一定程度上限制了
you ultimately want to do is run python on your own computer that way you have
你最终想做的是运行 python在你自己的电脑上这样你就可以
significantly more power and you also have more flexibility so this is what we
显着增加功率，并且您还有更多的灵活性，所以这就是我们
want to do now for that we have to install python on your computer and the
我们现在想做的就是在你的电脑上安装 python 并
important thing to understand here is that python is just another program that
这里要理解的重要一点是python 只是另一个程序
you have to install on your computer it's working basically like word or
你必须安装在你的电脑上它的工作原理基本上就像单词或
excel or literally any video game and the file you have to install you get
excel 或任何电子游戏以及您必须安装的文件
from python.org so let's have a look at this one
来自 python.org 所以让我们看一下这个
here we have the python website and what you have to do is click on downloads and
这里我们有 python 网站以及什么你所要做的就是点击下载并
in here you want to download python and then the latest version right now this
在这里你想下载 python 并那么现在最新的版本是这个
is 3.10.5 by the time you are watching this
是3.10.5 当你看到这个的时候
there's probably a higher number but that isn't going to make much of a
可能有更高的数字但是这不会有多大作用
difference so click on download and then you get the file downloaded and this is
差异所以点击下载然后你得到下载的文件，这是
going to work with your specific operating system in my case i have
将根据您的具体情况进行工作就我而言，我有操作系统
windows but if you have a mac this would also work although you would get a
Windows 但如果你有 Mac，这会也可以工作，尽管你会得到一个
slightly different file and once you have that you click on open
文件略有不同完成后，单击“打开”
file and now you get either install now or
文件现在您可以立即安装或
customize installation however before you do anything in here there is
但是自定义安装在你在这里做任何事情之前
one incredibly important thing and that you can see down here it says add python
一件非常重要的事情你可以在这里看到它说添加 python
3.10 to path this is an incredibly important option
3.10 路径这是一个非常重要的选择
that you absolutely have to take this one you really want to add i will
你绝对必须接受你真的想添加这个，我会的
explain later why this is important but do keep in mind this is incredibly
稍后解释为什么这很重要但是请记住，这是令人难以置信的
important if you don't add this you are going to run into a ton of problems
重要的是如果你不添加这个你就是会遇到很多问题
but besides that you can leave everything as it is and then click on
但除此之外你可以离开一切保持原样，然后单击
install now then you get an installation
现在安装然后你就得到了安装
and this one is going to work like literally any other program so just wait
这个的工作原理就像几乎任何其他程序，所以只需等待
until it finishes and you should be good to go
直到它完成，你应该很好去
there we go the setup was successful now we can close it and
现在设置成功了我们可以关闭它
nothing changed however now what you can do if you press
没有改变但是现在如果你按下你可以做什么
the windows key you can type python and you have python 3.10 installed on your
windows 键你可以输入 python 并你已经安装了 python 3.10
computer if you run this you get something like
电脑如果你运行这个你会得到类似的东西
this in here you can write whatever you want for example what you could be
在这里你可以写任何你想写的东西例如你想要成为什么样的人
writing is what we have already seen you can write
写作是我们已经看到的可以写
print then in quotation marks hello world
打印然后用引号括起来 hello world
close the bracket and now if you press enter you get hello world and this was
合上支架，现在如果你按输入你好世界，这是
done using python in here you could also write something
使用Python完成在这里你还可以写一些东西
like one plus two you would get the result
就像一加二你会得到结果
and you can do quite a bit more but this is basically valid python
你还可以做更多的事情，但是这个基本上是有效的 python
so with that we have basic python code although the limitation here is that we
这样我们就有了基本的Python代码尽管这里的限制是我们
can only ever write a single line of code which well isn't great what we need
只能写一行代码不太符合我们的需要
is some kind of code editor and that we are going to cover in the next video
是某种代码编辑器，我们将在下一个视频中介绍
because this is a slightly larger section
因为这是一个稍微大一点的部分
and just to make sure that everybody can follow here i have mac os
只是为了确保每个人都能关注这里 我有 mac 操作系统
in there i still have to click on download python and now i'm downloading
在那里我仍然需要点击下载 python，现在我正在下载
a pkg file other than that i can click on open file
一个 pkg 文件除此之外我可以点击打开文件
and now we're getting a python installer that messed with my window sorry about
现在我们得到了一个 python 安装程序弄乱了我的窗户，抱歉
that but in here you click on continue you click on continue continue more
但在这里你点击继续您点击“继续”继续更多
you click on agree and then you click on install
您点击同意，然后点击安装
now you need your password as always install software
现在你需要密码一如既往地安装软件
and then you're just installing anything for mac os you don't have to worry about
然后你只需安装任何东西对于 mac os 你不必担心
a path and now here you can see all of my
一条路径现在你可以在这里看到我的全部
programs and i have python 3.10
程序，我有 python 3.10
although just wait a second and there we go now the entire thing finished i can
虽然等一下，我们就在那里现在走吧，一切都完成了，我可以
click on close and move this thing to the bin and now i have python installed
单击关闭并将此内容移至bin 现在我已经安装了 python
now to actually use it on macos i need my launcher and you have a program
现在要在我需要的 macOS 上实际使用它我的启动器和你有一个程序
called python launcher although this one does look a bit weird in here you can't
称为 python 启动器，虽然这个这里看起来确实有点奇怪，你不能
do very much although you have a tick box that says run in terminal window or
尽管你有蜱虫，但还是做了很多事框显示在终端窗口中运行或
at least i hope you do a terminal is another program inside of
至少我希望你这样做终端是其中的另一个程序
mac os if you open the launcher again and type
苹果系统如果您再次打开启动器并输入
terminal there you have a terminal
终端那里有一个终端
and let me increase the font size here a bit so this is easier to read
让我增加这里的字体大小有点这样更容易阅读
now what you want to do in here is you want to type python 3
现在你想做的就是你想要输入 python 3
and then press enter and now you can write python code for example you could
然后按 Enter 键，现在您可以编写 python 代码，例如你可以
write print brackets open then quotation mark hello
写打印括号打开然后引号 hello
world and then closing quotation mark closing
世界然后用右引号结束
bracket and now if you print this you get hello world and like we have done on
括号，现在如果你打印这个你打个招呼，就像我们之前所做的那样
windows you could type one plus two and you're getting free
windows 你可以输入一加二和你获得自由了
and this is valid python code but once again you're only writing a single line
这是有效的 python 代码，但一次再说一遍，你只写了一行
of code but for that again we're going to work
代码的但为此我们将再次努力
on the code editor in this part we are going to install a
在代码编辑器上在这部分我们将安装一个
code editor and let's first talk about why we are going to need that
我们先来谈谈代码编辑器为什么我们需要它
right now we can run python code which is a really good start but we cannot use
现在我们可以运行 python 代码是一个非常好的开始，但我们不能使用
python comfortably right now we can write single lines of
蟒蛇舒适现在我们可以写单行
code but later on we want to write hundreds if not thousands of lines of
代码，但稍后我们想写数百甚至数千行
code and right now we just cannot do that for that we are going to need some
代码，现在我们做不到为此我们需要一些
kind of text editor for our code think of this like word or pages it's simply a
我们的代码认为的一种文本编辑器像单词或页面一样，它只是一个
text editor except now we are writing code instead of sentences
文本编辑器，除了现在我们正在写代码而不是句子
and there are a ton of popular code editors here's the list of the really
并且有大量流行的代码编辑这里是真正的名单
famous one we have visual studio code pycharm atom and sublime
著名的我们有 Visual Studio 代码pycharm Atom 和 Sublime
although there are a lot more there basically is no end to code editors the
虽然还有很多基本上代码编辑器是没有尽头的
one that i am going to use is called sublime this is a really straightforward
我要使用的一个叫做太棒了，这真的很简单
and simple code editor that you can also customize quite a bit which i really
和简单的代码编辑器，您也可以定制相当多，我真的
enjoy but basically all of those would be fine
享受但基本上所有这些都可以
if you have a strong preference although i would recommend just to follow along
如果你有强烈的偏好我建议只是跟随
to also use sublime and this is going to be just another program that we have to
也可以使用 sublime，这将是只是我们必须执行的另一个程序
install oh i should mention all of them are completely free you don't have to
安装哦，我应该提到所有这些完全免费，您不必这样做
pay anything but let's install it alright here we are on the website of
支付任何费用，但让我们安装它好的，我们现在在以下网站上
sublime and the url is sublimetext.com the full name of the code editor is
sublime 且 url 为 sublimetext.com代码编辑器的全名是
sublime text but nobody really calls it that and then here you can go to
崇高的文字，但没有人真正称呼它然后你可以去这里
download and download the entire thing now you can see it already probably
下载并下载整个内容现在你可能已经看到了
there is also a buy option you can purchase sublime it costs about 80 i
您还可以选择购买购买sublime大约需要80i
think but you don't have to do it the free version has exactly the same
想，但你不必这么做免费版本完全相同
features and this is what we are going to use
功能，这就是我们要做的使用
basically when you are buying it you are supporting the creators but you don't
基本上当你购买它时支持创作者，但你不支持
have to do it so in download you can download the version you need either mac
必须这样做，所以在下载时你可以下载您需要的 Mac 版本
os windows or linux in my case i need windows so i'm clicking on that and now
我需要的操作系统是 windows 或 linuxwindows 所以我现在点击它
i have a download for my specific version
我有一个针对我的具体情况的下载版本
obviously if you have a different operating system this would look a bit
显然如果你有不同的操作系统这看起来有点
different but now you click on open file and then you get this kind of menu in
不同，但现在您单击打开文件然后你会得到这样的菜单
here you just click on next and you install it
在这里你只需点击下一步然后你安装它
like anything else and finish there we go now you have
像其他任何事情一样完成那里，我们现在就可以了
installed sublime on mac os the installer might look
安装崇高在 Mac 操作系统上，安装程序可能看起来像
slightly different but that is minor details
略有不同，但很小细节
but once you have all of that you can type sublime text
但一旦你拥有了所有这些你就可以输入崇高的文字
and now you should be seeing something like this this is our code editor
现在你应该看到一些东西这是我们的代码编辑器
and in here you can write any kind of text whatever you want to write
在这里你可以写任何任何你想写的文字
in my case what i want to write in here is print
就我而言，我想在这里写下什么正在打印
and brackets and now quotation marks hello
和括号现在引号你好
world and this is going to be the python code
世界这将是 python 代码
we want to execute now to execute all of this we need two
我们想要执行现在要执行所有这一切，我们需要两个
major steps number one this is the easy one we have
主要步骤第一，这是我们拥有的最简单的一个
to save our file this we do under file and save or controller command s
为了保存我们的文件，我们在文件下执行此操作并保存或控制器命令
if i do that i end up somewhere in my file system in
如果我这样做我最终在我的文件系统中的某个地方
my case i have the folder here already you can save it wherever you want it
我的情况是这里已经有文件夹了你可以将其保存在任何你想要的地方
really doesn't make any difference although what does make a difference is
真的没有什么区别尽管真正重要的是
the naming of the file let me call this one test
文件的命名让我称之为一个测试
but you do have to specify an ending so you want dodge and then add p y short
但你必须指定一个结局你想要闪避，然后添加 y 短
for python this is telling your computer that you have a python file
对于Python来说，这是告诉你的计算机你有一个 python 文件
you could compare all of this to word which always needs a docx ending or a
你可以将所有这些与文字进行比较总是需要 docx 结尾或
text file which always has a txt ending but in our case we want dot pi and now i
始终以 txt 结尾的文本文件但在我们的例子中，我们想要点 pi，现在我
want to save and what you should be seeing now is
想要保存你现在应该看到的是
that the colors of our text changed if they didn't don't worry too much
我们文本的颜色改变了如果他们没有，别太担心
about it but now what you want to do let me show my mouse
关于它但现在你想做的让我展示一下我的鼠标
and i want to go to tools and in here we have build and build with
我想去工具在这里我们已经构建并构建了
this basically means you want to execute your code
这基本上意味着你想执行你的代码
i want to click on build and now i can see hello world down here
我想点击构建现在我可以在这里看到你好世界
now you might be seeing something else what you might be seeing is
现在你可能会看到别的东西你可能会看到的是
a dialog that looks something like this in here you want to select python so if
一个看起来像这样的对话框在这里你想选择 python 所以如果
i click on this one you're getting the same result
我点击这个你会得到相同的结果
the reason here is when you're running python for the first time sublime does
原因是当你跑步时python sublime 第一次做
want to double check that you do indeed want to run python but if you have done
想再次确认你确实这样做了想要运行 python 但如果你已经完成了
that once sublime does remember and most of the time what i am going to
曾经的崇高确实记得大多数时候我要做的事
do is instead of up here clicking on build
做不是在这里点击构建
i am pressing ctrl or command b this one is going to give you the same
我按 ctrl 或 command b这个会给你同样的
result and if you want to close this dialog down here you press on escape
结果，如果你想关闭它对话框在此处，您按“退出”
although there is a really important topic i do want to cover
虽然有一个非常重要的我确实想讨论的主题
and that is when we are running any kind of code in
那就是当我们运行任何类型的代码时
sublime what essentially happens is that sublime inserts all of the code into the
崇高本质上发生的是sublime 将所有代码插入到
python app however sublime doesn't know by default where that python app is
python 应用程序但是 sublime 不知道默认情况下，python 应用程序在哪里
because remember python is just another program on our computer it's nothing
因为记住 python 只是另一个我们计算机上的程序没什么
special the only reason sublime right now can
特别的现在崇高的唯一原因是
find the python app is because of the path files
找到python应用程序是因为路径文件
these path files are basically a directory inside of windows that makes
这些路径文件基本上是windows 内的目录使
it easier for programs to find other programs
程序更容易找到其他程式
and because of that sublime can find python very easily if we didn't add
正因为如此，崇高才能找到如果我们不添加的话 python 很容易
python to the path though sublime would not be able to find it and you would
python 到路径虽然 sublime 会找不到它，你会
have to add quite a bit more yourself to make it all work which fortunately we
必须自己添加更多内容使一切顺利，幸运的是我们
didn't need because we did add python to the path files
不需要，因为我们确实添加了 python路径文件
if you forgot that for some reason just uninstall python and reinstall it with
如果你因为某种原因忘记了卸载 python 并重新安装
the pathfire selected that's the easiest way to go on about it
选择最简单的路径火继续下去的方法
but alright what you can do now you could for example copy this line here
但好吧你现在能做什么例如可以在这里复制这一行
and paste it multiple times run all of this
并粘贴多次运行所有这
and you can see hello world multiple times
你可以看到 hello world multiple次
once again how all of this works in detail i will cover in the next well 10
再次说明这一切是如何运作的我将在下一个井 10 中介绍详细信息
hours or so but in here what you can also do
小时左右但在这里你还可以做什么
is inside of print add a math operation like 5 10 and now run all of this again
在 print 里面添加一个数学运算就像 5 10 现在再次运行所有这些
under tools and build and you get 15 all the way at the end
在工具和构建下，你会得到 15 个尽头的路
and with that we can run python code over multiple lines
这样我们就可以运行 python 代码了多行
so with this we can basically start the actual python tutorial
所以我们基本上可以开始实际的Python教程
although before we get started on that there's one more thing i do want to do
尽管在我们开始之前我还有一件事想做
that you don't necessarily have to follow because i think all of this is
你不一定必须这样做关注因为我认为这一切都是
looking kind of ugly and a bit hard to read
看起来有点丑而且有点难读
as a consequence i want to change the styling
因此我想改变造型
but i am literally only going to change the look of sublime in terms of
但我实际上只会改变崇高的外观
functionality nothing is going to change so if you want to skip this part you can
功能不会改变所以如果你想跳过这一部分你可以
totally do so let me show my mouse what i want to do
完全这样做让我向我的鼠标展示我想做什么
most importantly under view i can hide a couple of things that we don't need for
最重要的是在视图下我可以隐藏一个一些我们不需要的东西
example all the way in the bottom you can see a couple of bits of
示例一直在底部你可以看到一些
information that we don't need so i want to hide all of this
我们不需要的信息，所以我想要隐藏这一切
this is the status bar and i want to hide the status bar
这是状态栏，我想要隐藏状态栏
already looking better besides that up here you can see the
看起来已经好多了除此之外，你还可以看到
tabs if you have multiple python files this
选项卡如果你有多个 python 文件
can be really useful each tab would be one python file
每个选项卡都非常有用一个Python文件
but for a long time we are only ever going to have a single python file later
但很长一段时间我们只是永远稍后会有一个 python 文件
on we are going to use these tabs though but for now i want to go to view and
不过我们将使用这些选项卡但现在我想去看看
hide tabs already looking much cleaner
隐藏标签看起来已经干净多了
besides that what you can also do is hide the menu and this is making
除此之外你还可以做的是隐藏菜单，这就是
everything look even cleaner if you want the menu back you are
一切看起来更加干净如果你想要菜单回来你就是
clicking on alt and now you can see it until you click outside of it but then
单击 alt，现在您可以看到它直到你点击它的外面，然后
you can bring it back and all of this is already looking
你可以把它带回来而这一切都已经在寻找
significantly cleaner now if you want to get rid of this top bar here you have to
如果你想的话，现在明显更干净了你必须去掉这里的顶部栏
click on f11 and now you have a full screen app
点击 f11 现在你就有了完整的屏幕应用程序
which i think is much nicer to work in now what you can also do is change the
我认为在那里工作要好得多现在你还可以做的是改变
text size what you do with controller command and
字体大小你用控制器命令做什么
then either the equal or the minus sign equal makes the text larger minus makes
然后是等号或减号equal 使文本变大 minus 使文本变大
the text smaller and in here just choose whatever you can
文字变小在这里你可以选择任何你能选择的
see best in my case i usually aim for having 30 lines of code on one screen
在我的情况下看到最好的我通常的目标一个屏幕上有 30 行代码
so in my case the font size i usually choose if i copy this a couple of times
所以就我而言，我通常使用字体大小选择是否复制此几次
is something like this i have 30 lines of code on one window
是这样的我在一个窗口上有 30 行代码
but this is entirely subjective you probably want to have something smaller
但这完全是主观的可能想要更小的东西
and finally what we can do is change the color scheme and the theming of this
最后我们能做的是改变配色方案和主题
and for this you can install external themes this you do with control or
为此，您可以安装外部您可以通过控制或
command shift and p if you click all of them
命令 Shift 和 P如果你点击全部
you get a couple of options that you can use inside of sublime in here you want
你有几个选择在你想要的地方使用 sublime 内部
to click on install package now click on enter
点击现在安装包点击进入
now sublime is going to think for a second and now you can install external
现在 Sublime 会考虑一个第二，现在你可以安装外部
modules some of these change the functionality
模块其中一些改变了功能
of sublime but most of them are just different color schemes
崇高但大多数只是不同的配色方案
and in my case what i want to install is the agila theme so if you type agila
就我而言，我想要安装的是agila 主题，所以如果您输入 agila
this should be the first result and now just press enter
这应该是第一个结果，现在只需按回车键
and there you can see the nodes for the argila theme but we
在那里你可以看到argila 主题的节点，但我们
don't care about that now to get back to our code you want to press alt for the
现在不关心这个，回去吧我们的代码你想按alt键
menu and at least for now i do want to show
菜单至少现在我确实想展示
tabs so we can navigate around here although this package control message
选项卡，以便我们可以在此处导航虽然这个包控制消息
you can close by clicking on the x here and now we are back in the code but
您可以点击此处的 x 关闭现在我们回到了代码但是
nothing has changed now to actually apply the changes you have to go to
现在实际上什么都没有改变应用您必须执行的更改
preferences and in here you have select a color
优先在这里你可以选择一种颜色
scheme and select a theme let's start with the theme in here you
方案并选择主题让我们从这里的主题开始吧
have a bunch of different themes if you click on down you can see what is
有很多不同的主题，如果你点击向下你可以看到是什么
changing
改变
so if i click on a couple you see what the difference is in my
所以如果我点击几个你看我的有什么不同
case i just want to use the agile theme so if i click on this we already have a
案例我只想使用敏捷主题所以如果我点击这个我们已经有了
couple of changes what you can also do now if you click on preferences again
你还可以做一些改变现在如果你再次点击首选项
you can select the color scheme this one changes the actual code in terms of what
你可以选择这个配色方案更改实际代码的内容
you see and in here once again you can select a lot of different things i don't
你看，再次在这里你可以选择很多我没有选择的东西
want to go over this too fast because it might be a ton of colors and well i
想要过快地回顾这个因为它可能有很多颜色，我
don't overwhelm you but in here you can search for different color schemes
不要让你不知所措，但在这里你可以搜索不同的配色方案
depending on what you have installed in my case i'm gonna look for agila and
取决于您安装的内容就我而言，我要寻找阿吉拉
then oceanic next
然后是海洋
if i select this one all of this is looking significantly nicer
如果我选择这个，所有这些都是看起来好多了
if i now go to view and
如果我现在去查看并
hide the tabs this is basically what you're going to
隐藏选项卡这基本上就是你要做的
see most of the time and i think this is much easier to read although you might
大多数时候都会看到，我认为这是尽管您可能会更容易阅读
be wondering what is this line here on the left and
想知道这条线是什么左边和
well for now you really don't have to worry about it it's something much more
好吧，现在你真的不需要担心它还有更多的事情
advanced you can entirely ignore it as a consequence since it is not going to be
高级你可以完全忽略它作为后果，因为它不会
relevant for this entire tutorial i have hidden it
与我的整个教程相关隐藏它
which is bringing us to some more optionality inside of sublime so if i go
这给我们带来了更多崇高内部的可选性所以如果我去
to preferences and here i go to settings we get another window and in here you
到首选项，我在这里进入设置我们有另一个窗口，你就在这里
can see the settings now you might be used to other programs
可以看到设置现在您可能已经习惯了其他程序
you just have checkboxes in sublime this is working a bit different you are
你只是在 sublime 中有复选框你的工作有点不同
basically having on the left here all of the
基本上左边有所有的
different options you could be changing for example you could change the margin
您可以更改的不同选项例如，您可以更改边距
size to a four and to change this you would have to copy this one here and
大小为四并更改此你必须在这里复制这个
paste it on the right side like this and now you can change the
将其粘贴到右侧像这样，现在你可以改变
margin to whatever you want although my case i don't want to do this
尽管我的如果我不想这样做
and i don't want to add too many complications in here because all of
我不想添加太多这里的并发症是因为所有
this is getting a bit more advanced so what i'm going to do is i have a text
这变得更先进了所以我要做的是我有一条短信
file let me increase the size of the right one
文件让我增加大小正确对象，真爱
i have a text file that you can just copy if you want to have the exact same
我有一个文本文件，你可以如果你想要完全相同的复制
styling that i do you just paste it in here
我做的样式你只需将其粘贴进去这里
and now if you click on control s to save everything
现在如果你点击control s保存一切
you should see not much of a difference although the yellow bar for example
你应该看到没有太大区别虽然例如黄色条
disappeared and all of these options here you can
消失了所有这些选项都可以在这里
find in the description so with that you can minimize all of
在描述中找到这样你就可以最小化所有
this and now all of this looks as clean as it can be at least i think so
现在这一切看起来都很干净至少我是这么认为的
so with that we have python installed and we can get started i want to start
这样我们就安装了python我们可以开始了 我想开始
by talking about how code in python or in basically any programming language is
通过谈论 python 中的代码或基本上任何编程语言都是
being executed and there are a couple of things you
被处决有几件事你
have to understand the most important concept is that code
必须明白最重要的概念是代码
will always be executed from the first to the last line for example if we have
总是从第一个开始执行到最后一行例如如果我们有
these three lines of code python is going to start from the top so line one
这三行代码python是将从顶部开始，所以第一行
this one here then we do line two line three
这里这个然后我们做第二行第三行
and then we continue until we reach the end of the code
然后我们继续直到到达代码末尾
and later on we are going to learn some tools to make this more flexible
稍后我们将学习一些使这更加灵活的工具
for example if we want to repeat code or only run code if a certain condition is
例如，如果我们想重复代码或仅在满足特定条件时运行代码
true but for now i just want to execute some basic code so we can get started
是的，但现在我只想执行一些基本代码，以便我们可以开始
and let's have a look at all of this in some actual python file
让我们看看这一切一些实际的 python 文件
and here we have a completely empty one and something we have seen already is to
这里我们有一个完全空的我们已经看到的是
use the print statement and in here you can just write a random word
使用 print 语句，在这里你可以随便写一个词
so a random word and now if i execute the code
所以一个随机词现在如果我执行代码
which again i do with ctrl b or if i press alt
我再次使用 ctrl b 执行此操作，或者如果我按 alt
i can go to tools and build same thing if i click on it i get a
我可以转到工具并构建同样的事情，如果我点击它，我会得到一个
random word and just to be a bit more specific here
随机词在这里更具体一点
let me change this word to first line of code
让我把这个词改为第一行代码
and now if i add another print statement let me duplicate this line which i by
现在如果我添加另一个打印语句让我复制这行
the way do with ctrl shift and d that way you can duplicate lines and sublime
使用 ctrl、shift 和 d 的方式复制线条和崇高的方式
very easily now what i want to do for the second
非常简单地现在我想做什么
line of code i want to rename this to second line of code
我想将其重命名为的代码行第二行代码
and now if i run this we get the second line of code
现在如果我运行这个我们会得到第二个代码行
meaning this line here was run first then we have number two and this would
意味着这里的这条线是首先运行的那么我们有第二个，这将
then continue forever we are essentially executing code downwards in this
然后永远继续我们本质上是在此向下执行代码
direction and this would work with any other data
方向这适用于任何其他数据
type as well for example i could print some numbers and now we will get one two
也可以输入，例如我可以打印一些数字，现在我们将得到一二
and three and that is then giving us the most
和三个这就是给我们最大的
basic thing you have to understand that now we can execute some lines of code
你必须明白的基本事情现在我们可以执行一些代码行
and i suppose there's one more important thing when we are talking about words
我想还有一个更重要的当我们谈论文字时的事情
and print and that is let me copy this again
然后打印，让我复制这个再次
a space in here would also show up meaning if i add a ton of white space
这里也会出现一个空格意思是如果我添加大量空白
and run this again we now get this line of code here let me
并再次运行我们现在在这里得到这行代码让我
rename it really quick third line of code
重命名它真的很快第三行代码
all of this white space here is still showing up
这里所有的空白仍然是出现
so just keep that in mind and well with that we have covered all
所以请记住这一点至此，我们已经涵盖了所有内容
of the basics of really basic code execution
真正基本代码的基础知识执行
and i guess with that let's do an exercise
我想我们可以做一个锻炼
i want you guys to use these print statements to print some kind of tree
我希望你们使用这些印​​刷品打印某种树的语句
looking shape and for that you want to use basic characters and white space and
寻找形状和你想要的使用基本字符和空白
then combine these two and create that shape so pause the video now and see how
然后将这两者结合起来并创建形状所以现在暂停视频看看如何
far you get
你能走多远
the way you have to think about it i want to print again and i want to write
你必须考虑的方式我想再次打印并且我想写
five axes and if i run the code now we can see
五轴如果我现在运行代码我们可以看到
these five axes if i now print these five axes again one
这五个轴如果我现在再次打印这五个轴
two three four five but
二三四五但
remove the first two and replace them with a space
删除前两个并替换它们有一个空格
if i now do this i get the three axis on top of the five axes
如果我现在这样做，我就会得到三轴五个轴的顶部
and before the first x we have a white space so we start to have some kind of
在第一个 x 之前我们有一个白色空间所以我们开始有某种
pyramid shape i just want to continue
金字塔形状我只想继续
i want to print two spaces and an x and if i run the code now
我想打印两个空格和一个 x 和如果我现在运行代码
we can see we have a proper triangle and this would be the top of my tree
我们可以看到我们有一个正确的三角形这将是我的树顶
and now i can copy this line and at the bottom of the tree i can add
现在我可以复制这一行在树的底部我可以添加
it 3 times if i run this now we have a tree this is looking pretty
如果我现在运行这个，它会运行 3 次我们有一棵树，看起来很漂亮
good granted it doesn't look too nice but it
好的当然它看起来不太好但是它
is what it is i suppose
就是这样我想
what we can also do i can just print empty strings with no word inside if i
我们还能做什么 我可以打印空字符串，里面没有单词 if i
do that we have one line of space between the
去做我们之间有一行空间
words we have covered earlier and our tree although one important thing really
我们之前介绍过的单词和我们的树虽然确实是一件重要的事情
quick there is one line in here that i left intentionally empty to
快点，这里有一行我故意留空
organize my code for python this line does not exist if i
组织我的代码对于Python来说，如果我不存在这一行
run the code the empty line we have here is because of this empty statement this
运行我们这里的空行代码是因为这个空语句
one comes right below the one two three this one to three this line for python
一位于一二三的正下方对于Python来说这一行是一到三
is just being ignored meaning if you don't write a line of
只是被忽视意思是如果你不写一行
code python is just going to ignore it which is really helpful to keep your
python 代码会忽略它这对于保持你的
code organized so alright this is then the most fundamental thing you have to
代码组织得很好，然后就是这样你必须做的最基本的事情
understand and it's pretty simple we are just executing code from the top to the
理解，这很简单只是从上到下执行代码
bottom in this part we are going to learn about
底部在这一部分我们将学习
math operations and those are in python fairly similar because you probably
数学运算和那些在Python中相当相似，因为你可能
already know them from basic math classes that you learned when you were
已经从基础数学中了解了它们你小时候学过的课程
something like 5 or 6 it's really basic we have plus minus multiply and divide
5 或 6 之类的东西，这是非常基本的我们有加减乘除
and besides that we also have power floor divide and remainder i guess the
除此之外我们还有力量我猜地板除法和余数
letter 3 are a tiny bit more advanced but not that much
字母 3 稍微高级一些但没那么多
besides that you can also use brackets perfectly fine
除此之外你也可以使用括号，非常好
like in any kind of computer calculator you ever used
就像任何类型的计算机计算器一样你曾经用过
there are also comparison operators like smaller than or smaller equal then
还有比较运算符，例如小于或小于等于然后
but those we will cover later because they work ever so slightly differently i
但我们稍后会介绍这些，因为他们的工作方式略有不同我
guess i can talk about them for a tiny bit but don't worry about those too much
我想我可以稍微谈谈他们有点，但不用担心太多
yet let's have a look at all of this
然而让我们看看这一切
here again i have a completely empty python file
我再次有一个完全空的蟒蛇文件
and i want to start by printing a math operation and this i just do by typing
我想从打印一个数学开始操作，我只需输入即可
the math operation in here for example 10 plus 5
例如这里的数学运算10加5
is going to give me 15. and that is literally it it's quite
会给我 15。这就是字面上的意思，它相当
simple if i duplicate this line
简单的如果我复制这一行
i can change this to a minus and now we get 5.
我可以把它改为减号现在我们得到了 5 个。
i could duplicate this again change this to multiply and duplicate it
我可以再重复一次将其更改为相乘并复制它
once more and change this to divide and that way
再一次并将其更改为除法
we have all the basic operators so if i run this we get 15 5 50 and 2. i
我们拥有所有基本操作员所以如果我运行这个我们会得到 15 5 50 和 2.i
guess the one thing you do want to notice here is that when we're using
猜猜你确实想做的一件事这里要注意的是，当我们使用
division this operation here python is giving us 2.0
除法这里的操作python是给我们2.0
it happens to add a point zero even though we wouldn't need it
它甚至还添加了一个零点虽然我们不需要它
it's really not a big deal but just keep it in mind besides that we have slightly
这真的不是什么大不了的事，但只要保持除此之外，我们还有一点
more advanced math operators let me print
更高级的数学运算符让我打印
10 star star and 5 and this is giving us a
10星星和 5 这给了我们一个
fairly large number because we are taking the power here i
相当大的数量因为我们正在夺取这里的权力
guess if i do a 2 we have the equivalent of 10 to the
猜猜我是否做2我们有相当于 10 的
power of 2 which is 10 multiplied by 10 which is 100
2 的幂，即 10 乘以 10这是 100
and this is what we are getting down here
这就是我们要了解的这里
besides that we also have what is called a floor divide
除此之外我们还有所谓的地板鸿沟
and to understand what that means let me divide 10 by 3. if i do this we
并理解这意味着什么让我将 10 除以 3。如果我这样做，我们
get 3.333 and it continues basically forever
得到3.333并且它基本上永远持续下去
if floor divide essentially gets rid of all of the stuff after the decimal point
如果楼层划分基本上消除了小数点后的所有内容
and this floor divide you get with two divide symbols
这个楼层分为两个除法符号
meaning if i run the code now we are only getting three
意思是如果我现在运行代码只得到三个
you are essentially rounding the result of whatever you are getting in here
你基本上是在四舍五入结果无论你在这里得到什么
although keep in mind this value
尽管请记住这个值
is not rounding the result what we're doing is truncating the
没有对结果进行四舍五入我们正在做的是截断
result which is a fancy word for saying we are cutting off anything after the
结果，这是一个很奇特的词我们将在之后切断任何东西
decimal point i can demonstrate this by dividing 7
小数点我可以通过除 7 来证明这一点
over 2. if you do this in your head you are
超过 2.如果你在脑子里这样做，你就是
going to get 3.5 with a normal division
要拿到3.5 正常除法
and if we were to round this number it should be 4 because 0.5 is closer to 4
如果我们要四舍五入这个数字应该是 4，因为 0.5 更接近 4
than it is to 3 but if i run the code again i am getting
比 3但如果我再次运行代码我得到
3. and just be careful here this can
3.请小心，这可以
sometimes cause you some errors where you're losing decimal points and then
有时会导致一些错误你失去了小数点然后
end up thinking you're rounding when you're not actually doing that
最终认为你正在四舍五入你实际上并没有这样做
there's one more math operation we need and that is done with the percentage
我们还需要一项数学运算这是用百分比来完成的
sign for example this could look like seven
符号例如，这可能看起来像七个
percentage two and if i run this let's see what we get
百分比二如果我运行这个让我们看看我们会得到什么
we are getting one and this one here is the remainder
我们正在得到一个这是剩下的
the best way to think about it is we have seven units in total
最好的思考方式是我们一共有七个单位
we have one two three four five six and seven
我们有一二三四五六七
and when we are dividing seven by two we are basically looking for two whole
当我们将七除以二时我们基本上是在寻找两个完整的
units to get a full number meaning here is one
单位以获得完整的数字这里的意思是一个
there is two and here is 3.
有两个这里是 3。
and that is giving us the result we got from this operation
这就是我们得到的结果从这个操作
and this
和这
percentage symbol is giving us whatever remains at the end which is this one
百分比符号给了我们任何东西留在最后，就是这个
here and since this is one the one we're getting down here is well a one
在这里，因为这就是我们的到这里来是很好的一件事
you don't see this symbol too often but it can be really useful to figure out if
你不会经常看到这个符号，但是弄清楚是否真的很有用
a number is even or odd something you do surprisingly often we're going to have a
数字是偶数还是奇数 你所做的事情令人惊讶的是，我们经常会遇到
look at that later there's one more thing i do want to
稍后看看我还想做一件事
cover and that is brackets for example i could print
盖，即括号例如我可以打印
5 times 2 and the result
5 次 2和结果
is going to be 10 this should be fairly simple
将会是 10 这应该是相当的简单的
but now if i do 5 plus 5 multiplied by 2 think about it for a second and see what
但现在如果我做 5 加 5 乘以 2想一想，看看会发生什么
you should be getting the result is 15 and it is 15 because we
你应该得到结果是 15，它是 15 因为我们
always do multiplication first and then we are doing addition and subtraction
总是先做乘法，然后再做乘法我们正在做加法和减法
meaning this operation is basically 5 plus 10 which gets us 15.
意思是这个操作基本上是5加 10 就得到 15。
if i don't want to do that and add 5 plus 5 first of all i have to put both
如果我不想这样做并添加 5加 5 首先我必须把两者都加上
of those into brackets and now i'm getting 20.
将那些放入括号中，现在我是得到20。
what we're doing now is 5 plus 5 is 10 and this we multiply with 2 which is
我们现在做的是 5 加 5 等于 10我们将其乘以 2，即
getting us 20. i guess the one thing we can also cover
给我们20个。我想我们还可以讨论一件事
is very simple comparison operators and those do work in the same way that
非常简单的比较运算符这些的工作原理与
you would expect them to work to be honest for example i could type 10
你会期望他们能够工作老实说，例如我可以输入 10
is greater than 5. the difference here is the result we are
大于5。这里的区别就是我们的结果
getting because the result we're getting is true
得到因为我们得到的结果是真的
which i guess doesn't make sense because 10 indeed is greater than 5.
我想这没有意义，因为10确实大于5。
if i flip this around that 10 is smaller than 5 and run the
如果我翻转这个10 小于 5 并运行
code again we are getting false
再次编码我们变得虚假了
and how we can use these values we will see later on but for now don't worry too
以及我们将如何使用这些价值观稍后见，但现在也不必担心
much about this one now with that we have covered the basic
关于这个的很多现在我们已经介绍了基本的
operations and let's do an exercise
运营让我们做一个练习
what i want you guys to do is to get the average of the numbers from one to seven
我希望你们做的是得到从 1 到 7 的数字的平均值
so one plus two plus three plus four plus five plus six plus seven all
所以一加二加三加四加五加六加七全部
divided by seven and see how far you
除以七看看你有多远
get once again i have to type print and now in here i want one plus two plus
我必须再次输入 print 并现在在这里我想要一加二加
three plus four plus five plus six plus seven
三加四加五加六加七
and all of this has to be inside of brackets because what we're going to do
所有这些都必须在里面括号里是因为我们要做的
afterwards is divide all of this by 7. and the issue is in terms of math if we
然后将所有这些除以 7。问题在于数学，如果我们
left it like this we would first divide seven by seven which would be one and
像这样我们首先要分开七乘七，即一和
then we are adding all of these numbers but what we want to do instead
然后我们将所有这些数字相加但我们想做的是
is do all of this here first and then divide it by seven
首先在这里完成所有这一切然后除以七
for this sort of thing sublime is quite intelligent i can just select the entire
对于这种事情来说，崇高是相当的聪明的我可以选择整个
text create and open brackets and then
文本创建并打开括号，然后
sublime automatically adds the closing bracket afterwards
sublime自动添加结束语之后括号
and with that we are done if i execute the code now we get 4.0
如果我执行的话我们就完成了现在我们得到的代码是 4.0
although looking at the result here i realized for this entire part so far i
虽然在这里看结果我到目前为止我已经实现了整个部分
have only ever used full numbers which you don't have to it is perfectly fine
只使用过完整的数字你不必这样做，完全没问题
to write something like one plus one plus five
写一加一之类的东西加五
you would still get the appropriate result any number in here is going to be
你仍然会得到适当的结果这里的任何数字都会是
fine this is working like any math operation you have ever seen
很好，这就像任何数学一样你见过的操作
in this part we are going to talk about how to connect different lines of code
在这一部分我们将讨论如何连接不同行的代码
and let me explain the problem let's say we have some kind of math
让我解释一下问题假设我们有某种数学知识
operation and we want to print the result of that
手术我们想要打印结果
map operation on the next line the issue we have now is how can we
下一行的映射操作我们现在面临的问题是我们怎样才能
connect these two lines and the answer here is we are going to
连接这两行答案是我们要
need variables and variables are an incredibly
需要变量变量是一个令人难以置信的
important topic in any programming language
任何编程中的重要主题语言
so let's talk about it all that variables essentially are is a
那么我们来谈谈吧所有变量本质上都是
simple container for any kind of data we could for example put a word a number
适用于任何类型数据的简单容器例如，我们可以把一个词放在一个数字上
or really anything we have a python in there
或者任何我们有Python的东西那里
and once you have created this container you can reuse it over and over again
一旦你创建了这个容器你可以一遍又一遍地重复使用它
and this variable you create like this we have the variable name
你像这样创建这个变量我们有变量名
then we have the assign operator and that is just an equal sign and then we
然后我们有赋值运算符和这只是一个等号然后我们
have the actual data or the value we want to assign
有实际数据或我们的值想要分配
and that is basically it this instead of a word could also be a
基本上就是这样这个代替单词也可以是
number like one and it could be anything else
像一这样的数字，它可以是任何东西别的
but how you would solve the earlier problem is you would first store the
但你会如何解决之前的问题问题是你首先要存储
math operation result in a variable called result
数学运算结果为变量调用结果
and then this result you would print on the next line
然后你将打印这个结果下一行
and i suppose let's actually try all of this
我想我们应该尝试一下所有的这
once more completely empty python file and in here i want to do a map operation
再次完全空的 python 文件在这里我想做一个地图操作
again and so far we always used print and then did some math in here let's say
到目前为止我们总是使用打印然后在这里做了一些数学假设
ten plus five but this print we don't need
十加五但我们不需要这个印刷品
we could just have lines like this although if i execute the code now again
我们可以有这样的行虽然如果我现在再次执行代码
by pressing ctrl b nothing would happen
按 ctrl b什么都不会发生
although something did happen python did
虽然确实发生了一些事情 python 确实发生了
calculate the result here we just didn't tell to print the result
在这里计算结果我们只是没有告诉打印结果
so it doesn't print a result and we can't see anything but something did
所以它不会打印结果，我们看不到任何东西，但有一些东西发生了
indeed happen instead of printing this result i want to store it in the
确实发生了而不是打印这个结果我想将它存储在
variable and this variable i called result
多变的这个变量我称之为结果
and this is going to be the name of my variable now
这将是我的名字现在可变
and now to assign this value here to this result
现在将此值分配给这个结果
we are going to need the equals sign
我们需要等号
which is telling python that the result of this operation should be assigned to
这告诉 python 结果此操作应分配给
this variable and now on the next line we can just
这个变量现在在下一行我们可以
print that result and if i run the code now we are getting
打印该结果如果我现在运行代码我们会得到
15 or the result of this operation here and
15或此处操作的结果和
what is even better we could use this result for further
还有什么更好的我们可以利用这个结果进行进一步的研究
operations and we would use it like the actual value
操作，我们会像使用它一样实际价值
for example what i could be doing i could have another variable let's call
例如我可以做什么我可以有另一个变量让我们调用
it result 2 and the value here should be the original result
结果是 2，这里的值应该是原始结果
divided by 2. and if i now print result 2
除以 2。如果我现在打印结果 2
we can see we get 15 and 7.5 which is this result divided by 2.
我们可以看到我们得到 15 和 7.5就是这个结果除以 2。
and this we could do forever this result is basically a stand in for the value we
我们可以永远这样做这个结果基本上代表了我们的价值
have created here although there's one thing you do want
在这里创建了虽然有一件事你确实想要
to be careful about and that is variable naming let's talk about this one really
要小心，这是可变的命名让我们真正谈谈这个
quick there are two variable naming parts the first one is the mandatory
快速有两个变量命名第一个部分是强制性的
parts that you have to follow if you do not follow these naming conventions
如果您这样做，则必须遵循的部分不遵循这些命名约定
python is going to throw an error and fortunately they are fairly simple
python 会抛出一个错误幸运的是它们相当简单
the most important one is that variable names can only contain letters numbers
最重要的是这个变量名称只能包含字母数字
and the underscore symbol you couldn't use something like the
和下划线符号你不能使用类似的东西
dollar sign percentage space something like this space in particular should
美元符号百分比空间某物特别喜欢这个空间
make sense quite intuitively if there's a space in a variable name it's really a
如果有的话，很直观地有意义变量名中的空格实际上是一个
python to tell if we have one variable or two variables it just gets messy
python 判断我们是否有一个变量或两个变量，它只会变得混乱
and if you have a longer variable name and you want to add multiple words
如果你有一个更长的变量名并且您想添加多个单词
together you would use an underscore and that is quite a common thing to do i
一起使用下划线和这是我经常做的事情
will show you in a second the second rule is a variable name must
稍后会向您展示第二条规则是变量名必须
start with a letter or an underscore the important thing here is numbers are not
以字母或下划线开头重要的是数字不是
allowed a variable name cannot start with a number finally variable names
允许变量名无法启动最后带有数字变量名
must be different from the inbuilt python tools for example we couldn't
必须与内置的不同例如，我们不能使用 python 工具
name a variable print i hope this one makes sense as well it
命名变量 print我希望这个也有意义
would just be confusing and i guess let's have a look at all of
只会让人困惑我想让我们看一下所有的
these rules and see if we can play around with them
这些规则，看看我们是否可以玩和他们在一起
i want to create a new variable let me call it test
我想创建一个新变量让我称之为测试
and then here we can just add a word test it doesn't really matter
然后在这里我们可以添加一个词测试一下其实并不重要
if i run this code now we are not getting an error because this
如果我现在运行这段代码我们没有收到错误，因为这个
variable name here is perfectly fine and i could also add an underscore add
这里的变量名完全没问题我还可以添加下划线
some numbers add another underscore and add some capital
有些数字添加另一个下划线并且添加一些资本
letters all of this for python totally fine
字母所有这些对于 python 来说都很好
although this name here probably really confusing
虽然这个名字在这里可能真的很令人困惑
what python doesn't like let me put this on the next line is if we for example
python 不喜欢什么让我把这个下一行是如果我们例如
start with a number for the variable let's say to test
以变​​量的数字开头假设要测试
and the value here could be test again it doesn't matter
这里的值可以再次测试没关系
if i run this now we are getting a syntax error
如果我现在运行这个我们收到语法错误
oh well we are getting quite a bit let's actually go through this error message
哦，好吧，我们已经得到了很多让我们实际上查看这个错误消息
here first of all python is telling me which
这里首先 python 告诉我哪个
file has caused the error and also it's telling me on what line
文件导致了错误它还告诉我在哪一行
the error occurred line 8 in this case which you can see here on the left side
在这种情况下，错误发生在第 8 行你可以在左侧看到
besides that i also get the actual line that caused the error so 2 test is equal
除此之外我还得到了实际的线路这导致了错误，所以 2 个测试是相等的
to test and below that we have the really
去测试下面我们有真正的
important information and that is
重要信息那就是
this syntax error invalid decimal literal it sounds
这个语法错误听起来无效的十进制文字
somewhat cryptic but what python is complaining about here is that we are
有点神秘，但是 python 是什么这里抱怨的是我们
starting a variable name with a letter however if i change this to
以字母开头的变量名但是如果我将其更改为
2 test everything is working just fine again
2 测试一切又恢复正常了
and on top of that adding a number anywhere else inside of the variable
并在此基础上添加一个数字变量内的其他任何地方
name is perfectly fine i could for example add the two at the end this
名字很好我可以例如在最后添加两个
would also work just fine the other thing that you are really not
也会工作得很好另一件你其实不是的事
allowed to do is to add spaces in your variable name
允许做的就是在你的变量名
and if i run this one now we are getting invalid syntax again
如果我现在运行这个，我们会得到语法再次无效
and here python is giving me a ton more information although it really doesn't
python 给了我更多信息虽然实际上没有
tell me all that much this line here is the really important
告诉我这么多这行非常重要
one and i think it does make sense why
一我认为这确实有道理
there's no space allowed if we have something like this it looks
没有空间允许如果我们有这样的东西看起来
like we have two separate variables which obviously would be kind of
就像我们有两个独立的变量这显然是一种
confusing so what programmers i usually do in basically any programming language
我通常对程序员感到困惑基本上可以用任何编程语言进行
is they always add underscore signs to show that we want to add a space
他们总是添加下划线符号表明我们要添加一个空格
but with that we have all of the basics for variable naming or at the very least
但这样我们就具备了所有基础知识用于变量命名或至少
the mandatory parts there are some more that are more
强制性部分还有一些更多的
optional let's talk about those the most common rule that you are going
可选的让我们来谈谈那些你要去的最常见的规则
to see is that you should use snake case and snake case just means
看到的是你应该使用蛇盒蛇的情况只是意味着
that when you are starting a new word you always start with lowercase
当你开始一个新单词时你总是以小写开头
and every additional word always is lowercase you basically only use
每一个额外的词总是你基本上只使用小写
lowercase letters and then to connect words you're using
小写字母然后连接你正在使用的单词
the underscore and this one you have to use anyway since this is a python rule
下划线和这个你必须无论如何使用，因为这是一个Python规则
what snare case basically means is you are always going to use lowercase
军鼓盒基本上意味着你总是会使用小写
letters and space is replaced with an underscore that's all it means
字母和空格被替换为下划线就是这个意思
besides that the other rule is that variable names should make sense
除此之外，另一条规则是变量名应该有意义
this sounds very obvious but i can show you a couple of examples in just a
这听起来很明显，但我可以证明举几个例子
second that might get very confusing generally it's fine to have longer
第二个可能会变得非常混乱一般来说，时间长一点就好了
variable names but make sure that the variable name expresses its content
变量名，但请确保变量名表达其内容
it's very easy to not do that and end up with code that you do not understand
很容易不这样做并最终结束用你不理解的代码
anymore so always write long names that express
不再所以总是写长名字来表达
what the variable actually does and finally variable names should be
变量实际上做了什么以及最后变量名应该是
consistent i suppose this one is pretty obvious
持续的我想这很明显
and i guess the really important one is this one here because this one is
我想真正重要的是这个在这里，因为这个是
looking terrible if you were working with other people
看起来很糟糕如果你和其他人一起工作
and try to name a variable like this you would have some questions about your
并尝试像这样命名一个变量你会对你的问题有一些疑问
mental wellness i suppose something better would be more like test
我认为心理健康更好的东西更像是测试
variable and let's call it practice
多变的我们称之为练习
this one here would be a perfectly fine variable name it isn't a snake case
这里的这个就很好了变量名不是蛇形的
because we have lowercase letters and we are connecting the words with an
因为我们有小写字母将单词与
underscore and this one here would also be at least a valid python name but we
下划线，这里的这个也会至少是一个有效的 python 名称，但我们
are kind of inconsistent we are first writing a word with letters and then the
有点不一致，我们是第一用字母写一个单词，然后
actual number so what you might want to do here is
实际数量所以你可能想要在这里做的是
write 2 a bit more consistently or don't use any numbers when variable names
写 2 更加一致，或者不写变量名时使用任意数字
begin and always stick with numbers whatever you prefer just be consistent
开始并始终坚持数字无论你喜欢什么，只要保持一致
it really helps the final thing i really want to mention
这确实有帮助我真正想提的最后一件事
what i see a lot of beginners do is do something like x equals i don't know
我看到很多初学者所做的就是像 x 等于我不知道
some words
一些字
and this is fine for shorter programs but once you have longer ones it can be
这对于较短的程序来说很好但一旦你有更长的
really confusing meaning you want to replace this with
真的很混乱意思是你想用它替换它
something that actually means something it is a really common thing that you
真正有意义的东西这是很常见的事情
write a program you don't look at the program for half a year then you come
写一个你不看的程序计划半年然后你来
back to the program and you have no idea what you did half a year ago
回到程序，你不知道半年前你做了什么
happens to literally every programmer and naming your variables properly makes
几乎每个程序员都会遇到这样的情况并正确命名你的变量使得
it a lot easier to read what your code actually does
更容易阅读你的代码实际上确实如此
so name your variables properly there's one more thing that i really
所以正确命名你的变量还有一件事我真的
want to do because now that we have variables we get a few more math
想做，因为现在我们有了变量我们得到更多的数学
operations although those math operations are going
运营尽管那些数学运算正在进行
to look a bit weird they are looking like this we have plus
看起来有点奇怪他们看起来像这样，我们有加号
equal minus equal divide equal and multiply equal
等于减等于除等于并且乘以相等
i think to explain what they do let's do an example
我想解释一下他们做了什么让我们做吧一个例子
let's say i have num one is equal to one a really basic variable and i want to
假设我有 num 一等于 1一个非常基本的变量，我想要
increase the value of this num by a certain amount for example let's say by
将此 num 的值增加 a一定数量例如让我们说
5. to do that
5.要做到这一点
i could write some code like this that num1 is itself plus 5.
我可以写一些这样的代码num1 本身加 5。
and this would be fine but this also feels kind of clumsy
这很好，但这也感觉有点笨拙
and for that we have these operators here
为此我们有这些运算符这里
what you would do instead in python is something like this
在 python 中你会做的是像这样的东西
we have num itself then plus equal 5
我们有 num 本身然后加上等于 5
and those two code snippets here do exactly the same
和那两个这里的代码片段的作用完全相同
thing they take the original variable and then add a certain value to it
他们采用原始变量然后给它加上一定的值
let's do this in code actually i think that's going to make more sense
实际上我认为让我们在代码中做到这一点这会更有意义
i want to create another variable let me call it num1 and by default this one is
我想创建另一个变量让我称之为 num1，默认情况下这个是
10. and now this 10 i want to increase by 5
10.现在这个 10 我想增加 5
again and
再次和
this could look like this i want to get my original num1 and then
这可能看起来像这样我想得到我原来的 num1 然后
add 5 to it
添加5 到它
if i now print num 1
如果我现在打印数字 1
we are getting the value all the way at the end which is 15 again
我们一直在获得价值结局又是15
i guess let me use different numbers so we get some different results
我想让我使用不同的数字我们得到一些不同的结果
now we get 20 which is 10 the value of num1 plus 10.
现在我们得到 20，即 10 的值num1 加 10。
but again this here is kind of clumsy and python gets around this biting plus
但这又有点笨拙python 绕过了这个棘手的问题
equal and then we are adding 10 meaning now we are taking the original
等于然后我们加上 10意思是现在我们正在采用原始的
value of num1 and adding 10 towards it and assigning all of this again to num1
num1 的值并加 10并将所有这些再次分配给 num1
and if i run this we are getting the same result
如果我运行这个我们会得到相同的结果
so if i spell this out
所以如果我把这个拼出来
a bit better these two lines here are doing the exact
好一些这两行在这里做的正是
same thing and this is working with the other math
一样这是与其他数学一起工作的
operators as well for example we could have minus equal and we are getting zero
运营商以及例如我们可以负数等于，我们得到零
we could add multiply equal which is getting us a hundred and we
我们可以加上乘法等于这让我们得到了一百，我们
have divide equal which is getting us one
平分秋色，这让我们一
and if you just want to update a variable this is how you would do it
如果您只想更新变量 这就是你要做的
and this is now bringing us to the exercise for this part and what i want
现在我们就到了这部分的练习以及我想要的
you guys to do is to create a variable that has some kind of snake case and try
你们要做的就是创建一个变量有某种蛇盒并尝试
to use a bit of a longer word assign a value to it and on the next
使用更长一点的词为其分配一个值并在下一个
line increase this value by 20 and then on the third line print the
行将该值增加 20然后在第三行打印
variable
多变的
let's get started by creating a really long
让我们开始创建一个真的很长
variable name
多变的姓名
that is
那是
a bit
A少量
annoying obviously you would never use something
恼人的显然你永远不会使用某些东西
like this in practice but i hope you get the idea
在实践中就像这样，但我希望你能得到这个想法
and the value i want to assign is let's go with 10.
我想要分配的值是让我们和 10 一起去。
on the next line i want to get my really long variable
在下一行我想得到我的很长的变量
name that is a bit annoying and i realized i do have a typo let me fix it
名字有点烦人，我意识到我确实有一个拼写错误，让我修复它
really quick and i want to increase this value so i want plus equal and i think i
真的很快，我想增加这个值所以我想要加等于并且我想我
said 20. and now finally i want to print my
说20。现在我终于想打印我的
really long variable name that is a bit annoying
变量名真的有点长恼人的
and if i print this we are getting 30. and with that we have variables which is
如果我打印这个我们会得到 30。这样我们就有了变量
an incredibly important concept in this part we are going to talk about
一个极其重要的概念在这一部分我们将讨论
functions and all that functions are are special
功能所有的功能都是特殊的
commands in python we have actually seen one already and that is print which is
我们实际见过的Python命令已经有一个了，那就是打印
printing a certain kind of text this one you should be really familiar with at
打印某种文本你应该非常熟悉
this point but there are quite a few more for
这点但还有很多
example len gives you the amount of characters in a word
例如 len 给出的数量单词中的字符
and another one would be abs or absolute which is giving you the absolute number
另一种是abs 或absolute这给了你绝对数字
which in practice just means if we have a negative one and we're using apps this
这实际上意味着如果我们有负面的，我们正在使用这个应用程序
is turning into a one although to understand functions we need
正在变成一个尽管为了理解我们需要的功能
one really important concept and that is brackets
一个非常重要的概念，那就是括号
meaning when we're adding brackets after the name of the function
意思是当我们在后面添加括号时函数的名称
we are calling it and this we have done multiple times
我们称之为我们已经做过很多次了
already anytime we use print we have called a function by adding brackets
每当我们使用印刷品时，我们就有通过添加括号来调用函数
afterwards and inside of the brackets we are adding what is called arguments
之后在括号内我们添加所谓的参数
for example for print we can add any kind of argument and this is then what
例如对于打印我们可以添加任何一种争论，这就是
we are going to print in the case of well print
我们将在以下情况下打印印刷得好
and let's have a look at all of this in code i want to once again start with
让我们看看这一切我想再次开始的代码
print and this is the name of the function
打印，这是的名称功能
and to call it i need brackets and what we're adding in here is the
为了称呼它，我需要括号我们在这里添加的是
argument which right now is the word which
现在这个词的争论哪个
that's called test and what this function does is it prints the word so
这就是所谓的测试，这是什么函数的作用是打印单词 so
we can see it another function that we can use is called len and in here
我们可以看到它的另一个函数可以使用叫做 len 的东西，在这里
we could add another word if i run the code now we can't see
我们可以添加另一个如果我现在运行代码我们就看不到
any result because this is only giving us a value but we're not doing anything
任何结果，因为这只是给出我们有一个价值观，但我们什么也没做
with that value and to overcome that we have to print the result
具有这种价值并克服我们必须打印结果
and now if we run this we are getting 12 and this 12 means that inside of this
现在如果我们运行这个我们会得到 12这个 12 意味着在这个里面
word we have 12 characters we have 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 and 12.
单词 我们有 12 个字符 我们有 1 2 34 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 和 12。
notice here that python is counting a space as well
注意这里 python 正在计算空间也是如此
and all of this could also be used with variables for example this len
所有这些也可以与变量例如 this len
i could assign to the variable word length and then on the next line i want
我可以分配给变量单词长度然后在我想要的下一行
to print my word length and i get 12 again
打印我的字长，我得到 12再次
and this would be a slightly cleaner way of doing this although the previous one
这将是一个稍微干净的方式这样做虽然前一个
would also be perfectly fine and another function we can also work
也很好还有另一个我们也可以使用的函数
with is absolute or abs and in here i can add negative 50 and
with 是绝对或abs在这里我可以添加负 50 和
for this once again i have to print the result otherwise we wouldn't see it
为此我必须再次打印结果否则我们就看不到它
but now if i run the code we are getting 50 meaning abs removes this negative 50.
但现在如果我运行我们得到的代码50 意味着abs 消除了这个负数50。
and there's one more really important thing that you can also do with
还有一点非常重要你也可以做的事情
functions that right now we always only added a
功能现在我们总是只添加一个
single argument but for some functions you could add more than that print is
单个参数但对于某些函数你可以添加比打印更多的内容
actually one example of that let's put this on a separate line
实际上就是一个例子让我们把它放在单独的一行上
so far for print i always added one argument
到目前为止，对于打印我总是添加一个争论
but what i can do i can add a comma and then add
但我能做什么我可以添加一个逗号然后添加
another argument
其他争论
and now i have two arguments if i run the code
现在如果我跑步我有两个论点代码
i get one argument and then print adds the other argument and print
我得到一个参数，然后打印添加另一个参数并打印
accepts an unlimited number of other arguments
接受无限数量的其他论据
meaning if i run this now we are getting more and more arguments
意思是如果我现在运行这个我们收到越来越多的争论
the important thing here is you always add one argument then a comma and then
这里最重要的是你永远添加一个参数，然后添加一个逗号，然后
another argument another comma and so on depending on what the function accepts
另一个参数另一个逗号等等取决于函数接受的内容
and some functions only accept a single argument for example absolute only takes
有些函数只接受一个例如绝对参数只需要
one if i added another we will get an error and that is abs
如果我添加另一个我们会得到一个错误，那就是abs
takes exactly one argument and we have given two python here is very clear
只需要一个参数，我们就有这里给出两个 python 非常清楚
apps only gets one argument but that is essentially the basic concept of calling
应用程序只得到一个参数，但那就是本质上是调用的基本概念
functions now for the exercise i want you guys to
功能现在我希望你们进行练习
do some research online and i want you guys to look up the
在线做一些研究我希望你们查一下
function called max and try to figure out what it does and
称为 max 的函数并尝试弄清楚它的作用
call it inside of this code
在这段代码中调用它
here i have google open although you could use any search engine
这里我有谷歌打开虽然你可以使用任何搜索引擎
and to learn coding you have to do a ton of research so it's a really good idea
要学习编码，你必须做很多事情研究所以这是一个非常好的主意
to start early and what we want to do right now is look
早点开始我们现在想做的是看看
at the python function max
在Python函数中最大限度
and let's just see what we get in here we can see a bunch of websites
让我们看看我们得到了什么在这里我们可以看到一堆网站
and for python all of them are basically fine
对于 python 来说，所有这些基本上都是美好的
w3schools program is are really big ones geeks for geeks is
w3schools 计划是对于极客而言，极客确实是个大人物
also really big but the one you probably want to use the most is
也很大，但你可能会最想用的是
docs.python.org this is the official python
docs.python.org这是官方的Python
documentation if i click on this one
文档如果我点击这个
we can see all of the built-in functions for python
我们可以看到所有的内置函数对于蟒蛇
and the one i'm looking for is called max
我正在寻找的那个叫做最大限度
if i click on this i get a ton of information the most important one is
如果我点击这个我会得到很多信息中最重要的是
right in the beginning it's returning the largest item in an
就在一开始它返回最大的项目
iterable or the largest of two or more arguments
可迭代的或两个或多个参数中最大的一个
what an iterable is we have no idea so far but what we do know is the largest
我们不知道什么是可迭代的很远，但我们所知道的是最大的
of two or more arguments so let's have a look at that one
两个或多个参数让我们看一下那个
once again we are in the code and i want to use my max function and in here i
我们再次进入代码，我想要使用我的 max 函数，在这里我
want to just add a couple of random numbers
只想添加几个随机的数字
now i once again have to print the result
现在我必须再次打印结果
and if i run this i get 10.
如果我运行这个我得到10.
and well we get 10 because max is selecting the largest argument that we
我们得到 10 因为 max 是选择我们认为最大的参数
are passing into it which right now is 10.
正在进入它，现在是10.
and well that is basically what it does if you understand this one you also
这基本上就是它的作用如果你明白这一点，你也
understand min which is taking the lowest number which in our case is 2.
了解正在采取的分钟最小的数字，在我们的例子中是 2。
and with that we have covered functions besides functions we also have methods
这样我们就涵盖了函数除了函数之外我们还有方法
and especially for beginners methods and functions can be very similar so let's
特别是对于初学者的方法和功能可能非常相似，所以让我们
compare the two in the most basic sense a method does
比较两者从最基本的意义上讲，方法的作用是
the same as a function the only difference being that the method is
与函数相同唯一区别在于该方法是
always attached to an object which means
总是附着在一个物体上意思是
we are still calling a method with the name of the method followed by brackets
我们仍在调用一个方法方法名称，后跟方括号
and this is still called calling a method just like a function
这仍然称为调用方法就像函数一样
we can also still pass an argument in here this works in exactly the same way
我们仍然可以传递一个参数这里的工作方式完全相同
the difference is that methods always are connected to an object and this
区别在于方法总是连接到一个对象并且这个
happens with a dot which in practice looks like this
发生在实践中的一个点看起来像这样
we always start with some kind of object in this case it's a word it could also
我们总是从某种物体开始在这种情况下，它也可以是一个词
be a number or any other data type in python
是数字或任何其他数据类型Python
this is then followed by a dot and this is really important then we have the
然后是一个点，然后是真的很重要，那么我们就有了
method name and then we have brackets with whatever argument you want to put
方法名称，然后我们有括号无论你想提出什么论点
in and then all of this does a certain
在然后所有这一切都会产生一定的影响
thing just like a function what this thing could be is for example
就像函数一样例如，这件事可能是什么
we can use the upper method and this one takes a word and returns the same word
我们可以使用上面的方法和这个接受一个单词并返回相同的单词
all in uppercase letters and i think this example also
全部大写字母我认为这个例子也是
illustrates why we have functions and methods
说明了为什么我们有函数和方法
sometimes functionality only makes sense for a certain kind of data type or for
有时只有功能才有意义对于某种数据类型或
certain objects with a certain data type and
具有特定数据类型的特定对象和
here the upper case really only makes sense for a word there's no uppercase
这里的大写字母实际上只能使单词的意义没有大写
for a number for example and this is why we have methods
例如对于一个数字这就是为什么我们有方法
and i suppose we can implement all of this a bit more practically so let's
我想我们可以实现所有这更实际一些，所以让我们
have a look at all of this in code once again i have a completely empty python
在代码中看一下所有这些我又得到了一条完全空的蟒蛇
file and i want to create a new variable let's call it test
文件，我想创建一个新变量我们称之为测试
and the value for this test is going to be a word
这个测试的值是是一个词
to get started i want to print my test variable
首先我想打印我的测试多变的
and if i print it we are getting a word so far all of this should be very
如果我打印它，我们会得到一个词到目前为止，这一切应该是非常
familiar and the method we have seen we are
熟悉的我们所看到的方法是
calling with a dot after the word and then the name is upper and don't forget
在单词 and 后面加一个点来调用那么名字就在上面，别忘了
the brackets if i run this now we can see a word all in uppercase letters
如果我现在运行这个括号，我们可以查看全部为大写字母的单词
and with that we have called a method what we can also do let me demonstrate
我们调用了一个方法我们还可以做什么让我演示一下
it first and then explain i can cut out this upper here
先解释一下我可以删掉上面这个这里
and run it on this variable if i run all of this now we are getting
并在这个变量上运行它如果我现在运行所有这些，我们会得到
the same outcome and why this happened i will explain in
同样的结果为什么会发生这种情况我将在
the next section but in the most basic sense
下一节但在最基本的部分感觉
methods always change a value where you change that value is really up
方法总是改变一个值你改变的地方这个值真的上升了
to you in the first example
给你在第一个例子中
we created the word and then when we are creating the word we are calling the
我们创造了这个词，然后当我们创建我们称之为的词
upper method and this is returning
上法这正在回归
the uppercase letters and storing them in the test variable and once we have
大写字母并存储它们在测试变量中，一旦我们有
that we are printing the test variable that's all that's happening here
我们正在打印测试变量这就是这里发生的一切
and then the second example looked like this
然后是第二个例子看起来像这样
and in here we first created the word and saved the
在这里我们首先创建了这个词并保存了
word inside of the test variable after that we are still printing the
测试变量内的单词之后我们仍然打印
test variable but now when we are printing it we are modifying it with the
测试变量，但现在当我们打印它，我们正在修改它
upper method which is giving us the uppercase word the result for both of
上面的方法给了我们大写单词的结果
these examples is the same how this works in detail you are going
这些例子是相同的这具体是如何运作的
to understand very soon for now i'm going to call the upper
很快就能明白现在我要打电话给上层
method when i create this value now obviously this example really isn't
当我创建这个值时的方法现在显然这个例子确实不是
all that useful let's do something more relevant
所有有用的让我们做一些更相关的事情
let's say we have some kind of user name
假设我们有某种用户姓名
and we are expecting something like john smith
我们期待着像约翰这样的人史密斯
where we have a first name and a surname but since you are allowing user input
我们有名字和姓氏但由于您允许用户输入
this might instead look something like this we have a typo and maybe we have
这可能看起来像这是我们有一个错字，也许我们有
some access at the end and let me add another typo in here
最后有一些访问权限，让我添加这里还有一个错字
this would still be valid user input but
这仍然是有效的用户输入，但是
obviously it would look terrible which is something we couldn't use for
显然它看起来会很糟糕这是我们不能用的东西
our purposes and methods are really good to clean all of this up
我们的目的和方法真的很好清理这一切
and the one method we could start with is called title
我们可以从第一种方法开始被称为标题
and let me print the username and see what that one does
让我打印用户名看看那人做什么
now we get always let's expand this a tiny bit
现在我们总是让我们扩展这个一点点
we are always getting the first letters uppercase and then every other letter is
我们总是收到第一个字母大写，然后所有其他字母都是
lowercase meaning now we have john smith in the proper spelling at least for
小写意味着现在我们有约翰·史密斯至少以正确的拼写
names meaning with this we get rid of this o
名字这意味着我们摆脱了这个o
and this i what you can also do is combine
而这个我你还可以做的是结合
different methods what you do by adding another dot after
不同的方法在后面添加另一个点可以做什么
whatever value you want to change and then calling the other method in my case
无论你想改变什么值然后在我的例子中调用另一个方法
for this one i want to get rid of these two axes
对于这个我想摆脱这两个轴
and for that i need this strip method and what this one does is it looks at
为此我需要这种剥离方法这个所做的就是它看着
the right and the left side of any word and removes a certain kind of value
任何单词的右侧和左侧并删除某种价值
whatever we specify inside of the arguments
无论我们在里面指定什么论据
and in my case i want to get rid of these two axes
就我而言，我想摆脱这两个轴
which means i want to add the string
意思是我想添加字符串
x in here and if i run this now
x在这里如果我现在运行这个
we can see there is no difference so what went wrong here and i think you can
我们可以看到没有区别所以这里出了什么问题，我想你可以
already tell what the problem might be in the original word the two axes were
已经告诉了问题可能是什么在原文中，两个轴是
uppercase and this is what we are trying to remove
大写，这就是我们正在尝试的去除
but what this strip method here sees is this string
但是这里的剥离方法看到了什么是这个字符串
changed by this title meaning strip doesn't see a capital x it
被这个标题改变了意思是 strip 看不到大写 x 它
sees a lowercase x and for python again remember
看到一个小写的 x对于 python 再次记住
capitalization really matters an uppercase and the lowercase letter are
大小写确实很重要大写和小写字母分别是
two completely different things for python
两个完全不同的东西Python
to fix that all we need is a lowercase letter and if i run this now we have
为了解决这个问题，我们只需要一个小写字母信如果我现在运行这个我们有
removed the two values you might be asking yourself what
删除了两个值你可能会问自己什么
methods are available and there are a couple of ways to achieve that
方法是可用的，并且有一个有几种方法可以实现这一目标
if you want to stay inside of a code editor you would use the dir function
如果你想留在代码中编辑器你会使用 dir 函数
and in here you can pass in any value to figure out what methods it has
在这里你可以将任何值传递给弄清楚它有什么方法
for example i could pass in the user name in here and if i run the code now
例如我可以传入用户名称在这里，如果我现在运行代码
nothing happens the reason is that this function only
什么都没发生原因是这个功能仅
returns all of the methods it doesn't print them for that we again need the
返回所有它不返回的方法打印它们，我们再次需要
print function now if we run this we get something that
打印功能现在如果我们运行这个我们会得到一些东西
looks a fair bit more technical and you have two main things in here
看起来更有技术含量这里有两件主要的事情
you start with all of this stuff here a lot of names with double underscores
你从这里开始所有这些东西很多名字带有双下划线
before and after the word like this lte here we have two
在单词之前和之后就像这个LTE，我们有两个
underscores before and two underscores afterwards what these mean we're going
前面有一个下划线和两个下划线之后这些意味着我们要去
to cover much later what you want to focus on for now is all the stuff down
稍后再介绍您想要的内容现在的重点是所有的东西都下来了
here these are the methods that you could be
这里这些是你可以采用的方法
using and we have actually used a couple of them already for example strip we
使用并且我们实际上已经使用了几个例如，我们已经剥离了其中的一些
have used title and we have used upper i guess we can do one more method and
已经使用了标题，我们已经使用了上部我想我们可以再做一种方法
let's use is alpha what this method does is it checks if the values inside of a
让我们使用 is alpha 这个方法的作用它检查 a 内的值是否
word are in the alphabet meaning they are not numbers
这个词在字母表中意味着它们不是数字
let me close this one and instead of the dir function
让我关闭这个，而不是目录函数
i want to print user name and then dot is alpha
我想打印用户名然后点是阿尔法
and don't forget to call it and now if i run this
并且不要忘记调用它现在如果我运行这个
this is saying false the reason for that is that inside of
这是假的其原因在于
this word we have one value that isn't inside of the alphabet and that is this
这个词我们有一个值，但不是在字母表里面，就是这个
space here if i remove it and run out of this again
这里有空间如果我删除它并再次用完
now it says true meaning every letter inside of the word
现在它说的是真的表示单词中的每个字母
is inside of the alphabet if i added any kind of number in here
在字母表里面如果我在这里添加任何类型的数字
this would go back to false although i don't really want to do that
这会回到 false虽然我真的不想那么做
but this would be another way to check something in your word that may become
但这将是另一种检查方式你的话中的某些东西可能会变成
useful especially when you work with something like user input you might want
特别是当你与您可能想要的诸如用户输入之类的东西
to check if there are numbers inside of the name
检查里面是否有数字名字
however if i go back to the dir function run this again
但是如果我回到 dir 函数再次运行这个
this list here still isn't that useful because you have a name but you don't
这个列表仍然没有那么有用因为你有名字但你没有
really have an explanation of what the specific method does
确实有一个解释具体方法是
and well to really understand what a method does you do want to use google
并很好地真正理解什么是你想使用谷歌的方法吗
and if you want to google for specific
和如果你想谷歌具体
things you need to know their names for example in python or in really any
你需要知道它们的名字的东西python 中的示例或任何其他示例
programming language a word is always called a string
编程语言总是一个词称为字符串
we're going to cover that in much more detail in the next major section
我们将在更多内容中介绍这一点下一个主要部分详细介绍
just remember for now a word in programming is always called a string
暂时记住一句话编程总是称为字符串
and with that let's do some googling in here i want to look for python string
然后我们用谷歌搜索一下在这里我想寻找 python 字符串
methods and then i am getting a ton of different
方法然后我得到了很多不同的
results and again all of these websites here work quite well
结果以及所有这些网站这里工作得很好
the one that is the official documentation by python is called
那个是官方的python 的文档称为
docs.python.org and this one says built in types python something something
docs.python.org ，这个说已构建在类型中 python 某事某事
documentation and in here on the left side you can see
文档在左边你可以看到
all of the data types again we're going to cover those in a lot more detail very
我们再次讨论所有数据类型非常详细地介绍这些内容
soon for example here you have numeric types
很快例如这里你有数字类型
we have sequence types and then we have text sequence type str which stands for
我们有序列类型，然后我们有文本序列类型 str 代表
string methods this is the one i want to look at
字符串方法，这是我想要的看着
and in here you have a very long list let me minimize this part you have a
这里有一个很长的清单让我最小化这部分你有一个
very long list of methods that you could be using
你可以使用的方法清单很长正在使用
along with a fair bit of text explaining what they do
以及相当多的文字解释他们做什么
for example here is is alpha the one we have just looked at
例如这里是 alpha我们刚刚看过的那个
and if you have any kind of problem yourself you would probably read through
如果您有任何问题你自己可能会通读
this list and try to figure out what method works for your purpose
这个列表并尝试找出什么方法适合您的目的
and i suppose let's have a look at another website for example w3schools is
我想让我们看一下另一个网站，例如 w3schools 是
also really good and in here we also have a long list of all of the
也很好，在这里我们还有一长串所有的
methods the list contains the same number of methods and in here let's say
列表包含相同的方法方法的数量，在这里让我们说
if i click on is alpha we get to another website we have an
如果我点击是阿尔法我们访问另一个网站，我们有一个
explanation along with an example you honestly can use any of these
解释和例子老实说你可以使用其中任何一个
websites they all cover basically the same thing
他们基本上都涵盖了网站一样
all right with that we can do an exercise
好吧，我们可以做一个锻炼
and in my case i want you guys to do some research because i have an exercise
就我而言，我希望你们这样做一些研究，因为我有一个练习
string that is saying i like
细绳这就是说我喜欢
puppies and what i want you guys to do is to
小狗我希望你们做的是
find a method that replaces the word puppies with let's say kitties or any
找到一个方法来替换这个单词小狗和小猫或任何
other animal that you really like so pause the video now and try to figure
您真正喜欢的其他动物所以现在暂停视频并尝试弄清楚
this one out yourself
这个你自己出
in my case i want to look for python a string remember this is just a word and
就我而言，我想寻找 python a字符串记住这只是一个单词并且
i want to replace a let's say a value if i do this i already get one answer
我想替换一个值如果我这样做我已经得到一个答案
predicted by google that is called replace
谷歌预测称为代替
although if i go down i see replace a bunch more times and well
虽然如果我下去我会看到更换多聚几次就好了
i just had to look at one of them doesn't really matter which one it is
我只需要看看其中的一个哪一个并不重要
let's choose program miss this time this one is really good and then here we
我们选择这次错过的节目吧这个真的很好，然后我们就在这里
have an explanation of what this one does we have an example
对此有一个解释我们有例子吗
and then we have the syntax so how we would use it and in here
然后我们有了语法，那么我们如何会使用它并在这里
we have a string so any kind of word then the replace method then we have an
我们有一个字符串，所以任何类型的单词然后是替换方法然后我们有一个
old value a new value and a count and down here then we can see how we
旧值、新值和计数在这里我们可以看到我们如何
would use these values the old value here means the value we want to replace
将使用这些值旧值这里的意思是我们要替换的值
the new value is what we want to replace it with
新值就是我们要替换的值它与
and then the count basically means if we have the
进而计数基本上意味着如果我们有
old value multiple times how many times we want to replace it
旧值乘以多少倍我们想更换它
and this one is optional so you could leave it out entirely and with that we
这是可选的，所以你可以完全忽略它，这样我们
can implement all of this back in my code i want to add a dot and
可以实现这一切回到我的代码中，我想添加一个点和
then the replace method and in here we first of all need the old
然后是替换方法在这里我们首先需要旧的
word which in my case is puppies after that we need the new word and this
在我的例子中是小狗这个词之后我们需要新词和这个
in my case is going to be kittens although any kind of word would be fine
就我而言将是小猫虽然任何词都可以
in here and these two values would be mandatory
在这里这两个值是强制性的
so we have to have them but once we have them
所以我们必须拥有它们但一旦我们拥有它们
we can print the result and run this now and all the way at the bottom we get i
我们可以打印结果并立即运行一直到底部我们得到 i
like kittens we have successfully replaced puppies with kittens we could
像小猫一样，我们已经成功我们可以用小猫代替小狗
also add a third value and this one determines how many times we would want
还添加第三个值和这个决定了我们想要多少次
to replace this value let me actually paste it in a few times
替换这个值让我实际粘贴几次
here now we have puppies four times
这里现在我们已经养了四只小狗了
by default i am replacing all of them with kittens
默认情况下我将替换所有这些与小猫
meaning what i get is i like kittens kittens kittens and kittens
意思是我得到的是我喜欢小猫小猫 小猫和小猫
but if i add another value in here and this has to be a number let's say i want
但如果我在这里添加另一个值并且这必须是一个数字，假设我想要
to add a 2. now if i run this
添加 2。现在如果我运行这个
i am only replacing the first two instances of puppies with kittens but
我只替换前两个小狗和小猫的例子，但是
after that i keep my puppies around and again there are a lot more methods
之后我就把我的小狗留在身边还有很多方法
far too many to cover them in one video what you basically do as a programmer is
太多了，无法在一个视频中涵盖它们作为一名程序员，你基本上做的是
you keep on working and you learn more and more methods as you go along but
你继续工作并且学到更多以及更多的方法，但是
that being said even after a few years you are not going to know all of them
即使在几年后也这么说你不会知道他们所有人
for that you have google and you just look up different methods
为此，你有谷歌，你只需查找不同的方法
i have been programming for years and i still forget them all the time it's
我已经编程多年了，而且我仍然总是忘记他们
really not a major issue and with that we have methods
确实不是一个大问题这样我们就有了方法
in this part we are going to cover return and return is one of the most
在这一部分我们将介绍退货和退货是最多的之一
important concepts in all of programming so let's talk about it
所有编程中的重要概念那么我们来谈谈吧
in the most basic sense return is the glue that connects everything in python
从最基本的意义上来说，回报是连接Python中所有东西的胶水
what that means is that any operation returns a value
这意味着任何操作返回一个值
for example if we calculate 2 plus 2 f4 is being returned
例如，如果我们计算 2 加 2 f4正在被退回
we also have functions and methods and those can also return values for example
我们也有函数和方法例如，它们也可以返回值
upper returns the uppercase letters of a string
upper 返回 a 的大写字母细绳
and by combining different return values you are creating more complex logic
并通过组合不同的返回值你正在创建更复杂的逻辑
and what you are basically going to do in programming is combining different
以及你基本上要做的事情在编程中是将不同的
return values to create something more complex
返回值以创造更多东西复杂的
and an example here could look something like this
这里的一个例子可能看起来有些东西像这样
just read through this and try to think of what the outcome here is going to be
阅读本文并尝试思考这里的结果将会是什么
and let's go through this line step by step
让我们逐步完成这一行步
we are always starting with the innermost part in this case it is a word
我们总是从在这种情况下，最里面的部分是一个单词
and then we are applying right now the first function which is len this is
然后我们现在正在申请第一个函数是 len 这是
going to return a value and the value it is going to return is 6 or the amount of
将返回一个值及其值将返回 6 或数量
letters inside of this word and next up this value we are going to
这个单词里面的字母接下来我们将这个值
multiply with negative 10. this again is going to return another
乘以负10。这又会返回另一个
value negative 60. this is then going to return 60 because the absolute function
值为负 60。这将是返回 60 因为绝对函数
always turns a negative number into a positive number
总是把负数变成正数
and this would be one example of the return statement where we are taking
这就是一个例子return 声明我们正在采取的地方
specific functionalities like the length function here and then use the value
特定功能，例如长度在这里使用函数，然后使用该值
they return in another operation like this 6 multiplied by negative 10.
他们在另一次行动中返回，例如这个 6 乘以负 10。
what you absolutely have to understand is that every operation in python
你绝对必须明白的是 python 中的每个操作
returns a value and then this value you can combine with other operations like
返回一个值，然后你可以使用这个值可以与其他操作结合使用，例如
using it in another function or with another method or in a math operation
在另一个函数中使用它或与另一种方法或在数学运算中
it's really up to you but this is a really powerful system that allows you
这真的取决于你，但这是一个真正强大的系统可以让你
to add lots of logic on a single line of code
在一行中添加大量逻辑代码
let's play around with this i think that is going to be really important
让我们玩一下我认为将会非常重要
once more completely empty python file and let me create a test
再次完全空的 python 文件让我创建一个测试
variable let's use the example from the previous
多变的让我们使用前面的例子
part where we had e word and then we used upper
我们有 e 词的部分然后我们二手鞋面
let me print it as well and we are getting a word all in uppercase letters
让我也打印出来，我们是获取一个全部为大写字母的单词
and i think i want to have a bit of white
和我想我想要一点白色
space around it that makes my life a bit easier
它周围的空间这让我的生活变得更轻松
what happened in here is we have a word and then we're using the
这里发生的事情是我们有一个词，然后我们使用
upper method to change the word what this combined statement here
上面的方法来改变单词这里的组合语句是什么
returns is a word all in uppercase letters
返回的是一个全部大写的单词字母
and once we have that we can add another method to it and the
一旦我们有了这个我们可以向其中添加另一个方法
method we could be using here the one we have already seen let's use replace
我们可以在这里使用的方法已经看到让我们使用替换
and what we want to do in here is replace the letter a
我们想要在这里做的是替换字母a
with the letter let's say x and now if i run this
加上字母 x现在如果我运行这个
we have x word what happened here is that this
我们有 x 个词这里发生的事情是这样的
first statement returned e-word this one should be obvious by itself
第一个语句返回 e-word 这个本身应该是显而易见的
after that we have used the upper method to turn
在那之后我们已经使用了上面的方法来转
this e-word into e word all in uppercase letters after that
这个 e 词变成 e之后单词全部大写
we have used the replace method to change this a
我们使用了替换方法改变这个
to an x
到一个x
and we could continue this forever for example what we could do for example
我们可以永远继续下去例如我们可以做什么
what we could be doing is wrap all of this inside of the len
我们可以做什么将所有这些都包裹在镜头内
function and now if i run this
功能现在如果我运行这个
we are getting six we start with a word
我们有六个我们从一个词开始
then we are turning all of this into uppercase letters
然后我们把这一切变成大写字母
then we are changing the first letter from an a to an x
然后我们改变第一个字母从 a 到 x
so what we have inside of these brackets is x
所以我们在这些括号内有什么是 x
word all in uppercase letter and what we do then is use the len
单词全部大写然后我们要做的就是使用 len
method to count how many characters we have inside of this word
方法来计算我们有多少个字符这个词里面有
which right now is 6 and this is what we are storing inside of the variable i
现在是 6 这就是我们存储在变量 i 的内部
hope this makes sense it is a really important concept to understand
希望这是有道理的，这真的是需要理解的重要概念
all it means is every time you perform some kind of operation a different kind
这意味着每次你表演的时候某种操作 另一种操作
of value is being returned and then this value is what you are working with next
的值被返回，然后这个价值是你接下来要处理的事情
you really have to be aware that every operation returns some kind of value
你真的必须意识到每一个操作返回某种值
although this can be kind of weird sometimes
虽然这可能有点奇怪有时
one really good example let me remove the white space here
一个非常好的例子让我删除这里的空白
and then let's play around with the print function
然后让我们玩一下打印功能
because this one by itself just prints whatever we pass inside
因为这个本身只是打印无论我们在里面传递什么
so what's going to happen when we print a print function
那么当我们打印时会发生什么打印功能
and let's see we are getting 6 and none
让我们看看我们得到了 6 个，但没有
the 6 we are getting from this inner part
我们从这个内在得到的 6部分
and the none is what gets returned by a print statement and none is an actual
none 是 a 返回的内容print 语句，没有一个是实际的
data type in python you can work with it but it basically denotes the absence of
python 中的数据类型你可以使用它但它基本上表示不存在
a value but again print is returning something
一个值但 print 再次返回一些东西
although in this case what it is returning is the data type none i hope
虽然在这种情况下它是什么返回的是数据类型，我希望没有
you get the idea here now for this part i am not going to do
你明白了现在对于这部分我不打算做
an exercise but i would recommend you to play around with this yourself in your
一个练习，但我建议你自己尝试一下
own time and see what you can do yourself
自己的时间，看看你能做什么你自己
throughout this series we are going to do a lot of examples so there's plenty
在整个系列中，我们将做了很多例子，所以有很多
of time for practice a really important thing you have to
练习时间你必须做的一件非常重要的事情
understand is comments and comments do not influence your code whatsoever they
理解就是评论和评论吗不会影响您的代码
are just explaining it or well they are commenting what your code does
只是解释它或者他们是评论你的代码的作用
and you really want to use comments quite extensively because they are
并且你确实想使用评论相当广泛，因为它们是
really useful to help how you organize your code and to understand what it does
对帮助你如何组织非常有用你的代码并理解它的作用
especially if you work in a team you want to add lots of comments because
尤其是当你在一个团队中工作时想添加很多评论，因为
other people would really appreciate it it also works as a really good reminder
其他人会非常感激的它也是一个很好的提醒
for your own code it's a really common thing for programmers that you write
对于您自己的代码来说，这很常见你写的程序员的东西
some code you don't look at it for half a year and then you have no idea what it
有些代码你看一半都不看一年之后你就不知道那是什么了
does anymore and writing comments is a very good way to remind yourself
不再做，写评论是一个提醒自己的好方法
there are two ways to write comments in python the first one is the hashtag
有两种写评论的方式python 第一个是主题标签
symbol anything on that line after the symbol is going to be ignored by python
符号该行之后的任何内容符号将被Python忽略
the other way is a triple quotation mark this one will comment out anything
另一种方式是三引号这个会注释掉任何东西
inside of these quotation marks this would also work over multiple lines
这些引号内的这个也可以在多行上工作
although technically it's not a comment we are going to learn later what this is
虽然从技术上来说这不是评论我们稍后会了解这是什么
but you can use it as a comment and let's say i have again a test variable
但你可以用它作为评论假设我又有一个测试变量
and this one is a really important value
这是一个非常重要的价值
i want to add a comment to explain that this is a really important
我想添加一条评论来解释这一点这是一个非常重要的
value we are just using the hashtag symbol and
价值我们只是使用主题标签符号并且
anything after that symbol is going to be a comment
该符号之后的任何内容都会成为评论
you can also add multiple if you want to add some specific kind of
您还可以添加多个如果你想添加一些特定类型的
styling which is fairly common actually what you see fairly often is programmers
实际上相当常见的样式你经常看到的是程序员
doing something like this then a comment and then
做这样的事情然后评论然后
something like this at the end i guess we can close this box as well to make it
我想最后是这样的我们也可以关闭这个框以使其
look a bit prettier with something like this you have a very clear section
用类似的东西看起来更漂亮一点这是你有一个非常清晰的部分
inside of your code but the important thing here to understand is that
在你的代码里面，但重要的是这里要理解的是
anything after hashtag symbol on the line of code is going to be ignored
主题标签符号之后的任何内容该行代码将被忽略
i guess let me actually run the code by printing the test variable run this now
我想让我实际运行代码打印测试变量立即运行
and we can only see a really important value
我们只能看到一个非常重要的价值
anything here and here was ignored by python you could also put
这里和这里的任何东西被 python 忽略你也可以把
this anywhere else in your code for example here and then this line of code
这在你的代码中的其他地方示例在这里，然后是这行代码
is going to be ignored entirely and something that would make more sense
将被完全忽略以及一些更有意义的东西
is you could comment out the entire line and that is basically it for the easiest
你可以注释掉整行吗这基本上是最简单的
kind of commenting although for this type of comment
某种评论虽然对于这种类型的评论
sublime has a very neat trick let me duplicate it a couple of times
Sublime 有一个非常巧妙的技巧让我复制几次
and imagine all of these are different examples of code
想象所有这些都是不同的代码示例
and you want to comment out all of them it would be really annoying to write a
你想把它们全部注释掉写一个真的很烦人
hashtag in front of every single line of code it just wouldn't be efficient
每行前面的主题标签编码效率不高
so what you can do is select all of them and then press ctrl and the forward
所以你能做的就是选择所有这些然后按ctrl键并前进
slash the one below the question mark if you do that all of them are being
如果是的话，请在问号下方划线你这样做，他们所有人都在
commented out and if you press it again the comment
注释掉了如果你再按一次评论
disappears which is what i am using all the time
消失这就是我一直在用的
and well with that we have the first type of comment what you can also do
这样我们就有了第一个评论类型 您还可以做什么
i guess let me add something below here let me call it another
我想让我在下面添加一些内容让我再叫它一个
variable let me just use some numbers
多变的让我用一些数字
and now duplicate this a few more times and again i want to comment out
现在再复制一些我一次又一次想评论
multiple lines of code for that i can use three quotation marks
多行代码为此我可以使用三个引号
at the start and at the end you can already tell the color was
在开始和结束时你已经可以看出颜色是
changed to gray and this tells us this is going to be a comment
变成灰色，这告诉我们这一点将成为一条评论
meaning if i run the code now we wouldn't be able to see it okay
意思是如果我现在运行代码我们看不到它，好吧
granted we wouldn't be able to see this at all so let me add a print statement
当然我们看不到这个无论如何，让我添加一条打印语句
in here with another variable
和另一个人在这里多变的
if i run this now we still cannot see the print statement because all of this
如果我现在运行这个我们仍然看不到print 语句因为所有这些
is a comment now this example here
是一条评论现在这个例子在这里
isn't exactly great because it's just lots of individual variables that i
并不完全好，因为它只是我有很多单独的变量
copy-pasted how you would use this kind of comment
复制粘贴你会如何使用这种评论
most of the time is by adding a couple of lines of code that explains something
大多数时候是添加几个解释某事的代码行
more complex let's say this is a really important
更复杂假设这是一个非常重要的
section it does a couple of things
部分它做了几件事
that we need for the code to work
那我们需要让代码正常工作
whatever you want to put in here after that you would have the rest of
无论你想在这里放什么之后你就会拥有剩下的
your code this is what you see fairly often and
你的代码这是你经常看到的情况
python actually incorporated this into its functionality we're going to see
python 实际上将其合并到我们将看到它的功能
this later on as well i guess for now the really important
稍后也会这样我想现在真正重要的是
thing you want to be aware of is this one here the simple kind of comment that
你想要知道的是这个这里有一个简单的评论
you can just put anywhere and that way you can either add explanations or
你可以把它放在任何地方您可以添加解释或
sections to your code which really help with the organization before we are
代码中真正有帮助的部分在我们之前与该组织
finishing off this section i want to talk a bit more about the lines of
我想完成这一部分多谈谈
execution logic because there are a few things that i haven't covered yet let's
执行逻辑因为有几个我还没有讲到的事情让我们
go through them the most important part is that how you see lines differs from
浏览其中最重要的部分就是你看待线条的方式与
how python sees them a really good example here
python 认为它们非常好例子在这里
is that python does not see empty lines in the code only you do and let me
python看不到空行在代码中只有你做并让我
illustrate what i mean if i start typing print and let's call
说明我的意思如果我开始输入 print 然后我们打电话
it first line and then duplicate the line and type in second line if i
它的第一行，然后复制行并在第二行输入 if i
execute this code i get first line and second line this is the stuff we have
执行这段代码我得到第一行并且第二行这是我们拥有的东西
already seen quite a lot it should be fairly obvious by this point
已经看过很多了，应该是这样在这一点上相当明显
however what happens if i add a space in here
但是如果我添加一个空格会发生什么这里
now we have a line of code nothing and another line of code
现在我们一行代码什么也没有，另一行代码
if i run all of this now we are still seeing the same result
如果我现在运行这一切，我们仍然看到相同的结果
the reason being that python ignores a line without any code
原因是 python 忽略了没有任何代码的行
if there's nothing on the line python is just going to ignore it
如果 python 线上没有任何内容只是会忽略它
meaning what you could be doing is add a huge amount of white space and it would
这意味着你可以做的是添加一个大量的空白，它会
not make any difference to your code which is very often something you do
对你的代码没有任何影响这是你经常做的事情
want to work with quite extensively because this is making it much easier to
想要广泛合作因为这使得更容易
organize your code especially if you add more comments with
组织你的代码特别是如果您添加更多评论
something like let's say second line and then this could be
比如第二行然后这可能是
the first line you could have a setup like this which
第一行你可以有这样的设置
in your case might make it much easier to read but all that python sees is this
在你的情况下可能会让事情变得更容易阅读但 python 看到的只是这个
line and this line here which is giving you a ton of work to
这条线和这里的这条线这给你带来了大量的工作
customize whatever explains your code the best but there are quite a few more
自定义任何解释您的代码的内容最好的，但还有很多
things that you should be aware of what i have also covered is that python
你应该知道的事情我还介绍了 python
ignores white space within a line meaning you can add as many spaces as
忽略行内的空白这意味着您可以添加尽可能多的空格
you want let's have a look at this one as well for example what i could be
你想让我们看一下这个以及例如我可以成为什么
doing inside of a string i could add as much white space as i want
在字符串内部做我可以添加为我想要多少空白
and this one is going to be reflected in the code i am running
这将反映在我正在运行的代码
what i can also do is add white space between the different
我还可以做什么是在不同的之间添加空白
parts of the code something like this would still work
部分代码像这样的东西仍然有效
just fine although granted in this case there
正好尽管在这种情况下被授予
isn't much reason to do something like this
没有太多理由做类似的事情这
i suppose something slightly more relevant might
我想稍微相关一些的东西可能
be we could add 1
是我们可以添加 1
plus 2 plus
加2加
4 and so on and for this line python would just
4 等等对于这一行，python 只会
ignore the white space meaning if i run this we are just getting the result
忽略空白意味着如果我运行我们刚刚得到结果
python doesn't care what you do between these lines
python 不关心你在两者之间做什么这些行
which i suppose you could be using for something like 5 multiplied by 5
我想你可能会用它类似于 5 乘以 5
and then plus 10
然后加上10
so you indicate which operation comes first the 5 multiplied by 5 although
所以你表明哪个操作来了首先是 5 乘以 5 虽然
still kind of a stretch what you can also do is use tab
仍然有些困难还可以使用选项卡
you can add this as much as you want python doesn't care it trades tabs like
你可以根据需要添加这个python 不在乎它像这样交换选项卡
white space that being said there's something really
空白话虽如此，确实有一些东西
important and that is
重要的那就是
python really cares about the indentation of an
Python真的很关心一个的缩进
entire line let me demonstrate this this is going to become incredibly important
整行让我演示一下这个将变得极其重要
later on what we have seen so far is that these
稍后的到目前为止我们所看到的是这些
annotations do not matter to python however what python does care about is
注释对 python 来说并不重要然而 python 真正关心的是
if this entire line is indented if i indent this entire line and run this
如果整行缩进如果我缩进整行并运行
again python is going to give me an error the error we are getting is called
python 又会给我一个error 我们收到的错误被称为
indentation error unexpected indent why that is you are going to learn later
缩进错误意外缩进原因那是你稍后会学到的
what you have to keep in mind for now is that inside of a line you can add as
你现在要记住的是您可以在行内添加为
much white space as you want but you couldn't add white space when you start
你想要多少空白，但你开始时无法添加空格
the line like here python is not going to like that but right there's one more
像这里这样的行 python 不会出现喜欢这个，但是还有一个
topic i do want to cover and that is how to break the line space
我确实想讨论的主题这就是如何打破行空间
or at least how to make it a bit more flexible because you can create multiple
或者至少如何让它变得更多一点灵活，因为您可以创建多个
lines of code in one line the reason here again
一行代码行的原因又是在这里
is what you see as a line and what python sees as a line are two separate
就是你看到的一条线python将一行视为两条独立的线
things if you want to be a bit more specific
事物如果你想更具体一点
about it what you see is a physical line
关于它你看到的是一条物理线
all that really means is whatever is in a single line of code it's as simple as
真正的意思是里面的任何东西一行代码就这么简单
that but what python sees is a logical line
那但python看到的是一条逻辑线
and this is what gets executed one step at a time let me demonstrate this one as
这就是一步执行的内容一次让我将其演示为
well actually let me clean all of this up actually so
实际上让我把这一切都清理干净吧
things are a bit easier to read we have two physical lines and two
事情更容易阅读我们有两条物理线路和两条
logical lines meaning what we see and what python sees is identical we have
逻辑线意味着我们所看到的和python 看到的和我们看到的是一样的
this line and we have this line however what i can do now is put both of
这条线，我们有这条线但是我现在能做的就是把两者都放在
these print statements on the same line and python isn't going to like this at
这些打印语句在同一行python 不会喜欢这个
all and the reason here is that for us this
全部原因是对我们来说
is one physical line and we can i guess read it
是一条物理线，我猜阅读
but to python this is one logical line now that doesn't make sense python can
但对于 python 来说这是一个逻辑线现在这没有意义 python 可以
only execute one of these functions at a time
只执行这些函数之一时间
it has to execute this line first and then this line second it cannot do them
它必须首先执行这一行并且那么这一行第二行就不能做到
at the same time which is why we are getting an error
同时这就是我们收到错误的原因
here although this logic you can break to
这里虽然这个逻辑你可以打破
some extent and there are two ways of doing that the
在一定程度上有两种方法可以做到这一点
first one is you can use a semicolon and this way you can separate a physical
第一个是你可以使用分号这样你就可以分离物理
line into logical lines all of this here would be a physical
行转换为逻辑行这里的所有这一切都将是物理上的
line but because of the semicolon python is going to break this one out into two
行但是因为分号 python将把这个一分为二
logical lines and is going to keep happy the opposite operation i suppose you
符合逻辑并且会保持快乐相反的操作我想你
could call it would be a forward slash this one is breaking two physical lines
可以称之为正斜杠这个打破了两条物理线
into one logical line this is something you are going to use
进入一个逻辑行这是你要使用的东西
fairly often if you have a really long operation
如果你有很长的一段时间，那么经常手术
the example here is we're just adding some numbers and at some point we ran
这里的例子是我们刚刚添加一些数字，在某个时刻我们跑了
out of monitor space as a consequence we wanted to have all of this on the same
由于监视器空间不足，我们想要将所有这些都放在同一个上
line meaning this is two physical lines but
线这意味着这是两条物理线，但是
because of the forward slash python turn all of this into one logical line and
因为正斜杠 python 转所有这些都集中在一个逻辑行中
keeps being happy so all is good and let's have a look at those two and
保持快乐所以一切都好让我们看看这两个
then we are done with this entire section
然后我们就完成了整个部分
and i guess we can start with the semicolon
我想我们可以从分号
if i put print and print on the same line run this again python is going to
如果我把 print 和 print 放在同一个上再次运行 python 行
be unhappy but if i put a semicolon between the two
不高兴，但如果我加一个分号两者之间
then python is going to remain happy because this semicolon is breaking a
那么 python 就会保持快乐因为这个分号打破了
logical line now that being said this semicolon you are probably never going
逻辑线既然这么说分号你可能永远不会去
to use or at the very least you are very rarely going to use it it really is very
使用或者至少你非常很少会使用它，它真的很
very uncommon what is however much more common is let
非常罕见然而更常见的是让
me create another variable let's call it a
我创建另一个变量我们称之为A
what you do see fairly often is some kind of very long math operation let's
你经常看到的是一些一种很长的数学运算让我们
say one plus two plus three plus four plus five and this could go on forever
说一加二加三加四加五，这可能会永远持续下去
and you want to break this up and for that you would use forward slash and
你想要打破这个局面你会使用正斜杠和
then on the next line you can continue writing the line as you would normally
然后在下一行你可以继续像平常一样写下该行
do meaning i could add a plus 6 plus 7 plus
做这意味着我可以添加 plus 6 plus 7 plus
8 and so on if i now print a
8 等等如果我现在打印一个
and run this we are getting a proper result
运行这个我们得到一个正确的结果
keeping your code readable is a priority that you want to keep in mind and the
保持代码可读是首要任务您要记住的内容以及
forward slash is really useful for that but right with that we have all of the
正斜杠对此非常有用但就这样我们就拥有了所有的
basics covered in this section we are going to cover
涵盖的基础知识在本节中我们将介绍
data types and this is going to be an incredibly important part because
数据类型，这将是非常重要的部分，因为
understanding data types is one of the most fundamental things you have to
理解数据类型是其中之一你必须做的最基本的事情
understand about programming python does have quite a few different data types we
了解 python 编程确实我们有很多不同的数据类型
have actually seen some already the one that we have used the most is words
实际上已经看到了一些我们用得最多的是词语
which is just a string it really is just a fancy word that
这只是一个字符串这确实只是一个花哨的词
programmers use we are just talking about words
程序员使用我们只是在说话关于词语
besides that we have also used different kind of numbers
除此之外我们还使用了不同的数字的种类
we have seen integers and we have seen floating point numbers
我们已经看到了整数并且我们已经看到了浮点数字
the only difference between the two is that floating point numbers has decimal
两者之间唯一的区别是浮点数有小数
points whereas integers are always full numbers
点，而整数总是满的数字
the reason why that is is quite technical and you don't have to worry
这是因为技术性的，您不必担心
about it you can work with them very very easily and they are basically
关于它你可以和他们一起工作很容易，他们基本上是
interchangeable from your point of view there are only very rare exceptions
从你的角度来看可以互换只有极少数例外
where that is not the case and those exceptions you probably are
情况并非如此以及你可能属于的例外情况
not going to come across unless again to some very specific topics
不会遇到除非再次一些非常具体的主题
besides that there's one more data type that we have seen as well and that is a
除此之外还有一种数据类型我们也看到了，那就是
boolean and boolean data types can only ever have two values
boolean 和 boolean 数据类型只能曾经有两个值
they are either true or false and in the context where we have seen
它们要么是真要么是假在我们所看到的背景下
them is some kind of math operation for example 10 is greater than 5
它们是某种数学运算示例 10 大于 5
was true these boolean values you are going to work quite a lot later with to
这些布尔值是真的稍后要工作很多
organize the flow of your code for example you might only want to run some
组织你的代码流程例如你可能只想运行一些
code if a certain condition is true besides those four data types python has
如果某个条件为真，则代码除了这四种数据类型Python还有
quite a few more some are more important some are less important but there are
还有很多一些比较重要有些不太重要，但有
four that you absolutely have to know and let's start with the easiest one a
四个你绝对必须知道的让我们从最简单的开始
list this is basically just a container to
列表这基本上只是一个容器
store other data types for example in this list right now we have three values
存储其他数据类型，例如现在这个列表有三个值
we have one and two and both of those are integers
我们有一个和两个，两个都有是整数
and besides that we have a string which is just a word you could also
除此之外我们还有一个字符串这只是一个词，你也可以
store boolean or floating point numbers and you could even store a list inside
存储布尔值或浮点数你甚至可以在里面存储一个列表
of another list python really is flexible here
另一个列表的python在这里确实很灵活
besides that we have tuples we have sets and we have dictionaries
除此之外我们还有元组我们还有集合我们有字典
and all four of those data types are just there to store other values
所有这四种数据类型都是只是用来存储其他值
the difference between them is that they are storing data slightly differently
他们之间的区别在于他们存储数据略有不同
a list and a tuple differ because a list can be changed
一个列表和一个元组有所不同，因为列表可以更改
whereas a tuple cannot be changed a set would be different because every
而元组不能更改一组会有所不同，因为每个
value inside of it has to be unique and there are a lot of ways to compare
它内部的价值必须是唯一的有很多方法可以比较
different sets to filter out data and finally a dictionary
不同的集合来过滤数据最后是一本字典
is a much more organized way to store your data in here we always have a name
是一种更有组织性的存储方式您在这里的数据我们总是有一个名字
and then a data type i am going to go through all of those in
然后是数据类型我将详细介绍所有这些内容
detail throughout this section and then we are going to go in quite some detail
本节的详细信息，然后我们将详细介绍
into all of them besides those
进入他们所有人除了那些
there are also some data types that are much less common i will cover those at
还有一些数据类型不太常见，我将在以下位置介绍这些内容
the end of this section they really aren't that important but you do want to
本节结束时他们真的没那么重要，但你确实想要
be aware of where they appear and why they matter
了解它们出现的位置和原因他们很重要
but generally python is incredibly relaxed about
但一般来说python 非常轻松
different data types most of the time you are actually not even going to
大多数时候不同的数据类型实际上你根本不打算
notice for example if you have an integer and a floating
例如通知如果你有一个整数和一个浮点数
point number for example this could be 1 plus 1.2
点数例如这可能是 1 加 1.2
and python here would automatically convert these two numbers into a
这里的 python 会自动将这两个数字转换成
floating point number with 2.2 you have essentially combined different
浮点数与2.2你本质上结合了不同的
data types but because python is so flexible about it you didn't even notice
数据类型但是因为python是如此你甚至没有注意到它的灵活性
which is one of the main reasons why integers and floating point numbers
这是主要原因之一整数和浮点数
especially for beginners are basically identical and you never have to worry
特别是对于初学者来说基本上完全相同，您无需担心
about them on top of that python also has a ton of
关于他们除此之外，Python 还有大量
functionality to change different data types i'm going to cover that very soon
更改不同数据的功能我很快就会介绍这些类型
as well let's get started by talking about
还有让我们开始讨论
integers and floats or well just numbers and i just covered them but just as a
整数和浮点数或者只是数字我刚刚涵盖了它们，但只是作为
recap we are creating numbers either with
回顾我们正在创建数字
integers or with floating point numbers and again the only difference between
整数或浮点数再次，两者之间唯一的区别
the two is decimal points for floating point numbers and integers are always
两位是浮动小数点点数和整数总是
full numbers again
完整数字再次
the difference is because of how computers work but you really don't have
区别在于如何电脑可以工作，但你确实没有
to worry about it the most important thing for you is that all math operators
担心它最重要对你来说，所有数学运算符
work just as normal meaning if you add an integer and a floating point number
如果添加的话，就像正常的意思一样工作一个整数和一个浮点数
you are getting a floating point number let's have a look at some examples
你得到一个浮点数让我们看一些例子
and a really useful function to understand what data type you're working
和一个非常有用的功能了解您正在使用的数据类型
with is called type if i write type and then add an integer so a one in here
如果我写 type and 则 with 称为 type然后在此处添加一个整数，即 1
python is going to tell me what data type i am working with
python 会告诉我什么数据我正在使用的类型
and again we have to print the result so we can
然后再次我们必须打印结果以便我们可以
see something if i run the code now we're getting class and integer what a
如果我现在运行代码，会看到一些东西我们得到了类和整数
class is you're going to learn much later in this series
课堂上你会学到很多东西在本系列的后面部分
but the important thing for now is the integer this is the kind of data type we
但现在最重要的是整数，这是我们的数据类型
are working with if i change this 1 to a 1.1
正在与如果我把这个 1 改成 1.1
then we are getting a float or a floating point value
然后我们得到一个浮点数或一个浮点值
which means you are working with different data types
这意味着您正在与不同的数据类型
you could also add a string in here so a word let's say a
您还可以在此处添加一个字符串，以便让我们说一个
word that is horrible spelling but you get the idea and we have sdr for string
这个词的拼写很糟糕，但是你明白了，我们有字符串的 sdr
let's stick to a1 actually we don't need to type at all anymore instead what we
让我们坚持 a1 实际上我们不需要不再输入我们所输入的内容
can look at is
可以看看是
the conversion between different data types and for numbers this is all
不同数据之间的转换类型和数字这就是全部
automatic and here
自动的和这里
i could just type 1 plus 1 plus 1 and we get 2.1
我可以只输入 1 加 1 加 1，我们得到2.1
since this does have a decimal point we have a floating point value
因为这确实有小数点，我们有浮点值
although if you didn't know this specifically you would never notice
虽然如果你不知道这一点特别是你永远不会注意到
although i guess sometimes this can be slightly weird we have actually seen
虽然我想有时这可能是我们实际看到的有点奇怪
this very early on in this entire series if you divide any number by another
这是整个系列的早期部分如果你将任何数字除以另一个数字
number let's say 10 divided by 5 i am going to get a floating point
数字比方说 10 除以 5我要得到一个浮点数
number even though i wouldn't necessarily need it
即使我不会的数字必然需要它
and this always happens in python you can't really get around it
这在Python中总是发生无法真正绕过它
but that is basically all you have to know about numbers in python in terms of
但这基本上就是你所要做的了解 python 中的数字
data types python here is really flexible and makes all of this very easy
python 这里的数据类型确实是灵活，让这一切变得非常简单
which does make it much easier than most other programming languages
这确实比大多数人容易得多其他编程语言
i guess one thing we can cover as well is let me add this on the next line
我想我们也可以讨论一件事让我在下一行添加这个
you can use functions to convert different data types for example
你可以使用函数来转换例如不同的数据类型
let me print something again and i have a integer
让我再打印一些东西，我已经一个整数
let's say 2 and i really want to convert this integer into a floating point
假设 2 我真的很想转换将此整数转换为浮点数
number one way of doing this is to add 0.0 to
数字一种方法是将 0.0 添加到
it if i run this now we get 2.0 although this isn't exactly elegant so we're not
如果我现在运行这个，我们会得到 2.0这不太优雅，所以我们不
going to use it a better way would be to use a function
将要使用它更好的方法是使用函数
that is called float and float converts any kind of integer into a floating
这就是所谓的浮点和浮点转换任何类型的整数转换为浮点数
point value if i run this now we're getting the same result
点值如果我现在运行这个我们是得到相同的结果
you can see it's a float because we have a decimal
你可以看到它是一个浮点数，因为我们有一个小数
this would also work the other way around let me put this on the next line
这也可以以另一种方式工作让我把它放在下一行
if i print a number like let's use something else 5.1
如果我打印一个数字，比如让我们使用其他5.1
if i want to convert this 5.1 into an integer
如果我想把这个 5.1 转换成整数
i could use the
我可以用这
int function or int for integer if i run this i am only getting 5
int 函数或 int 表示整数如果我运行这个我只会得到 5
because remember integers are always 4 numbers we do not have values after
因为记住整数总是 4后面没有值的数字
decimal so we are losing some data also keep in mind when you are using int
小数所以我们丢失了一些数据当你使用 int 时还要记住
you are not rounding the operation you are doing is truncating
你没有四舍五入你的操作正在做的是截断
and truncating means we are getting rid of anything
截断意味着我们正在摆脱任何东西
after the decimal point which means if i had 5.9
小数点后这意味着如果我有 5.9
and run all of this again we are still getting 5. if you wanted to round you
再次运行所有这些我们仍然得到5.如果你想圆你
would use round and then you were getting 6.
会用圆形然后你就得到了 6。
it would also return an integer because again we don't have any decimal point
它还会返回一个整数，因为再说一遍，我们没有小数点
now there's one thing that you do want to be really careful about and that is
现在你确实想要一件事要非常小心，那就是
that floating point numbers sometimes can get really weird especially if you
有时浮点数可能会变得很奇怪，尤其是如果你
combine integers and floating point numbers for example if i print
结合整数和浮点数例如，如果我打印数字
1.1 times 3 what we would be expecting here is 3.3
1.1倍3我们期望的是 3.3
however if i run the code we are getting something really weird three point three
但是如果我运行我们得到的代码一些非常奇怪的三点三
and then zero a lot and then a three at the end
然后归零很多，最后是三
technically this result is wrong it resulted because floating point numbers
从技术上讲这个结果是错误的结果是因为浮点数
are kind of weird in computers now that being said in most cases
在计算机中有点奇怪现在大多数情况下都这么说
this error here makes absolutely no difference because it's such a small
这里的这个错误绝对不会差异因为它是如此之小
deviation you are never going to notice it but do keep it in mind you generally
你永远不会注意到的偏差但一般情况下请记住这一点
want to avoid floating point numbers because they can add some arithmetic
想要避免浮点数因为他们可以添加一些算术
errors once in a while generally integers are much easier and
偶尔会出现错误一般来说整数更容易并且
much cleaner to work with but obviously sometimes you just have to
工作起来更干净但显然有时你只需要
use floating point numbers and then you can just use them they work just fine in
使用浮点数然后你可以使用它们，它们工作得很好
basically all circumstances the next data type i want to talk about
基本上所有情况我想谈的下一个数据类型
are strings and this is the one we have seen a lot by now all we're talking here
是字符串，这就是我们拥有的字符串到目前为止我们已经看到了很多我们在这里谈论的内容
are words and this is something we do have to talk
是词这是我们必须要谈的事情
quite a lot about because we are going to use them extensively
很多关于因为我们要去广泛使用它们
strings are created either with single or with double quotation marks you could
字符串可以用 single 创建或者用双引号你可以
either write word with single quotation marks this one and this one
要么用单引号写单词标记这个和这个
or you could use double quotation marks this one and this one python really
或者你可以使用双引号这个和这个蟒蛇真的
doesn't care the only limitation is that you have to stick to the same kind of
不在乎唯一的限制是你必须坚持同一种
quotation mark you couldn't add a single quotation mark
引号你不能添加单引号
and then end with a double quotation mark
然后以双引号结束标记
and strings have a ton of methods to manipulate them i guess some examples we
字符串有很多方法可以操纵它们我想我们举一些例子
have seen are upper is numeric and strip what we haven't seen yet is you can also
见过的是上面是数字和条带我们还没有看到的是你也可以
use strings with math operations for example if you add hello plus world you
使用带有数学运算的字符串例如，如果你添加 hello plus world 你
are combining these two strings we are going to explore that functionality a
将这两个字符串组合在一起将探索该功能
bit more in this section besides that you can also add values
本节内容更多除此之外你还可以添加值
into strings in quite a few different ways the most important concept here
分成多种不同的字符串这里最重要的概念
that you have to understand are f strings
你必须明白的是f字符串
you will see in a second what that means it's basically another kind of method
你很快就会明白这意味着什么这基本上是另一种方法
and finally we can also cover how to write over
最后我们还可以介绍如何重写
multiple lines and how to add quotation marks inside of a string
多行以及如何添加报价字符串内部的标记
and that's a ton of stuff to cover so let's have a look at all of this
有很多东西需要涵盖让我们看看这一切
let's start by creating some test variable
让我们首先创建一些测试多变的
and in here to create a string we can either use single quotation marks or
在这里创建一个字符串我们可以使用单引号或
double quotation marks i guess let's start with single
双引号我想我们先从单身开始吧
quotation marks let's call it test 1 and then for test variable 2
引号让我们称之为测试 1然后对于测试变量 2
we can have double quotation marks with test 2.
我们可以用双引号测试2.
if i run the code now all of this is going to work just fine
如果我现在运行代码，所有这些都是会正常工作
as a matter of fact if i print testvar1 and testvar2
事实上，如果我打印 testvar1和测试变量2
both of them are going to give the same result python does not care if we use
他们都会给予相同的结果 python 不关心我们是否使用
double or single quotation marks the one thing python does care about is that we
双引号或单引号标记一个python 真正关心的是我们
do not mix quotation marks meaning something like this wouldn't work if i
不要混淆引号的含义如果我这样的话就行不通
run it we are getting a syntax error
运行我们收到语法错误
undetermined string literal i think the reason here should be quite obvious it
未确定的字符串文字我认为这里的原因应该很明显吧
would be very strange what i also want to do starting from
会很奇怪我也想做从
well now is to comment my code so it's going to be a bit easier to read when
现在是评论我的代码所以它是会更容易阅读
you read through it and this section here is about quotes
你读完它这一部分是关于报价的
for strings along with that there's one important
对于字符串除此之外还有一个重要的
thing that we do have to cover and that is quotes inside of strings
我们必须涵盖的事情是字符串内的引号
what that means let me create another test variable let's call it testvar3
这意味着什么让我创建另一个测试变量我们称之为 testvar3
and let's do an example let's say i have the case
让我们举个例子，假设我有案子
that he said and then i want other quotation marks
他说的然后我想要其他引号
this was great
这是伟大的
and let me add a bit of white space here so this is easier to understand
让我在这里添加一些空白所以这更容易理解
we are using quotation marks here and here and that way we are creating a
我们在这里使用引号在这里和那样我们正在创建一个
string inside of this string though we have
细绳尽管我们有这个字符串的内部
another quote and you can already see by the colors
另一个报价你已经可以从颜色看出
here python is not exactly happy about it
python对此不太满意它
if i run out of this we are getting an error invalid syntax
如果我用完了这个我们收到错误语法无效
python just doesn't know what to make of it
python 只是不知道该怎么做它
as far as python is concerned we are starting a string here and we are
就Python而言我们在这里开始一个字符串，我们是
ending the string here then we are adding some random words and
在此结束字符串然后我们添加一些随机单词
then we are creating another string the reason now where python is confused
然后我们创建另一个字符串现在 python 感到困惑的原因
is because these three words are neither variables nor inbuilt functions so
是因为这三个词都不是变量或内置函数所以
python just doesn't know what to do with them and it gives us an error so how can
python 只是不知道该怎么办他们，这给了我们一个错误，那么如何才能
we get around it and there are two ways of doing this
我们可以解决这个问题，有两种方法这样做的
the first one that you are probably going to use the most is to mix the
你可能是第一个最常用的是混合
quotation marks now we have
引号现在我们有
single quotation marks to create a string and inside of the string we have
单引号来创建字符串和字符串的内部
double quotation marks to explain that we have a quote this
双引号解释一下我们有一个报价
python is completely fine with let me print it actually testvar free
python 完全没问题让我免费打印它
if i run this now we are getting he said this was great python has no problem
如果我现在运行这个，我们就会听到他说这太棒了 python 没有问题
with that and let me remove the white space that
接着就，随即让我删除空白
should make all of this a bit easier to read
应该让这一切变得更容易读
while we add it i also want to comment out
在我们添加它的同时我也想发表评论出去
this stuff here at the top so things are a bit easier to see now if i run this we
这个东西在顶部所以事情是如果我运行这个，现在更容易看到
can see we have quotes inside of a string
可以看到 a 里面有引号细绳
this would also work the other way around
这也可以以另一种方式工作大约
if i start with double quotation marks and end with double quotation marks
如果我以双引号开头并以双引号结尾
then inside of here
然后这里的里面
i can add single quotation marks like this run it again and we would also see
我可以添加单引号，例如再次运行它，我们也会看到
the result now we have single quotation marks
结果现在我们有单引号分数
this would be one way to approach this although this system has its limitation
这将是解决这个问题的一种方法虽然这个系统有其局限性
for example if i add a test var4 and in here
例如，如果我添加一个测试 var4在这里
we want to have for whatever reason a single quotation mark a double quotation
无论出于何种原因，我们都希望有一个单引号 双引号
mark and then a single quotation mark as well
标记，然后用单引号标记为出色地
and this would just not work python would just get very confused
这是行不通的python 会变得非常困惑
not exactly something you would do all the time but it might come up once every
不完全是你会做的事情时间，但可能会出现一次
year and then you have a problem to overcome this you need what is called an
年，然后你有一个问题克服这个你需要所谓的
escape character let me add a comment and escape
转义字符让我添加评论并逃脱
character an escape character is again a forward slash and this you need in front
字符转义字符又是a正斜杠，你需要在前面
of every character you want python to just interpret as a string
你想要 python 处理的每个字符只是解释为一个字符串
and this you need in front of every character you want python to interpret
这是你在每个人面前都需要的你想要 python 解释的字符
as a normal character so in my case i want this escape
作为一个正常角色所以就我而言，我想要这种逃避
character in front of my double quotation mark and my single quotation
在我的替身面前的角色引号和我的单引号
mark and now you can see the comment appears as a proper comment
标记一下，现在就可以看到评论了显示为正确的评论
if i print it i can see the two quotation marks this
如果我打印它我可以看到这两个引号
way you can literally add any kind of character without disturbing your code
你可以从字面上添加任何类型的方式字符而不干扰您的代码
as a matter of fact let me rename this to simple escape character because
事实上让我重命名它简单的转义字符，因为
escaped characters can do quite a bit which means i want to add another
转义字符可以做很多事情这意味着我想添加另一个
comment for escape characters what we can do in here let me comment
转义字符的注释我们可以在这里做什么让我发表评论
out the earlier part and now i want to have a test var
出前面的部分现在我想要一个测试变量
five and for this one i want to print some
五对于这个我想打印一些
text over multiple lines let's say i want to have line 1
多行文本假设我想要 1 号线
[Music] some text
[音乐]一些文字
and then i want to have line 2 some more text
然后我想要2号线更多文字
and i want to tell python that this should be over multiple lines of code
我想告诉 python 这应该是多行代码
for example if you want to build some kind of text editor you want to store
例如，如果你想构建一些您要存储的文本编辑器类型
all of the text inside of one string but when you present a string you want to
一个字符串内的所有文本，但是当你呈现一个你想要的字符串时
have line breaks between them how could you do that
它们之间有换行符怎么可能你做吧
i guess let me print the test bar first if i run this
我想让我先打印测试条如果我运行这个
we get all of this on one line and to create a line break in here we
我们将所有这些都集中在一条线上并在这里创建一个换行符
need once again the forward slash and then the letter n
再次需要正斜杠和然后是字母n
if i run this now we are getting those two lines on well different lines
如果我现在运行这个我们会得到那些两条线在不同的线上
forward slash n tells python that we want to add a line break between these
正斜杠 n 告诉 python 我们想要在这些之间添加换行符
two different parts of the string there are actually quite a few more for
字符串的两个不同部分实际上还有很多
example forward slash t is adding a tab inside of your string
示例正斜杠 t在字符串中添加一个制表符
there's also forward slash r this one adds another kind of line break you
还有正斜杠 r 这个添加另一种换行符
don't really have to know the difference here for your purposes work essentially
真的不必知道其中的区别这里基本上是为了你的目的而工作
the same forward slash n though is the most
相同正斜杠 n 虽然是最多的
common one so that way you can write text over
常见的一个这样你就可以写文字了
multiple lines besides that
多行除此之外
let me add multiple lines as a comment here
让我添加多行作为评论这里
there's another way to write multiple lines and this is one way we have
还有另一种方法可以写多个线，这是我们的一种方式
actually already seen what you need here are triple quotation
其实已经看过了你需要的是三重引号
marks something that python by default
分数默认情况下 python 的东西
considers a comment
认为评论
however if you assign this comment here to a variable let's
但是如果你分配这个注释在这里是一个变量让我们
call this one test var six
将此称为测试变量六
all of a sudden it changes the color and it becomes a
突然间它改变了颜色，变成了
string and this string is kind of special
细绳这个字符串有点特殊
because for this one python does respect the white space
因为对于这个Python确实尊重空白区域
which means now i can press space end up on another physical line
这意味着现在我可以按空格键最终到达另一条物理线路
write some more text do the same thing again and then write on another line if
再写一些文字做同样的事情再次然后在另一行写如果
i print this test var 6 python is going to preserve all of the
我打印这个测试 var 6python 将保留所有
line breaks for example what we could be doing in
换行符例如我们可以做什么
here let me actually copy it that should save some time i could copy
这里让我实际复制它应该节省一些时间我可以复制
something like this in here if i run this now we have the tree we created in
如果我跑的话这里会有类似的东西现在我们有了我们创建的树
one of the very first section of this entire series
本节的第一部分之一整个系列
and this is a much easier way to see what's going on
这是一种更容易查看的方法这是怎么回事
although granted because of the first line here this is a bit difficult to
虽然因为第一个而被授予在这里线这有点困难
understand but with all of this covered we have
理解但有了所有这些，我们就有了
quite a bit more understanding about strings
有了更多的了解字符串
now there are two more things that i do want to cover the first one is math and
现在我还有两件事要做想要涵盖第一个是数学
strings and before we start that let me comment
字符串在我们开始之前让我评论一下
out the earlier stuff so it doesn't get confusing
拿出早期的东西，这样它就不会得到令人困惑的
what you can do let's call this testvar7
你可以做什么我们称之为 testvar7
you can add something like one string hello
你可以添加一个字符串之类的东西你好
and then plus a
然后加上A
world and python when it sees this plus it is
世界当 python 看到这个加上它时
just going to combine these two strings if i print test bar 7 now we are getting
只是将这两个字符串组合起来如果我现在打印测试栏 7 我们得到
hello world keep in mind here
你好世界请记住这里
there's no space between the two because neither hello nor world have any
两者之间没有空间因为 hello 和 world 都没有
white space one way to add them would be to just add
空白添加它们的一种方法是添加
them here and then
他们在这里进而
combine all of these with another plus you can add as many pluses here as you
将所有这些与另一个优点结合起来您可以在这里添加任意数量的优点
want there's no limit on it this would also work with different
希望没有限制这也适用于不同的
types of quotation marks python literally does not care
引号的类型python实际上并不关心
another math operation that we can use let me create a test var eight
我们可以使用的另一个数学运算让我创建一个测试变量 8
i can let me write a word like copy i can multiply it for example times ten
我可以让我写一个词，比如copy i例如可以乘以十
if i now print the result i get the word copy copied ten times
如果我现在打印结果我把这个词复制了十次
but again i think this concept here should be fairly straightforward
但我再次认为这个概念在这里应该相当简单
let me comment it out and now we come to the most important section of this
让我把它评论出来，现在我们来了本节最重要的部分
entire video and that is how to get values into strings and let's do this by
整个视频，这就是如何获得将值转换为字符串，让我们这样做
example i have a name and in here i have bob
例如我有一个名字，在这里我有鲍勃
and i have an h and let's go i don't know 40.
我有一个 h，我们走吧，我没有知道 40.
now i want to create another let's call it a greeting
现在我想创建另一个让我们打电话这是一个问候
string and this greeting string i want to say
细绳我想说的这句问候语
hello bob
你好鲍勃
you are 40 years old
你是40岁
let me add the print statement as well so we can see what's going on
让我也添加打印语句这样我们就可以看到发生了什么
i want to have the greeting string and let's run this
我想要问候语字符串让我们运行这个
i can see hello bob you are 40 years old right now the two values are matching
我可以看到你好鲍勃你40岁了现在两个值匹配
we have bob here and bob here and we have 40
我们有鲍勃在这里，鲍勃在这里，我们有 40 个
here and 40 here but this is only the case because i have
这里和这里 40但这只是情况，因为我有
written bob if i change this bob to tom
书面鲍勃如果我把这个鲍勃换成汤姆
and run all of this again we wouldn't see a difference
再次运行所有这些我们不会看到差异
so what i want to do is to somehow get this name variable into here
所以我想做的是以某种方式得到这个名字变量放到这里
and this h variable into here and python has quite a few ways of
并将这个 h 变量放到这里python 有很多方法
achieving that the one people tend to learn first is
实现这一点人们往往首先学习的是
called format this is just another method
称为格式，这只是另一种方法
this one works by adding curly brackets inside of your string where you want to
这个通过添加大括号来工作在你想要的字符串内部
add a variable in my case i want to replace the name with a curly bracket
在我的例子中添加一个变量我想要用大括号替换名称
and the age with another curly bracket and now i can add values into this
和另一个大括号的年龄现在我可以向其中添加值
format this could for example be a one and a two
格式例如可以是一个和一个二
if i run all of this now i can see hello one you are two years old
如果我现在运行所有这些我可以看到你好一你两岁
what python has done here is it looked at the first curly brackets
python在这里所做的是它看起来在第一个大括号处
and then it looked inside of format and found the first value after that it saw
然后它查看格式内部并且找到它看到的第一个值
another curly bracket and looked for the second value inside of format and then
另一个大括号并寻找格式内的第二个值，然后
inserted it into the string granted just adding one and two in this example isn't
将其插入刚刚授予的字符串中在这个例子中添加一和二不是
particularly helpful but what we can do is add variables in
特别有帮助但我们可以做的是添加变量
here as well like name and age if i run this now we get hello tom you
这里还有姓名和年龄如果我现在运行这个，我们会向你问好，汤姆
are 40 years old and this now means we can change these
40岁了现在这意味着我们可以改变这些
variables let's say a hundred and something it really doesn't matter what
变量比方说一百和某事，这并不重要
it is although you do have to be careful about
这是虽然你必须小心
the order if i switch them around with h coming first and then name
如果我用 h 交换它们的顺序先来，然后名字
now we have hello100 you are something years old
现在我们有 hello100 你很了不起岁
the order here being wrong messed all of this up which can be kind of annoying
这里的顺序错误搞乱了所有的这可能有点烦人
especially if you have longer strings where you want to add more variables
特别是如果你有更长的琴弦您想要添加更多变量的地方
this can become very confusing and as a consequence python has a way to
这可能会变得非常混乱因此 python 有办法
make all of this more organized you can inside of the curly brackets add
让这一切更有条理你可以在大括号内添加
something like variable names let me call them one and two and now you
像变量名之类的东西让我称它们为一和二，现在你
can assign one to name and two to the age
可以将 1 分配给名称，将 2 分配给年龄
if i run this now we are getting the same outcome
如果我现在运行这个我们会得到同样的结果
although now we know very specifically which value is being assigned to which
虽然现在我们非常具体地知道哪个值被分配给哪个
curly bracket one gets this one here
大括号有人在这里得到这个
and two is getting this value here
和两个在这里得到这个值
meaning now we're going to sign h to 1 and
意思是现在我们要将 h 签名为 1和
i guess we could keep h for 2 as well if i run this now we get hello 100 you are
我想我们也可以将 h 保留为 2 如果我现在运行这个我们得到你好 100 你是
100 years old the reason is we are assigning h to both
100岁原因是我们将 h 分配给两者
1 and 2 which is putting this age into here and
1 和 2这就是把这个年龄放到这里
into here and that way you can be much more
进入这里这样你就可以做得更多
deliberate about where you put the variables
仔细考虑你把它放在哪里变量
that being said very few people
话虽如此极少数人
use this kind of method because when you look at it it's kind of inefficient
使用这种方法是因为当你看看它，效率有点低
why do we have to add a whole method with arguments why couldn't we just add
为什么我们必须添加一个完整的方法有参数为什么我们不能添加
variables straight inside of these curly brackets that would be much better and
变量直接在这些卷曲内部括号会好得多
python developers agree and to achieve that
python 开发者同意并实现这一目标
they have created what is called an f string
他们创造了所谓的 f细绳
let me create another variable let's call it greeting string
让我创建另一个变量吧称之为问候字符串
better for this one i want to copy this entire
更好的对于这个我想复制整个
string and paste it in here and now i'm going to add the variables i
字符串并将其粘贴到此处现在我要添加变量 i
want straight into the curly brackets we have name for hello and h4 years old
想要直接进入大括号我们有 hello 和 h4 岁的名字
although now if i print greeting strings better
虽然现在如果我打印问候字符串更好的
i am getting hello name you are 8 years old python interprets this and this
我收到你好名字，你今年 8 岁老Python解释这个和这个
as a simple part of the string which isn't ideal
作为字符串的简单部分并不理想
to tell python that these are supposed to be variables we have to add an f at
告诉 python 这些是应该的要成为变量，我们必须添加一个 f at
the beginning of the string and that is all we need if i run this now we're
字符串的开头，即如果我现在运行这个，我们需要的就是
getting hello something you are 100 years old
打个招呼，你已经100岁了岁
and you can see it by the colors the name
你可以通过颜色看到它名字
and the age are not green anymore which in our case means they are not a
年纪已不再青涩在我们的例子中这意味着它们不是
string anymore although your colors may vary depending on what color scheme you
尽管你的颜色可能会不再串起来取决于您的配色方案
have we can let me return to bob who is 40
有我们可以让我回到 40 岁的鲍勃身边
years old this is still going to work and this version here is much more
好几年了，这仍然有效这个版本有更多内容
readable than this one up here i guess let me fix it this is better
我想比这里的这个更可读让我修复它，这样更好
but still this one here is very annoying to read whereas this one is really clear
但这里的这个还是很烦人阅读一下，而这个确实很清楚
and f strings can actually do quite a bit more inside of these curly brackets
f 字符串实际上可以做很多这些大括号内还有更多内容
you could even do basic math operations for example we could add h plus 10
你甚至可以进行基本的数学运算例如我们可以添加 h 加 10
all of this would also still work with that we have covered a lot of stuff for
所有这一切仍然适用于我们已经介绍了很多内容
strings and i think this part is getting quite long so let's do an exercise and
字符串，我认为这部分正在变得很长，所以让我们做一个练习
then finish it off and what i want you guys to do is this
然后完成它我希望你们做的是这个
one here i want you guys to create an f string that says hello my name is x and
我希望你们创建一个 f字符串表示你好，我的名字是 x 和
my hobby is y x and y should both be separate
我的爱好是yx 和 y 应该是分开的
variables and the second half of the sentence
变量和句子的后半部分
should be on a separate line and by second half i mean and my hobby is y
应该在单独的一行上并且由后半部分我的意思是我的爱好是你
this should be on a separate line when it is being printed pause the video now
这应该在一个单独的行上，当正在打印，现在暂停视频
and try this one yourself
并亲自尝试一下这个
let me comment out all of this here so we're not getting confused
让我在这里注释掉所有这些我们并没有感到困惑
and now let's go for this step by step first of all i want to start by creating
现在让我们一步一步进行首先我想从创建开始
an f string here let me copy it
这里有一个 f 字符串让我复制一下
and let's call this the exercise string
我们称之为练习细绳
in here i want hello my name is x my hobby is y
在这里我想问你好，我的名字是 x 我的爱好是y
since we want x and y to be in separate variables
因为我们希望 x 和 y 分开变量
x should be in curly brackets and y should also be in curly brackets
x 应该在大括号中，y 应该在大括号中也应该在大括号中
and since we want python to interpret these as variables we need an f at the
因为我们想要 python 来解释这些作为变量，我们需要一个 f
beginning of the string so now we have to tell python the values
字符串的开头所以现在我们必须告诉 python 这些值
for x and y let me put x here
对于 x 和 y让我把 x 放在这里
and y here let's say for x a value we haven't used
你在这里假设 x 是一个我们没有使用过的值
yet is lisa and i like i don't know
但丽莎还是我喜欢我不知道
programming with that i can print the exercise
编程这样我就可以打印练习了
string and we have hello my name is lisa my hobby is programming
字符串，我们有你好，我的名字是丽莎我的爱好是编程
this is already covering the first two parts of the exercise
这已经涵盖了前两个练习的一部分
next up is the second half of the sentence should be on a separate line
接下来是下半场句子应该单独一行
and this we could approach in two different ways
我们可以分两步来解决这个问题不同的方式
the first one is we could use an escape character
第一个是我们可以使用逃逸特点
meaning forward slash n
意义正斜杠 n
and now if i run this we get hello my name is lisa and my hobby is programming
现在如果我运行这个我们会得到你好我的我的名字是丽莎，我的爱好是编程
on two different lines another way of approaching this let me
在两条不同的线上解决这个问题的另一种方式让我
copy it you could use triple quotation marks
复制它你可以使用三引号
so i add two at the beginning and two more at the end now i get rid of the
所以我在开头添加两个，然后添加两个更多在最后，现在我摆脱了
line break and put all of this on separate lines
换行并将所有这些放在单独的线
i guess let me call this exercise string two
我想让我把这个练习字符串称为二
and now print two and we're getting the same result
现在打印两个，我们得到相同的结果
these two lines here and this line here both do practically the same thing
这两行在这里，这一行在这里两者实际上做同样的事情
although i guess this one is a bit more readable well i guess it's debatable
虽然我猜这个有点多可读性很好，我想这是有争议的
you could choose here whichever you like although be aware the first one is much
你可以在这里选择你喜欢的虽然要知道第一个是很多
more common also keep in mind here the variable naming i used capital x and
更常见的还要记住这里变量命名我使用大写 x 和
capital y is quite bad this should rather be called name and
大写 y 很糟糕这应该被称为名称和
hobby in this part we are going to learn two more data types lists and tuples
这部分我们要学习的爱好另外两种数据类型列表和元组
both are very similar and both are simply data containers for other data
两者非常相似并且都是只是其他数据的数据容器
types which means they are storing other kinds
类型这意味着他们正在存储其他类型
of data that's what a container does and they can contain any kind of data
数据的存储就是容器的作用它们可以包含任何类型的数据
this could be a string a number it could also be a boolean other lists and tuple
这可以是一个字符串也可以是一个数字也可以是布尔值的其他列表和元组
and a lot more there's no limitation on what they can store a tuple would look
还有更多没有限制他们可以存储什么元组看起来
something like this we are starting with normal brackets
像这样的东西我们从普通括号开始
and we're also ending with normal brackets and inside of that we have
我们也以正常结束括号和里面我们有
values that are being separated by a comma
由 a 分隔的值逗号
for example in this case we are starting with an integer and then we're adding a
例如在这种情况下我们开始用一个整数然后我们添加一个
comma then we have a string
逗号然后我们有一个字符串
another comma then we have a boolean value another
另一个逗号然后我们有另一个布尔值
comma and then we have a tuple inside of this original tuple which python is
逗号，然后我们里面有一个元组这个原始元组是 python 的
totally fine with and inside of this tuple we have another string and that is
完全没问题元组我们还有另一个字符串，那就是
the only value for this tuple so it really doesn't make too much sense i
这个元组的唯一值，所以它真的没有太大意义我
just wanted to illustrate that you can do it
只是想说明你可以做吧
besides a tuple we have a list and a list is looking very similar the
除了元组之外我们还有一个列表和一个列表看起来非常相似
only difference now is that to create a list we need square
现在唯一的区别要创建一个列表，我们需要 square
brackets but other than that we are still adding
括号但除此之外我们还在添加
values inside like integers strings booleans and other lists and we are
里面的值就像整数字符串布尔值和其他列表，我们是
separating each value with a comma like here here and here
用逗号分隔每个值，例如这里这里和这里
on the surface those two would look identical and you would be kind of
从表面上看，这两个人看起来相同，你会有点
correct the two are very similar but there's one incredibly important
纠正一下，两者非常相似，但是有一个非常重要的
difference tuples are what is called immutable
不同之处元组就是所谓的不可变
which just means that they cannot be changed
这只是意味着他们不能改变了
for example you could use something like list append
例如你可以使用类似列表附加的东西
and this would work because list can be changed
这会起作用，因为列表可以是改变了
but a tuple and depending a value would not work because we cannot change a
但一个元组和取决于一个值会不起作用，因为我们无法改变
tuple under any circumstance if you really wanted to add a new value
任何情况下的元组如果你真的想添加新的价值
to a tuple you would have to create a whole new tuple and combine the old
对于一个元组，你必须创建一个全新的元组并结合旧的
values with a new value which you can do fairly easily but if
具有新价值的价值观你可以很容易地做到这一点，但是如果
you are going to do that you could just use a list it would be much easier
你要做的就是你可以使用列表会容易得多
that being said because of this immutability
之所以这么说是因为这个不变性
tuples process a tiny bit faster in python
元组的处理速度稍微快一点Python
although the difference is so small you are hardly ever going to notice
虽然差别这么小你几乎不会注意到
i guess let's have a look at all of this and see how far we get let's get started
我想让我们看看这一切看看我们能走多远让我们开始吧
by creating some lists and a list let me store it in the
通过创建一些列表和一个列表让我将其存储在
variable again you are always creating with square
又变了你总是用方块来创作
brackets and in here you're adding values that are separated by a comma for
括号并在这里添加用逗号分隔的值
example you could be adding numbers like 1 2 and 3
例如，您可以添加数字，例如1 2 和 3
you could add floating point values like 4.5
您可以添加浮点值，例如4.5
and you could be adding words like let's say word
你可以添加像让我们这样的词说一句话
those are the data types we have already seen but any data type would be valid in
这些是我们已经拥有的数据类型可见，但任何数据类型都有效
here now if i print
这里现在如果我打印
my list we can see
我的列表我们可以看到
the output we have entered into this list it does work pretty seamlessly
我们输入的输出列出它确实工作得非常无缝
what you can also do is to use the functions we have already seen for
你还可以做的是使用我们已经见过的函数
example len is now going to give us the amount of
示例长度现在要给我们的金额
items we have inside of this list which right now is 5.
我们在此列表中包含的项目现在是5。
finally you could also use the list with methods and lists do have quite a lot of
最后你也可以使用该列表方法和列表确实有很多
methods i suppose a simple one would be clear
方法我想一个简单的就很清楚了
this one removes every value from the list
这个删除了所有值列表
meaning if i print my list after running this method
意思是如果我在运行后打印我的列表这个方法
i am getting 5 items from this line here and this line now is going to print an
我从这行得到 5 件商品现在这一行将打印一个
empty list i suppose if you want to look this up
我想如果你想看的话，列表是空的这个
in google all you would have to do is look for something like python list
在谷歌你所要做的就是寻找类似 python list 的东西
methods once again you are going to find a lot of different websites that talk
你会再次发现方法很多不同的网站都在谈论
about it the official python documentation this
关于它官方的Python文档是这样的
one here is probably the one you want to use
这里的一个可能就是您想要的使用
and in here let me hide this one we have append
在这里让我隐藏这个我们有附加的
extend insert remove and a lot more the one we have just seen was called clear
扩展插入删除等等我们刚刚看到的一个叫做clear
this one is removing all items from a list and it is equivalent to something
这个正在删除 a 中的所有项目列表，它相当于某物
else what this part here means we are
别的这部分在这里意味着我们是什么
actually going to learn in a couple of minutes it's super useful for now just
实际上要学习几个分钟，现在非常有用
keep in mind there are a lot of different methods in here that you could
请记住有很多这里有不同的方法，你可以
be using another easy one would be reverse this one reverses the list let's
使用另一个简单的会是反转这个 反转列表 让我们
have a look at this one i suppose we could change clear to
看看这个我想我们可以明确地改为
reverse and now if i run the code we are getting the entire list in the
相反，现在如果我运行代码我们正在获取整个列表
reverse order compared to this list here just like with words or well with
与此处的列表相比，顺序相反就像言语一样或很好
strings the main way you are going to learn the
字符串你学习的主要方式
different methods is by just using python and encountering different
不同的方法只是使用python 并遇到不同的
problems and finding the solutions to them and most of the time the solution
问题并寻找解决方案他们以及大多数时候的解决方案
is going to involve some kind of method at some point you are going to get used
会涉及到某种方法在某些时候你会习惯的
to different methods for a list that being said also
列表的不同方法话虽这么说也
you don't need to know all of them by hard i myself completely forgot about
你不需要知道所有这些很难我自己完全忘记了
reverse until i saw it when i prepared for this video
反向直到我准备时看到它对于这个视频
but well with that we have lists and i guess we have functions and we
但我们有清单我想我们有功能并且我们
have methods at least in a very basic outline
至少有非常基本的方法大纲
although there's one really important method that i do want to talk about and
虽然有一个非常重要我确实想谈的方法和
that one is called append
那个叫附加
and this one appends a value i think the
和这个附加了一个值，我认为
name makes sense here basically anything you add in here as an
名字在这里有意义基本上你在这里添加的任何东西
argument will be added at the end of the list
参数将添加在末尾列表
for example if i added let's say it 10 at the end
例如，如果我添加最后说10
run all of this now we can see all the way at the end we
运行所有这一切现在我们可以看到最后我们
have this 10. this would be one of the ways you add an
有这个10.这将是您添加的方法之一
item to a list there are quite a few more but this is a really basic one that
列表中的项目有很多更多，但这是一个非常基本的
i just want to cover for now with that we can look at the other kind of
我现在只想介绍一下我们可以看看另一种
container and that is called a tuple and the tuple you let me save it in a
容器，称为元组，你让我把它保存在一个元组中
variable that i called my tuple you would be creating with brackets
我称之为元组的变量你将用括号创建
and in here again you can add any kind of value you want could be a number
在这里你可以添加任何类型你想要的值可以是一个数字
could be a floating point number it could be a word
可以是浮点数这可能是一个词
or it could be a list as well that itself contains other values
或者它也可以是一个列表本身包含其他值
let's say 7 8 and 9. let me comment out the earlier stuff and
比方说 7、8 和 9。让我注释掉之前的内容
print my tuple and there we go now we can see all the
打印我的元组现在我们可以看到所有
values we have added in here a tuple and a list work in very similar
我们在这里添加的值元组和列表的工作方式非常相似
ways at least up to a point because there is
方法至少在某种程度上，因为有
a major difference that difference being that tuples
一个主要区别区别在于元组
cannot be changed under any circumstances
不能在任何情况下改变情况
this means i couldn't run something like my tuple
这意味着我无法运行像我的元组这样的东西
append and then let's use a 10 again
附加然后我们再次使用 10
the method we have used up here if i run this line of code we're getting
我们在这里使用的方法如果我运行这行代码，我们会得到
an error that tuple object has no attribute append
元组对象没有的错误属性追加
we also couldn't delete a value and we couldn't reverse the order of this tuple
我们也无法删除一个值，我们无法颠倒该元组的顺序
let me demonstrate the reverse one this one here
让我演示一下相反的这里有一个
this one also would not work on a tuple most of the time when you are using
这个也不适用于元组大多数时候当你使用
tuples you generally only want to use tuples
元组你通常只想使用元组
when you know you are not going to change the values
当你知道你不会改变值
but most of the time let's say 70 80 you are going to use a list this one is
但大多数时候我们说 70 80你将使用一个列表，这个是
the much more common data type because it is more flexible with that covered we
更常见的数据类型，因为我们所涵盖的内容更加灵活
have to cover a really important topic and that is how to pick
必须涵盖一个非常重要的主题这就是如何选择
elements from a tuple or a list what that means is for example i might
元组或列表中的元素这意味着例如我可能
want to get this floating point value here from the list and then work with it
想要得到这个浮点值从列表中选择这里，然后使用它
so how could i get this value and for that
那么我怎样才能得到这个值为此
we need a specific process that in python is called either indexing or
我们需要一个特定的过程python 被称为索引或
slicing the two are very much related
切片两者非常相关
let's talk about it actually let me actually go for this a bit more
让我们实际谈谈吧让我再努力一点
properly to restate the problem we want to pick one element from a list
正确地重述问题我们想从列表中选择一个元素
this could also be a tuple they both work in exactly the same way for us to
这也可能是一个元组我们以完全相同的方式工作
do that we need to cover two important concepts
为此我们需要涵盖两个重要的内容概念
the first one is that python assigns each value in a list on a tuple and
第一个是python分配的元组列表中的每个值以及
index number if this is our list python would give
索引号如果这是我们的列表 python 会给出
each of these numbers an index the first number is always going to be a
这些数字中的每一个都是一个索引第一个数字总是a
zero and then every successive number is going to be plus one of that number
零，然后每个连续的数字都是将是该数字的加一
meaning the second value is one the third value is two and then so on
意味着第二个值是第三个值是二，依此类推
and a really important point to notice here is that we always start counting
需要注意的一个非常重要的点我们总是从这里开始计数
from zero not one and this can be a very annoying concept
从零开始不是一这可能是一个非常烦人的概念
to deal with i think for beginners forgetting about this covers about half
我认为对于初学者来说忘记这一点大约占一半
of all of your errors just be ready for that
你所有的错误只是做好准备那
but anyway the concept we have for now is that every item inside of a list has
但无论如何我们现在的概念是列表中的每个项目都有
an index and this index we can use to pick an element and this works by adding
一个索引，这个索引我们可以用来选择一个元素，这可以通过添加来实现
square brackets after the list or tuple in practice this would look something
列表或元组后面的方括号实际上，这看起来有些东西
like this right now we have our list and then
像这样现在我们有了清单，然后
after the list we have another set of square brackets with an integer and this
在列表之后我们还有另一组方括号里有一个整数，这个
integer is going to pick one specific index right now the index
将选择整数现在有一个特定的索引
one which is going to be the second element this one here meaning this
一个将是第二个元素 this 在这里表示这个
operation would return the value 2 and since we are using an index this entire
操作将返回值 2 并且因为我们整个都使用索引
operation is called indexing it works on quite a few data types lists
操作称为索引它适用于相当多的数据类型列表
and tuples should be fairly obvious we could also be using it with strings
元组应该是相当明显的也可以与字符串一起使用
because they are basically another kind of container we can have a look at this
因为他们基本上是另一种容器的我们可以看看这个
one as well however indexing does not work on
也有一个但是索引不起作用
dictionaries and sets dictionaries work in a slightly
字典和集合字典的工作方式略有不同
different way and sets work in a very different way we are going to see that
不同的方式并以非常不同的方式工作我们将以不同的方式看待这一点
later on and i guess let's play around with all of this
稍后我想我们可以一起玩一下与这一切
here i am back in my code and i want to comment out
我回到了我的代码，我想要注释掉
the two methods for the tuple and i want to uncomment my list
元组的两种方法，我想要取消注释我的列表
meaning now i have a list and a tuple to work with
意思是现在我有一个列表和一个元组与...一起工作
and i want to just pick some random elements from them i guess we can start
我想随机挑选一些他们的元素我想我们可以开始
with my list and in here i am using square brackets and now i need an
与我的列表和在这里我使用方括号，现在我需要一个
integer i'm going to pick 0 just to pick the first element
整数我要选择 0 只是为了选择第一个元素
this zero now is going to refer to the first element
现在这个零将引用第一个元素
inside of my list or the one with the index zero
在我的列表中或带有索引零
if we added a one we will get the next element two three four and so on
如果我们添加一个，我们将得到下一个元素二三四等等
to show all of this we have to print it again now if i run this we are getting
为了显示所有这些，我们必须打印它现在再次如果我运行这个我们会得到
one indeed the value up here if i added it 2 in here
确实是这里的价值如果我在这里添加 2
and run this again we are getting the integer 3 which is
再次运行我们得到整数 3 是
this item here we have 0 1 and 2. all of this would also work with a tuple
这个项目我们有 0 1 和 2。全部这也适用于元组
meaning if i use my tuple this tuple here
意思是如果我使用我的元组这个元组这里
and now pick let's say the item number 5.
现在选择让我们说商品编号 5。
run this again we are now getting the list
再次运行这个我们现在正在获取清单
this one here at the end of the tuple because this one is the element with the
这个位于元组的末尾因为这个元素是
index five we have zero one two three four and five
索引五我们有零一二三四五
what we can do now as well is to add another square brackets
我们现在也能做什么就是再加一个方括号
afterwards because remember what we are getting from this one here
之后因为记住我们是什么从这里得到
is going to return one item from this tuple in this case this list here which
将从中返回一项元组在这种情况下这个列表在这里
means that this operation here stands in for this tuple so when we add
意思就是这里的这个操作代表这个元组，所以当我们添加
the square brackets afterwards these ones here
之后的方括号是这些这里的
we are basically adding the square brackets after here and then we can take
我们基本上是在添加正方形这里后面的括号然后我们可以采取
other elements from that if i add a zero in here we should be
其他元素如果我在这里加一个零，我们应该是
getting seven my tuple five gets us
得到七我的元组五让我们
this list here and then the zero gets us the first
这个列表在这里然后零让我们成为第一个
element inside of it these operations are fairly common right
里面的元素这些操作相当常见吧
now i assume they do seem quite confusing but if you play around with
现在我认为他们看起来确实很令人困惑，但如果你玩弄
them for a while they should become fairly familiar just remember what is
他们应该暂时成为相当熟悉，只记得是什么
getting returned and how you can work with that
返回以及如何工作接着就，随即
there's one more thing that you could be doing in here let me duplicate the line
你还可以做一件事在这里做让我复制该行
i only want to use one indexing operation
我只想使用一个索引手术
what you can also do is go in the negative direction for example if i use
你还可以做的是进入负方向例如如果我使用
negative one we are getting the list again
负一我们再次收到清单
what this negative one means is we are always starting at zero and if we go in
这个负面的意思是我们是总是从零开始，如果我们进去
the positive direction we are basically going to the right
我们基本上是积极的方向向右走
however if we are choosing a negative number
但是如果我们选择负数数字
we are going all the way to the back of the
我们是一直走到后面
list and then going in the opposite direction meaning this list here would
列出，然后进行相反的操作方向意味着这里的列表将
be negative 1 word would be negative 2
为负 1这个词将是负面的 2
and the 1.45 would be negative 3
1.45 将是负3
which means that negative 3 and 4 should have the same result unless i made an
这意味着负 3 和 4 应该除非我做了一个，否则会有相同的结果
error let's try if i enter negative 3 we get 1.45
错误让我们尝试一下如果我输入负 3 我们得到 1.45
if i add 4 we are getting word and i just realized
如果我加4我们收到消息，我刚刚意识到
i can't count um sorry about that
我数不清嗯对于那个很抱歉
this should be a 3 and this is a 4. talking and writing can be kind of
这应该是 3，这是 4。说话和写作可以是一种
challenging i guess you noticed this one already but now
具有挑战性，我猜你注意到了这个已经但是现在
what you should be able to see is if i add a 3 in here we are getting 1.45 and
你应该能看到的是如果我在这里添加 3，我们得到 1.45，
if i add a negative 3 we are also getting 1.45 all right with that we have
如果我加上一个负数 3 我们也是得到 1.45 就可以了
basically all we need to get started with indexing this is a very simple
基本上我们需要开始通过索引，这是一个非常简单的
operation when it comes down to it although this video is getting kind of
归根结底的操作虽然这个视频有点
long so let's do an exercise and then we finish this section
太久了，让我们做一个练习，然后我们完成本节
and what i want you guys to do let me paste it in here's the exercise
我想让你们做的让我做将其粘贴到这里是练习
we have a long string and of the string i want you guys to pick one word or
我们有一根长绳子和绳子我希望你们选一个词或者
string and that is hello that is going to be this element here
字符串，那就是你好成为这里的这个元素
although do notice here that this is a list
虽然请注意这里这是一个列表
inside of a list inside of another list so you
代替另一个列表中的列表，这样你
have to pick elements that are quite a bit nested
必须选择相当重要的元素位嵌套
but if you paid attention so far this should be doable so pause the video now
但如果你到目前为止注意到了这一点应该是可行的，所以现在暂停视频
and try this one yourself
并亲自尝试一下这个
alrighty let's get started and just to illustrate what is happening here
好吧，让我们开始吧说明这里发生的事情
let me save all of this in a separate variable that i'm going to call solution
让我将所有这些保存在单独的我将调用解决方案的变量
var and this
变量和这个
is going to be we always have to start with the exercise list
我们总是要开始与练习清单
now we need square brackets and we want to pick
现在我们需要方括号，我们想要选择
one item from here with the index we have item number zero we have item
这里的一项带有索引我们有零号物品 我们有物品
number one and we have item number two and item number one covers this entire
第一，我们有第二项第一项涵盖了整个
list here this is what we want meaning in here i want item number one which
在这里列出这就是我们想要的意思在这里我想要第一项
means if i print the solution variable and comment out all of the stuff above
意味着如果我打印解决方案变量并注释掉上面的所有内容
and run all of this now we can see we have the list with one two three four
现在运行所有这些我们可以看到有一二三四的清单
five and then the other list inside and from this we want to get another index
五个，然后是里面的其他列表和由此我们想要得到另一个索引
now we have let me clean this one up a tiny bit
现在我们让我清理这个一点点
purely inside of this list here we have a few more elements
纯粹在这个列表中，我们有还有一些元素
we have 0 we have 1 and then we have 2 2 being this entire thing this is all we
我们有 0 我们有 1 然后我们有 22 这就是整个事情，这就是我们的全部
want right now which means we now want the index number
现在想要这意味着我们现在想要索引号
2. now if i print my solution i get another
2.现在，如果我打印我的解决方案，我会得到另一个
list with zero and hello we are getting very close
列表为零，你好，我们得到了很接近
now inside of this final list this list alone here we have two entries
现在在这个最终列表中仅此列表就有两个条目
we have zero and we have 1 and 1 is our solution
我们有 0 个，我们有 1 个1 是我们的解决方案
which means at the end of this i want to add a 1 and then we should be done so
这意味着最后我想添加 1 然后我们就应该这样做
let's try and there we go we get hello obviously
让我们尝试一下，我们开始打招呼明显地
you would very rarely see something like this this is very poor data management
你很少会看到类似的东西这是非常糟糕的数据管理
because it's a very messy list that is really hard to work with
因为这是一个非常混乱的列表真的很难合作
but i guess it's a very good exercise this video is going to be part 2 on
但我想这是一个很好的练习该视频将成为第二部分
lists and tuples and this is primarily going to be about picking multiple
列表和元组，这主要是将要选择多个
elements so the main problem we have to cover is
元素所以我们要解决的主要问题是
how to pick multiple elements from a list
如何从a中选取多个元素列表
let's say we have a list with the numbers one two four and we want to get
假设我们有一个列表数字一二四，我们想要得到
the second and the third element how could we do that right now we can only
第二个和第三个元素如何我们现在可以这样做吗？我们只能
pick a single element fortunately python can do this with something that is very
幸运的是python选择了一个元素可以用非常重要的东西来做到这一点
similar compared to indexing and that is slicing
与索引相似，即切片
how this works is you are still going to need square brackets like with indexing
这是如何运作的，你仍然会需要像索引一样的方括号
but now instead of adding one number you are adding two numbers separated by a
但现在你不用添加一个数字将两个由 a 分隔的数字相加
colon the first number is the start and the
冒号第一个数字是开始和
second number is the end value for example it could look something like
第二个数字是最终值例如它可能看起来像
this for example in here we have the indexes
这例如在这里我们有索引
from zero to three one right now is going to refer to this
从零到三现在有人会提到这一点
two here and 2 is going to refer to the index
这里有两个2 将引用索引
number 2 which right now is going to be a 3. this is how we are picking the
2号现在将是a 3. 这就是我们挑选的方式
start and the end value however there is going to be a really important concept
开始和结束值但是有将是一个非常重要的概念
you have to understand and that is python only goes up to the
你必须明白那是 python 只上升到
end but it does not include it which means in this case we would only get one
结束但不包括它意味着在这种情况下我们只会得到一个
number we would be starting on this 2 here that
数字我们将从这 2 开始
is our start value however we are only going up to
是我们的起始值，但我们只是上升到
index number two we are not including it so in practice our list indexing ends
索引二我们不包括它所以实际上我们的列表索引结束
here right before our end index as a consequence this operation here is
就在我们的结束索引之前因此这里的操作是
only going to return this two and nothing else
只会返回这两个没有其他的
that is going to be a fairly common issue but you will get used to it let's
这将是一个相当普遍的现象问题，但你会习惯的，让我们
practice this one once again here i have a completely empty python file and i
我在这里再练习一次一个完全空的 python 文件和我
want to create a test list and that is the list we have just seen this one has
想要创建一个测试列表，那就是我们刚刚看到的这个列表有
the values one two three and four and just to demonstrate what i've just
值一、二、三和四只是为了展示我刚刚所做的
talked about i want to print my test list
谈到我想打印我的测试列表
and in here i want the values from 1 colon 2.
在这里我想要从 1 开始的值冒号 2.
if i now run this i am getting another list with 2.
如果我现在运行这个，我会得到另一个列出2.
that means that list slicing always returns a list even if there's only a
这意味着列表切片总是返回一个列表，即使只有一个
single value inside for example what we could even do is go from index 1 to
例如我们里面的单个值甚至可以做的是从索引 1 到
index 1 which would get us if i run this an
索引1如果我运行这个，这会让我们
empty list and this is something you always have to
空列表这是你必须做的事情
keep in mind if you want in this case for example the second and the third
在这种情况下，如果您愿意，请记住例如第二个和第三个
element you have to go to the index after that in this case this is going to
你必须转到索引的元素之后在这种情况下这将是
be one two three if i run this now we are getting the
成为一二三如果我现在运行这个我们会得到
numbers 2 and 3. and that for start is all you have to
数字 2 和 3。首先这就是你所要做的
know about slicing although you can do quite a bit more but let's talk about
了解切片虽然你可以做还有很多，但我们来谈谈
this inside of my slides besides the start and the end value you
我的幻灯片里面除了开始值和结束值之外
can also add a third number for the direction
还可以添加第三个数字方向
by default this one is going to be zero meaning we are always moving plus one in
默认情况下这个值为零意味着我们总是在移动加一
the positive direction it might look something like this we again have the
它可能看起来的积极方向像这样我们又得到了
same list and we have our indexes 0 1 2 and 3.
相同的列表，我们有索引 0 1 2和 3.
and this one here at the end means that we are moving in the positive
最后这个意味着我们正朝着积极的方向前进
direction in a step size of 1 which right now will get us the next
步长为 1 的方向现在这将给我们带来下一个
element but we could have a larger or smaller value you could also have
元素，但我们可以有一个更大的或您也可以拥有较小的值
negative values to go into the other direction
负值进入另一个方向
here we are back in the code and i want to add a few more values to this list so
我们回到代码中，我想要向此列表添加更多值，以便
it's a bit easier to visualize what's happening
更容易想象是什么正在发生
now we have the values from 1 to 10. although if i run this one here
现在我们的值是从 1 到 10。虽然如果我在这里运行这个
it is going to give us the same result but now let's say i want to have the
它会给我们相同的结果但现在假设我想要
values from 0 to 8. if i run this we are getting the
值从 0 到8.如果我运行这个我们会得到
first eight values although now what i can do i can add
前八个值虽然现在我能做什么我可以添加
another set of colons and then for example add a two in here
另一组冒号，然后例如在此处添加 2
and now if i run this i am only getting every second value
现在如果我运行这个我只会得到每秒值
so we are starting at the index number zero and we are only ever picking every
所以我们从索引号开始零，我们只挑选每一个
second value which is the three the five and then the seven
第二个值是三五然后是七个
and since our last index is going to be here we're not including this 9 anymore
由于我们的最后一个索引将是这里我们不再包括这 9 个
and then we're getting the values 1 3 5 and 7 the values down here
然后我们得到值 1 3 5和 7 这里的值
and this step size can also be negative for example you could in here add a
并且这个步长也可以是负数例如你可以在这里添加一个
negative one although right now this wouldn't do very much
负面的虽然现在这个不会做太多事
so the issue here is we are starting at this value as our starting point
所以这里的问题是我们从这个值作为我们的起点
and our end value is eight which i believe is this value here
我们的最终值为 8，我相信这个值在这里
and since we are now moving in this direction there simply isn't any value
既然我们现在要搬进这个方向根本没有任何价值
so this entire operation doesn't give us anything
所以整个操作并没有给我们任何事物
however what we can do is flip those two around so our start value is 8 and our n
然而我们能做的就是翻转这两个大约所以我们的起始值为 8，我们的 n
value is 0. if i now run out of this we get all of
值为 0。如果我现在用完了这个，我们就会得到所有
these values reversed and negative values you can add actually
这些值颠倒了和你实际可以添加的负值
everywhere in here so for example you could have the start value of negative
这里到处都是所以例如你起始值可能为负
one and the end value let's say at four this is going to work just like normal
1 和最终值（假设为 4）这会像平常一样工作
indexing this would mean you are starting here all the way at the end
索引这意味着你是从这里开始一直到最后
that is the negative one and then we're going to the fourth element which is
这是负面的，然后我们转到第四个元素，即
going to be zero one two three and four this one
将零一二三四这个一
here is index number four so we are expecting to get the numbers
这是索引号四所以我们期待得到数字
from ten to six let's see if that's the case
从十到六让我们看看情况是否如此
and it is we get numbers from 10 to 6 and that is basically all you have to
我们得到从 10 到 6 的数字这基本上就是你所要做的
understand about the basics here although there's one more thing that you
了解这里的基础知识虽然你还有一件事
can do and that is you can also leave values
可以做也就是说你也可以留下值
entirely empty when using slicing this might look something like this
使用切片时完全为空可能看起来像这样
this does look a bit strange but it does work
这看起来确实有点奇怪，但确实如此工作
what it means is let me talk through it every number in the slicing operation
这意味着让我来谈谈切片操作中的每个数字
has a default value so we have a start and end and a step
有一个默认值所以我们有开始、结束和步骤
value for start the default value is always the very first item inside of the
启动值默认值为始终是里面的第一个项目
list in the example here it would be a 1.
在此处的示例中列出它将是1.
the end value by default is always going to be the last item inside of the list
默认情况下的最终值始终是成为列表中的最后一项
in this case here that would be a 4 and for the step size the default value
在这种情况下，这将是 4对于步长大小，使用默认值
is a 1 which means we are always moving plus one in the positive direction by
是 1 意味着我们一直在移动正方向加一
default this one should make sense it's quite straightforward
默认这个应该有意义相当简单
and let's play around with all of that let's see how far we get
让我们尝试一下所有这些让我们看看我们能走多远
so here we are back in the code and let me actually add all of this inside
所以我们回到代码中让我将所有这些添加到里面
of a variable let's call it negative slicing i should
一个变量的我们应该称之为负切片
probably add more variables so it's easier to follow in the notes
可能添加更多变量，所以它是在注释中更容易理解
but let's start working on leaving values empty this i want to save in a
但让我们开始努力离开值为空，我想保存在
variable let me call it default slicing
变量让我称之为默认值切片
in here as always i need my test list and in here i want to go from my start
一如既往，我需要我的测试清单在这里我想从头开始
to the end of the list and i only want to get every second
到列表末尾我只想得到每一秒
value now the start is going to be easy
价值现在开始会很容易
because this one is always going to be one but you could also leave it
因为这个永远都会是一个，但你也可以留下它
completely empty it would have the same result and here we could also leave
完全空它会有相同的结果，我们也可以离开这里
empty that would get us the very last item inside of a list 10 right now and
空的，这会让我们最后一个现在列表 10 中的项目以及
this is actually really useful because by default we don't know what the last
这实际上非常有用，因为默认情况下我们不知道最后一个是什么
index is going to be finally i want to have every second element
索引最终将是我想要的每隔一个元素
this would be a 2 in here and now let me print the default slicing
这里是 2现在让我打印默认切片
variable let's run this and we're only getting every second value
变量让我们运行这个，我们只是获取每秒的值
we could also add every third value in here
我们还可以添加每第三个值这里
and there we go if you left all three of them empty and
我们就这样吧如果你把三个都留空并且
run this again you will get all of the numbers so this is looking a bit strange
再次运行这个你会得到所有的数字所以这看起来有点奇怪
but it certainly is working and this system can be incredibly useful
但它确实有效这个系统非常有用
as a consequence let's do an exercise and what i want you guys to do
因此我们来做一个练习我希望你们做什么
is this exercise here i want you guys to start from 8 and go to 2 and only pick
这是这个练习吗？我希望你们这样做从8开始，到2，只选择
every second element and when i say 8 and 2 i mean actual
每隔一个元素当我说 8 和 2 时，我的意思是实际的
number not indexes so you want to start at this 8 here and
数字而非索引所以你想从这里的 8 开始
then go to this to here at the end these are the values you are going to cover
然后转到这里到最后这些是您要涵盖的值
except only every second element meaning the 7 shouldn't be in here this 5
除了每隔一个元素的含义7 不应该在这里，这 5
shouldn't be in here and so on so pause the video now and try to figure
不应该在这里等所以现在暂停视频并尝试弄清楚
this one out
这个出来了
let me save all of this inside of a variable and as always we need the test
让我将所有这些保存在一个变量，一如既往，我们需要测试
list in here
列表在这里
we need square brackets for slicing and now we need a start an end and a step
我们需要方括号来进行切片和现在我们需要一个开始、一个结束和一个步骤
size since we do have to go negative remember
尺寸因为我们确实必须消极记住
we are starting from 8 and we are going to 2 this has to be a negative number
我们从8点开始，我们要去到 2 这必须是负数
let's say negative 1 now just to have a start value
现在我们说负 1 只是为了有一个起始值
while i do this let me show the solution right now what we are going to get is
当我这样做时，让我展示解决方案现在我们要得到的是
the entire list in reverse although in my case i don't want to
整个列表相反虽然就我而言我不想
start at 10 i want to start at 8 meaning we have to figure out how we can
10 点开始 我想 8 点开始这意味着我们必须弄清楚如何才能
get this 8 here that would be our start value
在这里得到这个 8这将是我们的起始值
and one mistake you could be making in here is simply add an 8 because this
以及你可能犯的一个错误这里只是添加一个 8 因为这
would not work right now we are starting at 9.
行不通现在我们9点开始。
the problem here is remember when we're using indexing we are starting at zero
这里的问题是记住当我们使用索引我们从零开始
meaning this is zero one two three four five six seven eight and nine
意思是零一二三四五六七八九
meaning if we are adding the index eight we are adding on the nine here which
意思是如果我们添加索引八我们在这里添加九个
isn't helpful instead what we could do is add a 7 in
没有帮助相反，我们可以做的是添加一个 7
here and now if i run this again we are starting at 8. alternatively what you
此时此地，如果我再次运行这个，我们就会从 8 开始。或者你
could also do is add a negative 3 in here
还可以做的是添加一个负3这里
if i run this one we are also starting at 8.
如果我运行这个，我们也将开始在8点。
and i guess remember we could also go negatively so this 9 would be negative 1
我想记得我们也可以去负数，所以这个 9 将是负 1
then we have negative 2 and negative 3 that would be our 7.
那么我们有负 2 和负 3那将是我们的7。
both would be fine it's really up to you what you prefer i guess the 7 here is a
两者都可以，这完全取决于你你喜欢什么我猜这里的 7 是
bit more expressive but well it's basically subjective
更具表现力但是嗯，这基本上是主观的
but now we have to find the end value and in here you might be very tempted to
但现在我们必须找到最终值在这里你可能很想
pick one for the index let me actually do that
选择一个作为索引让我实际这样做
if i add a one in here run this again we are ending on three as our final
如果我在这里添加一个，请再次运行我们将以三作为最后的结局
element the reason is that
元素原因是
python always only goes up to the final element but it doesn't include it
python总是只进入决赛元素但不包含它
as a consequence three is going to be our final element the way around that
结果三将是我们的最后一个元素就是围绕这个问题
one is this should be a zero now our final element is this zero so
一是这应该是零现在我们的最后一个元素是零所以
we're going up to that element but we're not including it so two is our final
我们正在讨论这个元素，但是我们不包括它，所以两个是我们的最终结果
number the final thing we need is we only want
数字我们需要的最后一件事就是我们只想要
to pick every second element this is quite easy all we need is a
选取每隔一个的元素这很简单，我们需要的是
negative two if i now run out of this again we get eight six four and two and
负二如果我现在用完了这个我们再次得到八、六、四和二，
with that we are done this is basically all you need for slicing and this would
这样我们就完成了，这基本上是切片所需的一切，这将
also work for a tuple i guess let me demonstrate this one really quick let's
也适用于元组我想让我让我们快速演示一下这个
call it tuple slicing
称之为元组切片
and then here we have a test pupil and this one would just have the values one
然后我们有一个测试学生这个只有值 1
two three four five six seven 8 9 and 10 and in here i could for example print
二三四五六七8 9和10在这里我可以例如打印
test pupil
测试瞳孔
with the values 0 5 and let's say 3
值为 05 假设 3
it should be a colon and let me comment out the exercise here
它应该是一个冒号让我在这里评论一下这个练习
and there we go we get 1 and 4. once again a list and a tuple are
这样我们就得到了 1 和 4。再次是列表和元组
incredibly similar the only difference is is that a list can be modified
令人难以置信的相似是唯一的区别是一个列表可以修改
whereas a tuple cannot there is one more topic that i want to
而元组不能我还有一个话题想要讨论
cover with lists and tuples and that is unpacking
用列表和元组覆盖，那就是拆包
basically what that means is both lists and tuples can be unpacked in
基本上这意味着列表和元组都可以解包在
a way like this we have a and b and we are assigning a tuple to them
像这样我们有 a 和 b 并且我们正在为他们分配一个元组
what this is doing we are taking the first value and assigning it to the
这是在做什么，我们正在采取第一个值并将其分配给
first variable a and 10 in this case and the second value gets assigned to
本例中第一个变量 a 和 10第二个值被分配给
the second value and that way you are unpacking a tuple on two variables
第二个值就是这样解包两个变量的元组
this would also work with a list you would have the exact same result and
这也适用于列表你会得到完全相同的结果
let's have a look at all of this in code so for example what we can do i have a
让我们用代码来看看这一切例如我们可以做什么我有一个
variable called a and a variable called b
变量名为 a 和变量名为乙
and i want to assign them to the values 10 and 5 inside of a list
我想将它们分配给值列表中的 10 和 5
and this is well all we need if i now print a and print b
这就是我们所需要的，如果我现在打印a并打印b
we are getting an n5 we have unpacked this tuple on these two variables
我们收到了一个已拆封的 n5这两个变量的这个元组
although keep in mind this only works if you have the same number of items as you
尽管请记住这仅在以下情况下才有效你的物品数量与你相同
have variables if for example i added a third item to
有变量例如，如果我添加了第三个项目
this tuple let's say a 1. if i run this now
这个元组我们假设是 1。如果我现在运行这个
we're getting an error that we have too many values to unpack and python
我们也遇到了一个错误许多值需要解压和 python
expected 2 which we don't have but if you have the same number of
预计 2 但我们没有但如果你有相同数量的
variables as you have in the tuple you are good to go
元组中的变量可以走了
and this would also work inside of a list but let me add two more variables
这也适用于列出但让我添加两个变量
let's say c and d and now we have a list with i know 20
假设c和d现在我们有一个名单，其中我知道 20 个
and this also works with strings let's say hello
这也适用于字符串让我们问好
if i now print c and i print d we are getting 20 and hello and this you
如果我现在打印 c 并打印 d我们快到 20 了，你好，这是你
can also make more powerful because when you are creating a tuple
还可以让自己变得更强大因为当你创建一个元组时
you don't actually need brackets for example you can have a list like this or
你实际上并不需要括号例如，您可以有一个这样的列表或
you could create a list like this without the brackets just having values
你可以创建一个这样的列表没有括号，只有值
separated by a comma automatically creates a tuple
自动用逗号分隔创建一个元组
although most of the time when you want to create a tuple it makes more sense to
虽然大多数时候当你想要的时候创建一个元组更有意义
write the brackets because it's clearer what you are doing but you don't
写在括号里因为这样更清楚你正在做什么但你没有
actually have to do it now where all of this becomes really interesting is when
实际上现在必须这样做这变得非常有趣的是
you combine these two approaches because by doing that you can assign
你结合这两种方法因为通过这样做你可以分配
multiple values to multiple variables on a single line of code which is super
多个值到多个变量一行代码就超级棒
powerful for example we have the variables a b
强大的例如我们有变量 a b
and c and we are assigning the values 1
和c我们分配值 1
hello and 4.5 we have assigned values to three variables inside of a single line
你好，我们已经给 4.5 赋值了单行内的三个变量
of code so let's have a look at this one in practice and then we can do an
代码所以让我们看一下这个在实践中，然后我们可以做一个
exercise for example for video game you could
锻炼例如对于视频游戏你可以
have health you could have energy and you could have a weapon
拥有健康，你就能拥有能量和你可以有武器
and this you could all assign inside of a single line for the health we could
这你都可以在里面分配为了我们的健康，一条线
have 100 for the energy we could have 50 and for the weapon we could have a sword
100 的能量我们可以拥有 50对于武器我们可以有一把剑
and now i could print weapon for example and all the way at the end we are
现在我可以打印武器一直到最后我们都是
getting sword and i hope you see the value of this if
得到剑我希望你能看到这个的价值
you have to assign multiple variables this is really really useful to keep
你必须分配多个变量这真的非常有用，值得保留
your code a bit more organized and all right this video is going to be
你的代码更有条理好吧，这个视频将会是
a bit shorter we can do the exercise right away
稍微短一点，我们可以做这个练习马上
and what i want you guys to do is this we have a variable 1 with the value 10
我希望你们做的是这个我们有一个值为 10 的变量 1
and variable 2 with the value test and i want you guys to switch the values of
变量 2 的值为 test 和 i希望你们改变价值观
these two variables meaning value 1 should have the value
这两个变量意味着值 1 应该具有值
test and value 2 should have the value 10.
测试和值 2 应该具有值10.
so pause the video now and try to figure this one out
所以现在暂停视频并尝试弄清楚这个出来了
alright the solution here is actually incredibly simple all you have to do is
好吧，这里的解决方案实际上是难以置信的简单，你所要做的就是
you want to assign value 1 and value 2
你想赋值1和值 2
and what you want to assign them to is value 2 and value
你想把它们分配给什么值 2 和值
1. basically what we're doing now is for value 2 we are assigning it to value 1
1. 基本上我们现在所做的就是为了值 2 我们将其分配给值 1
and value 1 gets assigned to value 2. this is basically how you would switch
并且值 1 被分配给值 2。这基本上就是你切换的方式
around different values across different variables
围绕不同的价值观变量
meaning now if i print value one let me run this we are getting
意思是现在如果我打印价值一让我运行这个我们得到
test the value the value that used to be in
测试值 以前的值
the second variable before we're getting to the next section
第二个变量在我们进入下一部分之前
i want to do a short intermission and this one is strings lists and tuples
我想做一个短暂的中场休息这是字符串列表和元组
because those are surprisingly similar all three of them are basically just
因为它们惊人地相似他们三个基本上都只是
containers they just happen to have different formats
他们恰好拥有的容器不同的格式
and as a consequence you can move between them very easily and also use
因此你可以移动它们之间非常容易并且也可以使用
indexing on strings let me demonstrate all of this actually
字符串索引让我实际演示这一切
i already have two variables a test string and a test list
我已经有两个变量进行测试字符串和测试列表
i suppose we can start by turning a string into a list or a tubal
我想我们可以从将字符串转换为列表或管道
the two are very similar we don't really have to worry about the difference here
两者非常相似，但我们并不真的相似必须担心这里的差异
and to convert a string to a list or tuple you have a couple of different
并将字符串转换为列表或元组你有几个不同的
ways the first one we can use to test string
方法我们可以用第一个来测试字符串
and then use the method split and this one splits the string at a
然后使用 split 方法这个将字符串分割为
certain point if you don't specify anything in here and print a result
如果您不指定某个点这里有任何东西并打印结果
we are using a space to separate the values
我们使用空格来分隔价值观
if you enter a value in here let's say a t and run this again we now separate
如果您在此处输入一个值，比如说t 并再次运行此命令，我们现在分开
this wherever we have a t we start at the beginning here and the t
无论我们有什么地方我们从这里开始，然后
in there disappears meaning now in the string this t disappears and we have an
那里的意义现在消失了字符串这个 t 消失了，我们有一个
empty string at the beginning of the list
空的列表开头的字符串
then we have all of this stuff here up to the next t which is his is a and
那么我们这里就有所有这些东西直到下一个 t 是他的 is a 并且
then a space then we have the next t here and this
然后是一个空格然后我们有下一个 t 和这个
one then gets us to the next point the e s bit this one here and then finally we
然后，我们就可以到达下一点 e我们在这里咬了这个，最后我们
have another t and this one disappears and we are just left with an empty
再有一个t，这个就消失了我们只剩下一个空的
string most of the time you are just going to
细绳大多数时候你只是要去
use the space here this one does make a whole lot more sense another thing you
利用这里的空间，这个确实做了一个你更能感受到另一件事
could do is to use the list function
可以做就是使用列表功能
and this one turns any kind of data type into some kind of list or at least it
这个可以转换任何一种数据类型进入某种列表或至少它
tries to it doesn't work with every data type but a string definitely does work
尝试它并不适用于所有数据输入但字符串肯定有效
if i run this we are now turning every single
如果我运行这个我们现在正在转动每一个
character into one element inside of a list
将字符放入 a 内的一个元素中列表
this would also work with a tuple this is another function
这也适用于元组是另一个函数
here we can add test string once again and now we have the same thing except
在这里我们可以再次添加测试字符串现在我们有同样的事情除了
now it's a tuple instead of a list the other way also works just fine we
现在它是一个元组而不是一个列表另一种方式也很好用
can turn a list or a tuple into a string although the process here can be a bit
可以将列表或元组转换为字符串虽然这里的过程可能有点
weird basically what you would be doing is you first get a string
基本上你会做什么很奇怪你首先得到一个字符串
and right now i'm going to leave it empty intentionally
现在我要离开它故意空着
then i need a dot and then i need a specific method and this method is
然后我需要一个点然后我需要一个具体方法，这个方法是
called join and into this method as an argument i
称为加入并作为参数 i 进入该方法
have to pass in some kind of list and as an argument here we are going to
必须传递某种列表作为这里的一个论点，我们将
need a list or a tuple although it has to be a special kind of tuple because
需要一个列表或一个元组，尽管它有是一种特殊的元组，因为
this one has to contain some kind of string
这个必须包含某种字符串
let's say one and two just to keep it simple
比方说一个两个只是为了简单起见
and now for run this these two elements here
现在运行这个这两个元素在这里
have been merged together what we are specifying inside of the string is going
我们已经合并在一起了指定字符串内部的内容
to be what determines the gap between the two
成为是什么决定了两者之间的差距
right now it's empty so there's no gap between 1 and 2.
现在它是空的，所以没有间隙1 到 2 之间。
i guess i could just add the gap in here if i run this now we get one gap two
我想我可以在这里添加间隙如果我现在运行这个，我们会得到一间隙二
if we added more values in here let's say three
如果我们在这里添加更多值我们说三个
and four
和四
we would always have a gap between each of these values
我们之间总会有差距这些值的
most of the time you are just going to leave it empty and now you have one
大多数时候你只是要去把它留空，现在你就有了一个
space between the values what you really have to be careful here
值之间的空间这里你真正需要注意的是
though is that all of these values have to be a string
但所有这些价值观都有成为一个字符串
i guess let me copy it and replace this with the test list
我想让我复制它并替换它与测试清单
we have up here if i run this now we are getting an
我们在这里如果我现在运行这个我们会得到一个
error that python has a type error sequence
错误python 有一个类型错误序列
item 0 expected is string instance in found
预期项目 0 是字符串实例成立
which is python's way of saying it wanted a word or a string but it
这是 python 的表达方式它想要一个单词或一个字符串，但它
found a number and it's really not happy about it
找到了一个号码，实在不高兴关于它
finally what you can do is to let me print it again
最后你能做什么是让我再打印一次
you can use the str function and pass in a list in here
您可以使用 str 函数并传入这里有一个列表
to turn this list into a string if i run this now
将此列表转换为字符串如果我现在运行这个
we are getting what looks like a list but this is actually a word or a string
我们得到了一个看起来像列表的东西但这实际上是一个单词或一个字符串
to demonstrate this let me put all of this inside of the type function if i
为了证明这一点让我把所有this 在类型函数内部如果我
run this now we get class string this one here is
现在运行这个我们得到类字符串，这里是
going to be a string it just looks like a list
将是一个字符串，看起来就像一个列表
but i hope you get the idea one more thing really quick and that is
但我希望你明白还有一件事真的很快，那就是
indexing on strings this one works like it would work for a list
在字符串上建立索引这个工作原理如下它适用于列表
for example i could have my test string and in here i want
例如我可以有我的测试字符串在这里我想要
the first element which right now should be a t
现在应该的第一个元素打
if i print all of this i am indeed getting a t
如果我打印所有这些我确实是得到一个 t
just like with a list in the string the first element is going to be 0 then we
就像字符串中的列表一样第一个元素将为 0 那么我们
have 1 2 3 and so on you could even use slicing here and for
有 1 2 3 等等你甚至可以在这里使用切片
example at the 5 and now we're getting this the first word
以 5 为例，现在我们得到这是第一个词
and i think it is quite valuable here to compare these two data types because
我认为这是非常有价值的比较这两种数据类型，因为
when you think about words they really are just containers for individual
当你思考词语时，它们确实只是个人的容器
characters and for python it made a lot of sense to make these interchangeable
字符和Python它做了很多使这些可以互换是有意义的
with a list or a tuple because well it does make kind of sense
带有列表或元组，因为它确实有道理
one of the major operations you are going to do as a programmer is to work
您从事的主要业务之一作为一名程序员要做的就是工作
between different data types so understanding how you can change one
不同数据类型之间因此了解如何改变
data type to another data type is a really valuable experience
数据类型到另一种数据类型是非常宝贵的经验
but okay there's one exercise i do want you guys to do and that is going to be
但好吧，我确实想要一项练习你们要做的就是
connected to this operation here let me copy it and add an exercise here
在这里连接到此操作让我复制它并在此处添加练习
at the end what i want you guys to do on this
在最后我希望你们对此做什么
string test list i want you guys
字符串测试列表我想要你们
to use string methods to remove all of the stuff so you only
使用字符串方法删除所有的东西，这样你就可以
get one two three and four let me comment out
得到一二三四让我评论一下
all of the other parts to see what we get
所有其他部分，看看我们有什么得到
right now we're getting square brackets then 1 comma 2 comma 3 comma 4
现在我们得到了方括号然后 1 逗号 2 逗号 3 逗号 4
and square brackets again and i only want to have 1 2 3 and 4.
再次加上方括号我只想有 1 2 3 和 4。
try to use some methods to get rid of all of the other values besides the
尝试用一些方法来摆脱除 之外的所有其他值
numbers and see how far you get
数字，看看你能走多远
to make this a bit easier let me save the result in a separate
让这变得更容易一点让我将结果保存在单独的文件中
variable let's call it exercise this is also what i want to print
变量我们称之为练习这也是我想打印的
right now we have to get rid of a couple of different things
现在我们必须摆脱几个不同事物的
let's start with the square brackets for those
让我们从方括号开始对于那些
we need the method we have already seen much earlier called strip
我们需要我们已经见过的方法更早以前称为条带
and this one we want to start with one of the square
和这个我们想从其中一个正方形开始
brackets doesn't really matter which one you start with
括号中的哪一个并不重要你从
if i run this now we got rid of one square bracket
如果我现在运行这个我们就摆脱了一个方括号
and remember we can combine different methods meaning i can call
记住我们可以结合不同的方法意味着我可以打电话
strip again and now add the other square brackets
再次脱衣现在添加其他方括号
the closing one we now have all the numbers and the commas in between them
最后一个我们现在拥有了所有数字和它们之间的逗号
and to get rid of the commas we want to replace them
并去掉我们想要的逗号替换它们
meaning i want to target my comma and then replace it with an empty string
意思是我想定位我的逗号然后用空字符串替换它
so nothing now if we run this we are only getting
所以什么都没有现在如果我们运行这个我们只会得到
the numbers 1 2 3 and 4 and we are done if you wanted to you could even get rid
数字 1 2 3 和 4 我们就完成了如果你愿意的话你甚至可以摆脱
of the spaces here as well and this you would achieve with another
这里的空间也是如此而这你可以通过另一个实现
replace method and now i want to target the empty space
替换方法现在我想瞄准空白区域
and replace this with nothing now if i run this
并将其替换为空现在如果我运行这个
we have all of the numbers right next to each other whichever you prefer
我们旁边有所有的数字彼此，无论你喜欢哪个
at this point this is hopefully at least manageable
在这一点上，这至少是有希望的易于管理的
the next important data type is a dictionary and this one is a more
下一个重要的数据类型是字典，这个是一个更多
complex container but still just a container for other variables
复杂的容器，但仍然只是一个其他变量的容器
this one always has a key and a value pair the example 4 that i have is this
这个总是有一个键和一个值配对我的示例 4 是这样的
one in here we have a key and we have a value the key right now is an integer
在这里，我们有一把钥匙，我们有一把value 现在的键是一个整数
the one but it could also be any other data type
唯一的那个但它也可以是任何其他数据类型
python is fairly flexible here and then we have a value this one here a
python在这里相当灵活然后我们在这里有一个值
list but again it could also be any other data type
列表，但同样它也可以是任何其他数据类型
what you ultimately have to understand about dictionaries is that they are a
你最终必须明白什么关于字典的一点是它们是
container but a more organized one where every value has a key associated
容器，但更有组织性其中每个值都有一个关联的键
and you would use the key to access the value that way you wouldn't go by
您将使用密钥来访问价值是你不会过去的
indexing you would instead have specific values we're going to cover that in more
索引你会得到特定的我们将在更多内容中介绍这一点
detail later on but let's start playing around with that
稍后详细介绍，但让我们开始玩吧与此相关
let me start by creating a test dictionary
让我首先创建一个测试字典
and a dictionary you always create with curly brackets
以及一本你经常用来创建的字典大括号
and inside of the curly brackets you need a key
在大括号内需要一把钥匙
then a colon and then a value both of those have to be valid python
然后是冒号，然后是一个值这两个都必须是有效的 python
data types for example for the key let me call it
数据类型例如，对于钥匙，让我称之为
capital a and the value could just be an integer
资本a并且该值可以只是一个整数
let's say one two three this would now be one key value pair if you want to add
假设现在是一二三如果要添加，则为一个键值对
a second one you would add a comma and then the second key value pair
第二个你会添加一个逗号和然后是第二个键值对
let's say i want to call this one b and now i need a colon again and for the
假设我想将此称为 b现在我再次需要一个冒号
value now i want a list with the values i guess one two and three again
现在我想要一个包含值的列表我又猜一二三
i guess let me print this one so we can see the result if i run this we can see
我想让我打印这个，这样我们就可以看看结果如果我运行这个我们可以看到
we have a dictionary with two key value pairs
我们有一个有两个键值的字典对
right now the key is always a string but this doesn't have to be the case you
现在键始终是一个字符串，但是这不一定是你的情况
could also use a number like 1 and then give it the value of i guess we
也可以使用像 1 这样的数字然后给它的值我想我们
haven't used the boolean yet so i can just add true in here if i now run this
还没有使用布尔值所以我可以如果我现在运行这个，只需在此处添加 true
we get another key value pair the one limitation you do want to be aware of
我们得到另一个键值对您确实想了解的限制
here is you cannot duplicate keys for example if i added another a
这是你不能重复的钥匙例如，如果我添加另一个
with i don't know let's say another value and if i now run this
我不知道，让我们说另一个值，如果我现在运行这个
this first value has disappeared the reason being that once we add the
第一个值已经消失原因是一旦我们添加
same key we are overwriting the original key value pair
相同的密钥我们将覆盖原来的键值对
although most of the time that really isn't an issue you are too concerned
虽然大多数时候确实这不是你太关心的问题
about and once again you also have a ton of methods you could be using for
大约，再一次你也有很多您可以使用的方法
dictionaries to go through all of them here is w3schools with a list of all of
字典来浏览所有这些这是 w3schools 的所有列表
the methods you have available some that you are going to use fairly
您可以使用的方法一些你会公平使用的
often are values keys and items this one here because those return specific parts
通常是值键和项目这一项这里因为那些返回特定部分
of the dictionary let's play around with a couple actually
我们来玩一下字典的实际上是一对
right now if i run this we are getting the entire dictionary but if i add
现在如果我运行这个我们会得到整个字典，但如果我添加
another method here and add values don't forget the brackets run this again
这里的另一种方法并添加值不忘记括号再次运行
now i am getting some kind of list looking thing
现在我得到了某种清单看起来的东西
with just the values from this dictionary
和只是这个字典中的值
keep in mind this is a different kind of data type
请记住这是一种不同的数据类型
if i put this into the type function run this again
如果我把这个进入类型函数再次运行
we're getting class dictionary values this is a completely separate data type
我们正在获取类字典值这是一个完全独立的数据类型
in and of itself although you don't have to worry about
在其本身虽然你不必担心
it too much there are specific use cases for it and they all work basically
太多了，有特定的用例为此，它们基本上都可以工作
automatically and you never think about the data type here
自动地，你永远不会想到这里的数据类型
the other method would be keys and this one gives you all of the keys again in
另一种方法是键，这个一个人再次给你所有的钥匙
the dig keys data type finally what we could also be looking at
dig 键数据类型最后我们还可以关注什么
is items and this one is going to return the list but now it has two builds
是物品，这个将要返回列表，但现在它有两个版本
inside and those we could also access we are going to learn how this works later
里面以及我们也可以访问的那些稍后将了解这是如何工作的
on and if you go for the list of the
在如果你去查看列表
different methods this one should be fairly straightforward
这个应该是不同的方法非常坦率的
besides that you can also use once again the lan
除此之外您还可以再次使用局域网
method is incredibly versatile in here we can add the test dictionary and we
这里的方法非常通用我们可以添加测试字典，然后我们
would get three meaning we have three key value pairs inside of this
会得到三个意味着我们有三个this 里面的键值对
dictionary we have one two and three and that's kind of it for the basics of
字典中我们有一、二和三这就是基础知识
a dictionary it really isn't that complicated i guess let me add a comment
一本字典，其实不是那样的复杂我想让我添加评论
here at the top for basics of a dictionary
在顶部了解 a 的基础知识字典
one topic i do want to cover really quick is converting a dictionary
我确实想讨论一个主题快速正在转换字典
for example what we could be doing i guess let me print the results straight
例如我们可以做什么猜猜让我直接打印结果
away i could get my test dictionary and
离开我可以拿到我的测试词典
convert it to a list for example if i run this
例如将其转换为列表如果我运行这个
we are now getting an actual list with all of the keys
我们现在得到了一个实际的列表所有的钥匙
meaning the list contains a b
意味着列表包含乙
and 1. something you really want to keep in
和 1。你真正想保留的东西
mind when you are converting the data type here
转换数据时请注意在此输入
tuple would result in the very same outcome i
元组会导致完全相同的结果我
guess finally you could also convert all of this to a string
最后猜想你也可以转换所有这个到一个字符串
and then you would get the entire dictionary as a string
然后你会得到整个字典作为字符串
probably not the most useful thing you could do but well you can do it
可能不是你最有用的东西可以，但是你可以做到
i do want to cover one more important thing and that is indexing with
我确实想介绍一个更重要的内容东西，那就是索引
dictionaries
字典
and here we have a problem because indexing the way we have learned it so
这里我们遇到了一个问题，因为按照我们学到的方式建立索引
far does not work and i think this makes sense if you have a dictionary like that
远不起作用，我认为这使得感觉如果你有一本这样的字典
and you want to add some kind of indexing operation at the end let's say
你想添加某种最后的索引操作比方说
with the number zero this to python would be kind of
与数字零这对 python 来说是一种
confusing this could for python mean you want to
令人困惑的这对于 python 来说可能意味着你想要
have the first item inside of the index or it could mean you are supposed to
索引中的第一项或者这可能意味着你应该
look for a key
寻找关键
with the value 0. in this dictionary this doesn't exist
值为 0。这本字典里不存在这个
but python doesn't know it when it sees this number here
但Python看到时并不知道这个号码在这里
as a consequence the normal indexing does not work
因此正常索引不起作用
but there is another way actually there are two other ways you would do
但实际上还有另一种方式还有另外两种方法吗
something like this instead of an integer you would add the
像这样的东西而不是整数，您可以添加
name of the key in this case we have square brackets with an a and
本例中键的名称我们有一个带有 a 和 的方括号
the a refers to this key here what is then being returned is
a 在这里指的是这个键然后返回的是
the value associated with the key which is the one another way of doing this is
与键关联的值另一种方法是
the method get this one works in the same way you are
该方法得到这个和你的工作方式一样
passing in a key this key looks for a specific key value pair in the
传递一个键，这个键寻找一个中的特定键值对
dictionary and we are getting the value associated returned
字典，我们正在获取值相关返回
back in my code i want to print test dictionary
回到我的代码我想打印测试词典
and now i want to get the value for capital a
现在我想得到的值资本a
if i run this now we get 1 2 3 which is the value we have gotten all the way up
如果我现在运行这个我们得到 1 2 3 这是我们一路上涨的价值
here along the same lines instead of using square brackets you
这里沿着同样的路线而不是使用方括号
could use the method get and in here pass in the key you are
可以使用方法 get并在这里传递你的密钥
looking for and you will get the value associated with it one two three again
寻找，你就会得到价值再次关联一二三
you may be wondering now what is the difference between these two approaches
你现在可能想知道什么是这两种方法之间的区别
and generally get is slightly better because if you're looking for a key that
一般来说得到的是稍微好一些因为如果你正在寻找一把钥匙
doesn't exist let's say x in this case if you use square brackets
不存在，在本例中假设为 x如果你使用方括号
you are going to get an error meaning your entire code is going to crash
你会得到一个错误的意思你的整个代码将会崩溃
which usually is not a good sign but if you use the get method
这通常不是一个好兆头但如果你使用 get 方法
you don't get an error instead you get none returned
你不会得到错误，而是得到没有返回
which means let me add comments doesn't crash
这意味着让我添加评论不会崩溃
when it cannot find a key and i guess the comment here would be does crash
当它找不到钥匙时我猜这里的评论是 do crash
when it doesn't find the key or e
当它找不到钥匙时或e
besides that the two approaches are pretty much identical
除此之外，这两种方法是几乎相同
and with that we have covered all of the basic things for this part so let's do
这样我们就涵盖了所有的这部分的基本内容让我们开始吧
an exercise what i want you guys to do is to do some research and look up the
我希望你们做的一个练习是做一些研究并查找
update method for a dictionary and via this method add another key
字典的更新方法并通过此方法添加另一个密钥
value pair to this dictionary
该字典的值对
once again i am on a website that looks at all of the different methods that we
我再一次访问了一个看起来在我们使用的所有不同方法中
could be using with a dictionary and the one we want to look for right
可以与字典一起使用以及我们想要寻找的那个
now is called update if i click on it we have an example a definition syntax
如果我点击它，现在称为更新我们有一个定义语法的示例
and quite a few different things that we could be doing
还有很多不同的事情我们可能正在做
usually what i'm looking at is the example
通常我正在看的是例子
in here we have one dictionary and then we're
在这里我们有一本字典然后我们
using the update method and we are passing in as an argument in another
使用更新方法，我们是作为另一个参数传递
dictionary and this dictionary has a key and a value pair and this is going to
字典，这本字典有一个键和一个值对，这将是
insert all of this into the other dictionary
将所有这些插入到另一个中字典
so let's have a look at this i want to get my test dictionary and i
让我们看看这个我想要我的测试词典，我
want to use the update method and what we have seen so far is to
想要使用更新方法到目前为止我们所看到的是
insert another dictionary and in here we can just add some values
插入另一个字典在这里我们可以添加一些值
let's say i want another key that's not how you spell that then a colon
假设我想要另一把钥匙，但不是你怎么拼写然后冒号
and then some other values i guess what we haven't used yet is a tuple
然后是其他一些值我猜是什么我们还没有使用的是一个元组
with i don't know some other values in here
和我不知道这里还有其他一些值
if i run this we're not going to see any difference because we are not printing
如果我运行这个我们不会看到任何差异是因为我们不打印
our new dictionary meaning now if i print my task
我们的新词典意思是现在如果我打印我的任务
dictionary i can now see another key and one two
字典我现在可以看到另一把钥匙和一两个
three at the end although you could be using this method
最后三个虽然你可以使用这种方法
in another way as well let me get rid of the argument we had so
也以另一种方式让我摆脱我们之间的争论
far and what you could be doing as well is specify
到目前为止以及你还可以做什么是指定
some kind of name for a key in my case c and then specify a value let's say let
在我的案例 c 中，某个键的名称然后指定一个值让我们说让
me call it test if i run this now
我称之为测试如果我现在运行这个
we get a string c and then test as another value
我们得到一个字符串 c 然后测试为另一个值
and you could even add multiple values in here let's say d is going to be
你甚至可以添加多个值在这里假设 d 是
i know one two three it doesn't really matter and with that we have well
我知道一二三，但其实不知道很重要，这样我们就有了
another value i suppose while we are here there's one more way to add a value
我想当我们在的时候还有另一个价值这里还有另一种增加价值的方法
inside of a dictionary or a key value pair to be more specific
字典或键值内部配对更具体
and that is by using test dictionary and then using brackets and specifying a
那是通过使用测试字典然后使用括号并指定
new key here this is very similar to using the key here except now we are
这里的新密钥非常类似于使用这里的钥匙，但现在我们是
creating a whole new key value pair a value we haven't used yet would be e
创建一个全新的键值对我们还没有使用过的值是 e
and now you can just assign a new value to it let's say a hundred
现在你可以分配一个新值假设有一百个
if i now run this we have all the way at the end
如果我现在运行这个我们一路走到最后
the key e with the value 100 the thing we have specified here
键 e 的值为 100 的东西我们在这里指定了
and that is basically all you have to know about dictionaries it really is a
这基本上就是你所要做的了解字典，它确实是一个
fairly simple data type but one that gives a lot of order to your code
相当简单的数据类型，但给你的代码带来很多秩序
the final major data type is a set and these are also simple containers
最终的主要数据类型是集合这些也是简单的容器
just like the other containers we have seen but this one is kind of different
就像我们拥有的其他容器一样见过，但这个有点不同
and special in some way it would look like this we still have curly brackets
在某种程度上它看起来很特别像这样我们仍然有大括号
like in the dictionary at the start and at the end and inside we have values
就像字典中开头的那样在最后和内部我们有价值观
separated by a comma so far all of this is really
用逗号分隔到目前为止，这一切确实是
straightforward the only difference compared to
直截了当唯一的区别是
dictionary is we don't have keys we just have values
字典是我们没有钥匙，我们只是有价值观
where a set becomes unique is that every single value inside of a set has to be
集合变得独特的地方是每个集合内的单个值必须是
unique and any kind of duplicate will be deleted
唯一的并且任何类型的重复都将是已删除
once more i have a completely empty python file and i want to create a
我再一次拥有了一个完全空的python 文件，我想创建一个
variable let's call it my set and here
变量让我们称之为我的集合和这里
i need curly brackets and inside of those i want to have some values i want
我需要大括号和里面那些我想要有一些我想要的价值观
to have separated by commas once i have that i can print this
以逗号分隔一旦我有了，我就可以打印这个
variable run the code and we can see we have some kind of set
变量运行代码，我们可以看到有某种集合
you know it's a set because we have values surrounded by curly brackets
你知道这是一套，因为我们有用大括号括起来的值
without any kind of keys if they had keys it would be a dictionary
没有任何钥匙（如果他们有的话）键这将是一本字典
the one crucial thing you have to understand is that if i have a duplicate
你必须做的一件至关重要的事情我明白的是，如果我有一个重复的
value in here let's say i have two fours if i run this again the second four is
这里的值假设我有两个四如果我再次运行这个，第二个四个是
going to disappear because every value in here has to be unique and python is
将会消失，因为每个值这里必须是唯一的，而 python 是
going to get rid of any value that is duplicated
将摆脱任何价值重复的
let's say duplicate values will be exterminated
假设重复值是消灭的
all right but other than that we can do quite a few normal things with a set for
好吧，但除此之外我们还能做相当多正常的东西，一套
example we could print the len of my set that is not a bracket let's run this now
例如我们可以打印我的集合的长度这不是括号让我们现在运行它
and we know this set has a length of 4 because we have 4 elements inside of it
我们知道这个集合的长度为 4因为我们里面有 4 个元素
because we get rid of the duplicate values what you can also do is to use
因为我们去掉了重复的值你还可以做的是使用
methods and sets do have quite a few one that is fairly popular is you can
方法和集合确实有很多相当受欢迎的一个是你可以
add another value and in here you just add as an argument the value you want to
添加另一个值，在这里你只需添加您想要的值作为参数
add and if you run out of this now we have a 5 added at the end of the set
添加，如果你现在用完了，我们在集合末尾添加 5
along the same lines you can also remove a value
同样，您也可以删除一个值
and let's say i want to remove the 2 in here
假设我想删除 2这里
if i run this now we don't have a 2 in the set anymore
如果我现在运行这个我们的套装中不再有 2
for the full list of all the methods you have available let's use a different
获取所有方法的完整列表有可用的让我们使用不同的
website this time i'm using a website called geeksforgeeks this one is also
网站 这次我使用的是网站叫做 geeksforgeeks 这个也是
quite good for python and i do want you guys to get used to looking at different
对于 python 来说非常好，我确实想要你伙计们要习惯看不同的东西
websites they all do very similar things but slightly different so it is a really
他们都做非常相似的事情的网站但略有不同，所以它确实是
good idea to understand different ones all i really did was i typed python set
理解不同的好主意我真正做的就是输入 python set
methods into google and there we have w3schools we have programmers we have
进入谷歌的方法，我们有w3schools 我们有程序员
geeks for geeks and we have the python documentation
极客归极客，我们有 python文档
these are the four that usually come up in google that tell you all you need to
这是通常出现的四个在谷歌中，它会告诉你所有你需要的
know about specific parts of python in here if you scroll down you have a
了解Python的特定部分在这里，如果你向下滚动，你会看到
whole list of all the methods you could be using
您可以使用的所有方法的完整列表正在使用
the one you have just seen was add and this one adds another value
你刚刚看到的是 add 和这个增加了另一个价值
and in here well you have a lot of different stuff you can work with and
在这里你有很多你可以使用不同的东西
the list really isn't that long it should be fairly easy to work with
这个清单确实没那么长应该很容易使用
now there's one thing
现在有一件事
that is quite limiting for sets and that is that indexing and slicing
这对于集合来说是相当有限的就是索引和切片
does not work
才不是工作
i guess let me put these two print statements at the top and now i want to
我想让我把这两个打印出来顶部的声明，现在我想要
print my set
打印我的一套
and then the one with the index 0. if i run this
进而索引为 0 的那个。如果我运行这个
we are getting an error and the type error we are getting is set object is
我们收到一个错误及其类型我们得到的错误是设置对象是
not subscriptable which is a pythonic way of saying that
不可订阅这是一种Python式的表达方式
you cannot use indexing for a set as a matter of fact there actually isn't a
您不能将集合的索引用作事实上实际上并没有
really easy way to pick one element from a set
从中选择一个元素的非常简单的方法一套
the one that gets closest to it is to use the pop method
最接近它的是使用弹出方法
let me comment this one out and instead i want to have my set and then use the
让我评论一下这个我想要一套，然后使用
pop method
弹出方法
if i run the code now we are getting a 1 or the first item inside of the set
如果我现在运行代码我们会得到 1或集合中的第一项
however what this one is doing if i print this set
但是如果我这个人在做什么打印这套
after this operation the one has now disappeared
此操作后现在已经消失了
the reason being that this pop takes the first item from the set returns it and
原因是这个流行音乐采取了集合中的第一项返回它并且
then removes it from the set if you call this multiple times at some
然后将其从集合中删除如果你在某个时候多次调用这个
point your set is going to run out of items
你的集合即将用完的点项目
which again very often is not what you want to do
这又常常不是你想要的想做
sets are not designed for indexing or generate to pick items from them
集不是为索引或生成以从中挑选项目
the actual use case is something entirely different i'll cover that in a
实际用例是这样的完全不同，我将在
second but first of all we could actually do a really interesting
第二但首先我们可以实际上做了一个非常有趣的事情
exercise just in the middle of this and the exercise i want you guys to try
就在这中间锻炼以及我希望你们尝试的练习
is to use type conversion to get one item from the set by index
就是利用类型转换得到一个按索引设置的项目
basically what that means is you should try to convert this set into another
基本上这意味着你应该尝试将此集合转换为另一个集合
data type and then on this data type get the index
数据类型，然后在此数据类型上获取索引
the main thing i want you guys to take away from this is that you can very
我想让你们做的最重要的事情远离这个就是你可以非常
easily change the data type of something in python and then use different methods
轻松更改某物的数据类型在 python 中，然后使用不同的方法
or different operations so see if you can figure this one out
或不同的操作看看你能不能解决这个问题
we know that we cannot take the index of a set this one just doesn't work
我们知道我们不能采用索引一套这个不行
however what we can do is get the index of a list
然而我们能做什么是获取列表的索引
so what i can do is convert my set to a list and then from this list i want to
所以我能做的就是将我的集合转换为列出，然后从这个列表中我想要
take the index meaning if i run this now this one is
取索引意思是如果我现在运行这个
going to work i get the first index i could get the index at one
去上班我得到第一个索引 i可以获得索引为一
or any other index this is now going to be a list that we can work with
或现在要使用的任何其他索引是我们可以使用的列表
if i remove the indexing and show the entire thing that we are getting is well
如果我删除索引并显示我们得到的一切都很好
it's just a list that came from the set and this is also non-destructible we are
这只是来自集合的列表这也是不可破坏的
just doing this for this one print statement outside of it the set is going
只是为了这一张打印而这样做在它之外的语句集合将要进行
to remain a set we are not changing the entire variable just for this one line
为了保持一套，我们不会改变整个变量仅用于这一行
we are changing the data type for a very specific purpose
我们正在更改数据类型特定用途
which is what you are going to do very often as a programmer
这就是你要做的事情经常作为程序员
meaning this is something you definitely want to get used to
这意味着这绝对是你的事情想要习惯
and that way you would select different values from a set although that really
这样你就会选择不同的一组值，尽管那确实
isn't the idea of a set but i guess let's talk about what the
不是一个集合的想法但我想我们来谈谈
actual purpose of a set is in python and what they are supposed to do is
集合的实际用途是在 python 中他们应该做的是
being used for comparison operators sets are incredibly good at that
用于比较运算符集非常擅长于此
there are a lot of ways to check if two sets have values in common or if they
有很多方法可以检查两个是否集合有共同的值或者如果它们
have different values for example what we could be doing is
有不同的价值观例如我们可以做的是
set one and check if there's a union with a set two and that way we are
设置一个并检查是否存在联合有了第二组，我们就这样
getting all of the shared elements another way we'll be looking at the
获取所有共享元素我们将用另一种方式来看待
intersection between two elements and now we only get the values that are
两个元素之间的交集和现在我们只能得到以下值
present in both data sets there are actually quite a few more
存在于两个数据集中其实还有很多
let's go through a couple of them let me add another comment for another
让我们来看看其中的几个让我为另一个人添加另一个评论
section and let's call this comparison
部分，我们称之为比较
operators and in here to keep things a bit cleaner
运营商在这里让事情变得更干净
i want to have two more sets set one and set two that do share some
我想要多两套设置一和设置二确实共享一些
values and everything else i want to comment
价值观以及我想评论的所有其他内容
out so we are not going to get confused what you can do
这样我们就不会感到困惑你可以做什么
for example the one we have seen already i can print set 1 and then union
例如我们已经见过的那个我可以打印集合 1 然后联合
and set 2. if i run this now
并设置 2。如果我现在运行这个
we essentially merged these two sets i suppose an operation that is a bit
我们基本上合并了这两组我想这个操作有点
easier to see in terms of what's going on is the intersection method
更容易了解正在发生的事情on 是交集法
if i run this one we are now only getting 4 because 4 is the only value
如果我运行这个，我们现在就只剩下得到 4 因为 4 是唯一的值
that is shared with set 1 and set 2. any other value disappears because they
与集合 1 和集合 2 共享。任何其他价值都会消失，因为它们
are not shared by the two sets a really good way to think about it is
不被两个集合共享一个非常好的思考方式是
to use venn diagrams this one is set one this one is set to and let me draw two
使用维恩图，将其设置为一这个设置为让我画两个
circles and set two would be the other circle
界第二组是另一个圆圈
what intersection is doing this one here is it only finds the shared values
这里有哪个路口在做这个它只找到共同的价值观吗
between the two union
两者之间联盟
got all
得到全部
of the values and the third operation we could go we
的价值观我们可以进行第三次手术
can have set one and the one here is difference again i want
可以设置一个并且我想要的又是不同的
to check with set two and this looks like a typo difference this fits better
检查第二组，这看起来就像拼写错误一样，这个更适合
let's run this now and there we go now we only get the values one two and
现在就运行这个吧现在我们只能得到值一二
three these three here
三这三个在这里
we are getting this area here now where we only get the values that are not
我们现在正在这里找到这个区域我们只得到不存在的值
present in set 2 which specifically here means that 4 is
出现在第 2 组中这里具体意味着 4 是
disappearing and those are the main comparison operators that being said
消失，这些是主要的所说的比较运算符
there are a few more there's a different way to use these
还有一些有一种不同的方式来使用这些
methods and those are going to look slightly
方法这些看起来会有点
weird for the union instead of writing union
对于工会来说很奇怪而不是写作联盟
we could do set one then i think this is called a pipe
我们可以做一套那么我认为这叫做管道
operator and then set two
操作员然后设置两个
let me comment out the other two lines so we're not getting confused if i run
让我注释掉另外两行所以如果我跑步我们不会感到困惑
this now we get the exact same outcome along the same lines in this section
现在我们得到了完全相同的结果在本节中沿着同样的思路
we could replace with the and character so set one and set
我们可以用 和 字符替换所以设置一个并设置
two if i run these two i am getting four we
二如果我运行这两个，我会得到四个
are only getting the values shared by both sets
只获得共享的值两套
and finally difference
最后不同之处
we could access with set one minus set two and if i run this
我们可以使用设置一访问减去设置二，如果我运行这个
we are again getting the same values this one may look weird but it actually
我们再次得到相同的值这个可能看起来很奇怪但实际上
makes a lot of sense we are basically taking set one and we are subtracting
这很有意义，我们基本上是取第一组，我们减去
all of the values from set 2. if they exist they are going to remove
第 2 组中的所有值。如果它们存在，他们将删除
the value for in this case if they don't we're just going to ignore them
在这种情况下的价值，如果他们不这样做我们只会忽略他们
now that being said these operators or sets in general
话虽这么说这些运算符或集合通常
you are not going to see all that often they are very rarely used
你不会经常看到这些它们很少被使用
list tuples and dictionaries are the really common one and sets you only
列表元组和字典是非常普通的一个并且只设置你
really use when you do some more data oriented stuff
当你做更多数据时真正有用定向的东西
all right now with that we are nearly done i just want you guys to do an
好吧，现在我们已经差不多了完成了，我只是想让你们做一个
exercise and for the exercise i have a long list
锻炼对于这个练习，我有一个很长的清单
i'm not even sure how many numbers are in here but there are a lot
我什至不确定有多少个数字在这里但是有很多
and what i want you guys to do is to use a set to figure out if this list has
我希望你们做的是使用一个集合来判断这个列表是否有
duplicate values try to figure this one out yourself it's a really common
重复值尝试找出这个
operation that is incredibly useful
i have added a comment to explain what the exercise is going to be but it
actually isn't all that difficult the function you want to use here is len
and right now if i pass the list in here i know we have 34 items in there in
total let me comment out the earlier stuff so
we're not getting confused we have 34 items inside of this list how we can use
this is we know
if we are creating a set so i want to create a set from this test
list since a set cannot have any duplicate
values if the length of this set is shorter
than the length of this original list then we know there are going to be
duplicates inside of this list which means
if i run the lan method on this
run both we are getting 26
which means we have quite a few duplicate values in the original list
if you want to do this a bit more fancy you could also do i guess let me put
this on a separate line you could print len of the test list then the comparison
operator i don't think we have seen this one yet but this checks if two values
are equal to each other and then
we have len of the set of the test list and if i run this now we are getting
false and if this is false we know there are duplicate values
with that we have all the important stuff for a set
although keep in mind sets are fairly rare in python you would only really use
them when you run something that requires a lot of data work like running
a database or doing data analysis for anything else like making a gui or
making games they really aren't used that often
so don't worry too much about them for now when you actually need them you can
learn about them in more detail the next incredibly important data type
is a boolean all a boolean is is either true or false
and usually we are creating booleans with comparison operators
for example if we are running something like 5
smaller than 10 we are getting the boolean value true
and this is incredibly useful to control the flow of our code something we are
going to talk about a lot in the next section for example if a condition is
true then you want to do something and booleans can be created in a lot of
different ways the one way we have seen already is
we're using either integers or floats and then we use comparison operators
we can also use some string methods like is num
to check if there's a number inside of a string i think we have seen is alpha
to check if there are only letters inside of a string
another way is we can check if there are values inside of a list instead of
tuples or a set or a dictionary this would also work
we could also compare different sets to create booleans and finally we can also
create booleans by themselves although that's something you really aren't going
to do too often i guess let's go through this entire
list and we're going to start with comparison operators and there are quite
a few the one we have just used in the last part is the equal sign so we are
checking if two values are equal with two equal signs and we are using two
because a single equal sign is reserved to assign a data type to a variable
meaning we couldn't use it and to check if two numbers are not
equal we have the exclamation mark equal and that checks if two numbers are
different and finally we have smaller or smaller
equal to check if something is smaller than or smaller or equal than and
greater and greater equal would work in the same way
those are the main comparison operators in my code let me start by printing and
i want to print if 1 is equal to 1. if i run this we are getting true
if i use a different number let's say 10 run out of this again i am getting false
because 1 is different from 10 this should be quite
obvious the next operator would be
exclamation mark equal and let me add comments
is not equal whereas the double equal sign
looks for is equal if i run those two we get false and true
false here because those two are not equal and we get true from this
operation because they are indeed different
i suppose a better way of writing the comment here would be true
if is equal or is not equal
or besides not equal is different we can also print if 1 is smaller than
10 and this one gives us the obvious result
because 1 is indeed smaller than 10 and we could also use smaller or equal
than and this one in this case would also be true
i guess where this one matters if we have a 10
smaller equal here is going to be true but 10 is not going to be smaller than
10 meaning this operation would return false
this also works with greater than again this would be false because 10 is
not greater than 10. and those are all the major comparison operators for
integers for the next part we could look at lists
and booleans and in here we can check if a value is in a list or if a value is
not in the list and this by the way also works with
strings an important point here is that not
reverses a boolean if we have not false it is going to be
true if we have not true it is going to be false
python here works very similar compared to what you would use in a sentence
and i am trying to be better with comments
let's do this booleans and numbers i think it's a good name here
next up we have booleans and lists and strings
what you could do for example here is you could check if one is in the list
one two and three if i run this we're getting true because
one is indeed in the list of one two and three
let me comment out this part here so we're not getting confused and run this
again now we are only getting true and this is also going to work with
different data types if i for example had a tuple
and run this again we would have the very same outcome if i duplicate all of
this i can also check if e is in the word hello
and run this again and we will be getting true again because e is indeed
in the word hello finally what you can also do is to use
the not operator for example you could be checking if 4
is not in the list of 1 2 and 3.
if i run this one now we're getting true again because 4 is indeed not in this
list generally not reverses all of these
operations i could for example uncomment
this print 10 is greater than 10 and this one
let me keep it the only one without a comment
if i just had this one line by default this one is going to be false
but if i put a not in front of it and run this again we are now getting
true not reverses any kind of boolean so if
you have not true you are going to get false you can actually do this by itself
let me add another comment and let's call it booleans by themselves
and comment out everything else what you could do
you could just create a boolean by just writing true
or false if you wanted to and this one would get you true which is its own data
type and if you write not true you would get false this i think is
going to make sense and i guess while we are here
we can do another data conversion exercise
so data conversion exercise
and what i want you guys to do here are the notes i have an e
and this one contains three key value pairs
it's always the integer of a number and then the word of the number as well
although honestly it really doesn't matter what the specific value here is
and i want you guys to do two things number one check if one of these keys
exists specifically if this key one exists just assume you don't know what's
inside of the dictionary and you want to check if this key exists in the first
place and number two i want you guys to check
if the value not the key the value for exists inside of the dictionary and
again assume you don't know the actual content of the dictionary
so try to figure out these two problems
the first problem i guess let me put it right below is the easier one
we want to check for a specific key and in here we can use the same thing we
have used up here it works in the same way i can just check if one exists
inside of the e-dictionary and let me comment out
this print statement down here so we're not getting confused if i run this now
we're getting true because we can see it right here
this one does exist inside of the dictionary as a key
if you want to be more specific about it you could also use the method dot keys
and you would get the same result this edict.keys would now return
something that looks like a list with only the keys inside of it
although this is what you get by default anyway so you don't really have to use
it the second part
is we want to check if the value 4 is in the e dictionary
although this right now is not going to work because this edict is checking for
keys not for values which wouldn't help us all that much
to access the values we would need the values method the one we learned about
earlier and now we're getting something that is basically a list and it only
contains all of the values of the dictionary
if i run this now we're getting false because we know this 4 does not exist as
a value inside of this e dictionary although if we had a 3
this one would be true so we know it is working all right with
that there's one more really important topic
i want to cover and that is the bool function let's talk about this one bool
is a function that creates a boolean data type and this one can accept
basically any kind of other data type it's really flexible here we could pass
a number a string any type of container and we would still get a value
as a matter of fact bool accepts so many different values
that are actually different rules that determine how the values are going to be
converted and just think about the problem here
you have some really complex data set let's say a really long word and you
pass this into the boolean function to ever get true or false
how is python going to determine what values count is true and what values
count as false and the logic here is actually so common that python has
dedicated words for it we have the words truthy and fault c
truffy means all the values that will be converted to true and false c is all the
values that will be converted to false the way you have to think about it is
that some values will always be converted to false and those are fairly
specific and anything else will always be true
and faulty values are 0 or 0.0 so integers or floats that have
the value 0 any positive or negative number will become true
any kind of empty string so a string without any content not even a space
any kind of empty list tuple set or dictionary is also going to become false
and finally none so the absence of a value
and literally any other value is going to become true
meaning you don't actually have to learn that much
now this is something we definitely want to play around with so let's have a look
at all of this in code let me comment out all of the stuff we have written
earlier so things are not getting confusing
right the bull function
is another function that creates a boolean data type and i do want to print
the result we could for example add in a number any
kind of number and we will get true
what python basically does is it looks at a number and then determines if the
value is truthy or falsey if it is truthy we get true if it is falsy we're
getting false and what i talked about just now is that
any number besides zero will be true this one here indeed has become true
this would also work with negative numbers let's say negative one
is also true the only time a number becomes false is
when you have zero this one is false or 0.0 this one is also false as soon as
you have any other value besides zero let's say zero point a lot of zeros and
one you are getting true again
but if you have any floating point with just zeros it is going to be false
and this was the first rule besides that for strings
if you have any kind of word even if it's just a space
it is going to be true however
if you have an empty string this one is going to be false
finally if you have an empty list
this one is also going to be false but if you have any kind of value inside it
is going to be true the way you want to think about it is that if any kind of
data type has an actual value then it is going to be converted to true if it
doesn't have any content it is going to be false
there's one more data type we haven't really covered yet in detail and that is
the absence of a value so none and this by itself is also data type in
python and this one obviously is also going to
become false i think this one makes sense
we are actually going to talk about this in just a second in a bit more detail
but it's not something you have to worry about too much
but well with that we have boolean data types that's kind of all you need to
know and in the next section we are going to use this a lot more
before we are finishing off this entire section i want to cover some other data
types because python does have a lot what we have seen so far is that python
is really flexible with data types sometimes data is even converted
automatically like with integers and floating point numbers
but other than that we also have functions to change data types
and this is the entire list for the major data types you would most of the
time actually need and these are very forgiving python here
again is super flexible now besides those we do have a couple of
data types you see once in a while but not very often or in other words data
types you don't specifically use the most common one here is none or the
absence of a value this could for example happen if a
certain kind of value got deleted or if you didn't get value from some kind of
input field but besides that we also have a sequence
like a range of numbers bytes complex numbers memory view frozen
sets lots of really specific data types that
you sometimes see in very specific circumstances
you usually have to look them up and they are very rare so i am not going to
cover them i will however cover later on none and
sequence those you do see reasonably often
but values like bytes complex numbers memory view frozen sets
you would only ever use in highly specific circumstances and i'm not going
to cover them because we don't really need them
almost the entire time you are going to be perfectly happy with
these data types here and they are what i am
going to focus on so right with that we can come to the
next major section and welcome back in this section we are
going to work with the flow of our code now what does that mean
basically so far we always executed code from the start to the finish meaning if
these are different lines of code we are starting all the way at the top
and we are going down line by line which works fine by itself but it is
fairly limiting because sometimes we want to do
something else for example we might only want to run
code if a certain condition is true or we might want to run code multiple times
or we might want to run code for every item inside of a list or a tuple or
something like that and all of these things can be done
quite easily python has a lot of ways to control the
flow of your code although to understand how it is going
to work we need to understand one really important concept
and that is how python groups chunks of code together
you're going to see in a second why that is important but the way python groups
code together is by using indentation let's say we only want to run some code
if the condition is true and this white line here is the left
side of our code editor just to better illustrate how we are using indentation
the basic problem we have now is if we have code below this condition
how do we tell python that it belongs to the condition and isn't something that's
independent of the condition for that we need indentation anything
that is indented by one indentation after this line belongs to this if
condition meaning these three lines here all belong to this if condition i think
i actually added a bit more text here yeah there we go indentation determines
where the code belongs to if we added some other code in here like
line three and line four those would be independent of each other
they would run no matter what happens whereas
line 1 line 2 and line 3 would only run if this condition is true if it was
false then none of this would be run but line
4 and line 5 would still run meaning lines that are not indented do
not belong to that if statement i hope this makes sense once you
understand the system it makes a lot of sense
and indentations indentations in general and python are incredibly important you
are going to see them all the time but first of all
once we understand indentation there are four major ways to determine the flow of
the code the first one is if l if and else these are different kind of if
conditions to run code if certain conditions are true
we are going to talk about this one in the next part besides that we have match
this one is kind of like if but it's more designed for specific value to find
one very specific condition then we have while and this one just
repeats code as long as the certain condition is true
and finally we have four and this one is about
running some code for every item inside of a container let's say you have a list
with one two and three
and you want to run some code for every item inside of the list a for loop for
that would be perfect and those are the four major concepts
that we are going to learn there are also a few more extra tools you can use
like breaking a certain kind of statement or skipping to a next part in
a while loop i will talk about those at the
appropriate point so i guess with that let's start with
the first major part possibly the most important concept to
determine the flow of your code is the if statement all this one does is it
tells python to only run some code if a certain condition is true
note here we are always looking for a boolean value
they are crucial to make all of this work
and an if statement can also be extended with l if and else
and you can also add different conditions together we're gonna cover
all of this in quite a bit more detail over the next two videos
let's have a look at all of this in code let's do a super quick recap of boolean
values all i really do is if i have something like 10 is greater than 5 i
print it i'm getting true because this condition is indeed true
and if i do the other way around that 10 is smaller than 5 this would get me
false because this condition is not correct
and these boolean values we can now use to control the flow of our code for
example we could run some code if a value in a variable
is greater than let's say 10. for that let me first of all create a variable
let me call it x and let's start with five
and now i want to run some code only if this value is greater than 10.
and for that i would need the word if and then the condition i want to check
which in my case is x is greater than 10.
after that i need a colon and now if i press enter
sublime is very intelligent here and already creates one level of indentation
so we are here if i write some code and this is really important
let me write some code here actually let's say print
the if statement was true
because of this indentation we know that this print statement belongs
to this if statement here if i execute all of this we can see nothing the
reason why we can't see anything is that this condition here was not true
5 is not greater than 10 but if i change this 5 to a 15
run all of this again now we can see
this print statement here the main thing that you have to
understand here is this condition if it becomes true
then we are running all the indented parts below the if statement and if it
is false we're not running any of the indented parts
this would also work over multiple lines of code i could for example print
another line if i run this again we get another line
as well i could also create another variable in here let me call it y is
equal to 10 and i could print
y all of this works just fine we can write any kind of code in here as long
as it's indented it always belongs to this if statement
however if i write now
some other line of code after the if statement that is not indented
let me call it some other code this one
is always going to run regardless of what the if statement does because it's
not indented if i run the entire code right now we
can see some other code the line we get here and if i
return x back to 5 run this again we now can still see some other code
because this line is not affected by the if statement because again of the
indentation indentation is really important to python you absolutely have
to understand it although that being said this is the
core part of an if statement it really isn't that complex
although you can extend the logic here in two different ways a very easy one
would be an else statement this one again is going to need a colon
and now if i press enter again we have another indentation and in here i can
write the code
that was run if
the statement was false
how does this work basically
this else statement always has to be connected to an if statement
and what it does is if this condition here is false then we are not running
any of this but we are running anything inside of the else statement
since x is 5 this condition is going to be false meaning none of this will run
but this one here should be run and this line is going to run no matter
what happens so if i run the code i should be seeing the output of this line
and of this line let's try it
and there indeed we can see these two lines
and there's one more thing that you can do
and that is called an l if statement
and again this elf statement has to be connected to an if statement
basically what it means is shorthand for else if
it's kind of similar to the else statement except now we are adding a
condition which means if this condition here
is false then we want to run
this statement here but we only want to run this one if another condition is
true and this condition is just going to be
another boolean value let's say i want to check x again
and i want to check if x is different from 0.
if that is the case i once more need some indented code
and for this one let me print the l if statement was
correct and now we have a much more complex if
statement we first check if this condition here is true
which in our case right now is going to be false because 5 is smaller than 10
meaning this would be a false statement then we are coming to the al if
statement and now we are checking if let me use a different color if x is
different from zero and since five is different from zero this one is going to
be true as a consequence we are going to run or
expect this code here to be run let me add it properly here so we can see
what's inside of the line and once any of these lf statement has
run we are stopping this if statement meaning this else statement here would
not be run at all and once again this print statement here
is going to be happy either way because it does not care what happens in this
entire thing let's try all of this now and we can see
the al if statement was correct which is this line here and then we have some
other code this bit here i suppose we could be doing another example and now
let me add a zero in here and i would really recommend you to go over this one
yourself and see which line
you would expect to run here once again we are starting at the first
line and we know 0 greater than 10 is going to be false that can never be true
next up we are looking at x being different from 0 which in this case is
also going to be false which means at the end we are left with
this else statement which means the code we are expecting is
the code that was run in the if statement was false
and we're also expecting this one at the end although that's getting repetitive
let me run the code now and we get the code that was run if the
if statement was false and some other code
with that we have all the basics for an if statement if you understand if l if
and else you already understand what you need
i guess one more thing that i haven't covered yet
is if and else can only occur once inside of this if
statement but l if you can multiply as many times as you
want for example i could add x is greater
than negative 20 for example and then add something else i know print
something else
and you could add as many if statements as you want or as you need
but else and if can only occur once although what you could be doing is add
another if statement afterwards i guess we could add if
one in the list one two and three and then we want to print
another if statement when i said an if statement or an else
statement can only occur once i was always referring to this
block here where we are starting with an if and
inside of that we can only have one else we couldn't have a second else however
python is totally happy to have a completely separate if statement
but with that we can do an exercise and what i want you guys to do is this
one here we have one variable that determines how
much money we have and from this amount of money i want you
guys to figure out what we are going to eat
if we have greater or equal than 80 units of money i want you guys to print
eat something fancy if the money is greater than 45 eat
something nice if it is greater than 15 eat something okay
and else eat something cheap and obviously there should only ever be
one print statement running at any point in time
so pause the video now and try this one yourself
before we start i want to comment out all of this because it would otherwise
get kind of confusing first of all we need an if statement and now i want
to check the money available and i want to work on the first line
here and what we are being asked to do is
greater or equal than 80 which we get with greater or equal and
we want to check for 80. if you want a reminder on boolean values check out the
last section on boolean data types this is going to be really important for this
entire section but in here i now need a colon and now i
want to print eat something fancy i guess let's add an exclamation mark
because why not the really important part here this
print statement has to be indented but with that we have covered the first
line of the exercise next up we want to check if the money is
greater than 45 which means we want to first check if
the money is greater than 80 but if that is not the case and the money is still
greater than 45 we want to do something else which means we need an l if
statement else because we want something else in the if
statement and if because we have another condition
what i want to check in here if the money available is greater than 45 after
that again i need a colon i need an indented line and now i want
to print eat something nice
and with that we have covered this line here
next up we have a very similar line meaning now we again need l if
and what i want to check now if the money available is greater than 15.
if that is the case this is getting a bit repetitive i want to print it
something okay
that covers this line and finally we have an else statement
that if all of these conditions are false we want to do something else
anything else we want to do is to print eat something cheap
and there we go this is going to cover all of the four if statements if i run
this now we get each something fancy because the first if statement
this one here is true
however if i change this 100 to let's say 50
we get eat something nice if i change it to 20
we get eat something okay and if i change it to 5
we get eat something cheap and with that we have basic if
statements now that we have learned about basic if
statements we can work on the more complex ones because if statements can
be extended number one is you can combine different
conditions inside of one if statement on the same line
and number two is you can nest one if statement inside of another if statement
which lets you create really complex systems that check different values
let's start with combining conditions and in here the two keywords we need are
and and or kind of confusing to say but you get the
idea how this would look like is we have if 5
is smaller than 1 and e in hello or 10 is different from 4.
this may look confusing but let's go through it one by one to
understand how this works we have to understand and and or
and means that all the parts have to be true
meaning when we are talking about this and here
this bit in particular both of these conditions five is more
than one and e and hello have to be true individually
for this entire statement here to return true as a whole whereas or works in the
opposite way where only one or a statement has to be true which means if
this or statement here is true then it wouldn't matter if all of this is false
because as long as one or statement is true
then the entire if statement is going to return true as a whole
and this is probably going to sound very confusing so let's do this a bit more
practically let's do this actually in the simplest
possible way let's say i have if true and i want to print
true this if statement here
really doesn't make too much sense but to illustrate the point it's really
useful but since we're adding the boolean value
true in this if statement this is always going to run meaning if i execute the
code we are getting true and now what we can do is use and in here and if i add
false now and run this again nothing is going to happen this line
will not be executed because of and both the first one this one here and the
second one have to be true for this entire condition to be true as a whole
which there aren't right now but if it was true
then this would run again the way you have to think about and is
i'm only going to run this if statement if this is true and this is true and
anything else is true and if any single statement is false then the entire thing
is not going to be run i hope that makes sense it does take
some time to get used to it let me go back to false
and the other word we can use is or now we want to run this line of code if this
is true or this is true meaning if either of these is true then the entire
if statement is going to run if i run this now this is going to be true
because for or only one of them has to be true
and once you get so far you can combine and and or for example what i can do is
true and true and true or true now this
would obviously return true as a whole because we only have true values in here
but now if i set this to false this would still run
and the reason is let me add a bit of white space around it so i have more
space to draw on i am assuming that this is kind of confusing right now still
python essentially combines all of the n statements into one block inside of the
if statement and this entire block can either be true or false
for and every single value has to be true and if a single value is false then
the entire thing is going to be false in our case since there is one fault
statement the entire block here is going to be
false once we have that python is looking at
the or statement this bit here and as a consequence of this we now have false
from all of the and statements and then we are checking false or true and if
either of these are true then the entire if statement is going to be true which
in this case it is just to make sure let's do one exercise
for this one already and what i want you guys to do
is here we have three variables and the exercise is going to be fairly similar
compared to what we have done in the last video
what you should be working on is another if statement that checks if
the money available is greater than 80 and if you are hungry if those two
conditions are true print eat something fancy or whatever you want however this
should also run if board is true and for that to work you have to combine
end and or statements so pause the video now and try to figure this one out
to get started i need an if statement once again and now i want to check if
money available is greater than 80.
this covers this first bit on top of that i also want to check the
end if hungry
is equal to true
with that i have covered this entire bit now that i have that
i can print eat something
fancy if i run this now
this is going to return eat something fancy let me comment out this stuff at
the top so we're not getting confused eat something fancy
if i change hungry to false run this again we are not getting
anything the simple reason being
that both of these statements have to be true
because of the end statement here if either of these is
false then the entire thing is going to return
false which it does right now so none of this
is going to be run however now what we can do
is use an or statement as well to cover the last bit or if bored
and now i want to check our board equals to true as well
if we run all of this now we get eat something fancy and what
happened here is python first checks the two statements connected by and
and it sees that money available is 100 which indeed is greater than 80 meaning
this part here is going to be true but then for hungary equals true it
looks at the hungry variable and this one is false
meaning this one is going to return false
as a consequence the entire bit here
is going to give us a big false the difference now is we are also
checking this or statement which means we want to check if anything in here is
true or if this condition is true which it
actually is right now and as a consequence
the entire thing combined is going to return
true consequence being we are going to run this line of code
and i hope this makes sense using these and or keywords can be a bit confusing
definitely play around with this in your own time if you're struggling
that being said most of the time you are going to keep this fairly simple
you usually only have a single and statement in here and then you are good
to go don't overthink this
the other way to make if statements more complex is by nesting them
and let me do an example we could have an if statement if a is
inside of the list a and b right now this one would be true but
inside of this we can add another if statement that is indented by one line
and inside of that we could even add another if statement and this system we
could continue forever as long as we keep on adding more indentation levels
let's have a look at this one in a bit more detail
i'm going to comment out the stuff we have done earlier i guess i could
organize it a tiny bit better there we go
and now i will look at nested if statements
and to keep comments a bit more consistent let me add one for the first
part let's call it combining conditions
the example we have just seen is we want to check if the letter a
is in the list a and
b if that is the case
i let's say i want to print a is in
the list executing the code is going to print
this line this one should be fairly straightforward
and again remember we are on one level of indentation on this line of
indentation though we could add another if statement
we could for example check if
a and then use the method
then i need a colon again and now i need another indentation line or another
level of indentation and then here let me print
it is a letter
if i run this now i get a is in the list and it is a
letter now this example really doesn't make too
much sense but we can make it quite a bit more interesting for example what
you could be doing is create a variable and in this right now i want to have
let's say the string a and now i want to check if x is inside
of this list and i want to check x is alpha
if i run this again we are going to get the same result we essentially just
replaced the string a with a variable that contains the same string
but once we have that i could add another string in here that contains a 1
which is not in the alphabet so if i check this one here what i
expect now to happen is that this is still going to be inside of the list so
this entire condition should be true as a consequence this print statement
should run however
the number one even if it's inside of a string is not
in the alphabet so this condition should not be true
and if i run this we can indeed only see this line here was run but this was
false and as a consequence this line here was not executed
if you wanted to you could even add another level of indentation
i don't know let me just add true so we always execute it and inside of that you
could keep on adding more if statements there's absolutely no limitation on how
many if statements you can add the only thing you really have to consider here
is that each if statement has to be on a separate level of indentation
at the very least if you want them to be part of the other if statement
if you added an if statement here
let me get rid of this one you would check those two individually
the way you want to think about it is that each if statement is one block of
code this if statement here is one block inside of this if statement we have one
block for this if statement and another block for this if statement
and these two here are independent of each other but they both depend on this
if statement to run if this if statement does not run neither of those will run
just to have something in here let me print
something and let me add some purple white space
so this looks a bit cleaner all right with that we can do another exercise and
then finish this part what i want you guys to do let me copy
it from up here i want you guys to check these three
conditions but now instead of using this system here
i want you guys to create a nested if statement
and if all three conditions are true so you have enough money you are hungry and
you are bored then i want you guys to print eat
something fancy or really whatever you want it doesn't matter that much
let me actually uncomment them and add a comment for the exercise and now pause
the video and do this one yourself
let's start with money available is greater than 80. that's the one we have
already used and
i guess while we are here i can also print something to check on what if
statement we are for this one i want to print i have
enough money
after that i want to check the next if statement
and i just want to check if hungary is equal to true
and if that the case i can print and i am hungry
inside of that i want to check if board is equal to
true and if that the case i want to print the final thing eat
something fancy
before i run it i do want to comment out this part here so we keep things a bit
cleaner if i run this now we only get up to i have enough money this line here
we are not getting to if hungry because hungry is false
if i said this hungry too true we get let me expand this a tiny bit
i have enough money i am hungry and eat something fancy all three
conditions here are true and with that we have if statements
obviously you could also add else statements in here if you really wanted
to and make this even more complex now there's one more thing that i want
to cover really quick writing something like this is a bit
redundant all you really need
is hungry by itself if i run this it would still work
what happens here is that python looks at the hungry variable and the
value for hungry is true meaning this if statement here is essentially if true
and keeping like this is much more readable
if a value is truthy you could just add it in here and then python would take
care of the rest for you but being more explicit about it would
also still work perfectly fine but alright with that we have if statements
covered in this part we're going to cover the match case statement
and this one is kind of similar to an if statement the major difference is
you still run some code if a certain condition is true
but match case is more designed to check for one specific value out of a long
list of possible values that probably doesn't mean too much
let's do an example let's say you want to check the mood of
something if you used an if statement it might look something like this we have
if hungry you want to run some code and else if you're tired or bored you want
to run some other code all of this would be just fine but it
also feels kind of inefficient having one l if statement for each mood seems
kind of annoying to write every single time
and as a consequence python has a slightly different way to approach this
kind of case and this is a match case you would use the match keyboard and
then you would look at the variable in this case i am looking at the mood
and then you can specify different kinds of cases for example case for hungary
and if that is the case we have colons again and we are running some code
inside of it and then we can check for different cases and run some code for
all the different possibilities it is very very similar to an if
statement if you compare the two
match case is actually a tiny bit longer if that makes a difference to you
although the main thing you want to look at here is readability
all of these l if statements here eventually get kind of annoying to read
whereas case this case that gets much better and is a much easier way to check
the value of this mood both approaches here would be perfectly
fine though as a matter of fact
match case is a reasonably recent addition to python
which is the reason why very few people actually use it
most of the time you are going to see some kind of if statement which is still
perfectly fine but in some cases match is the more appropriate way to go on
but well let's have a look at all of this in code
once again i have a completely empty python file and i want to create a new
variable let's call it mood and right now my mood is going to be
hungry if that is the case i want to run some
code what we have seen so far you could use
an if statement if mood is equal to hungry
then let me print
get some food or something like that running this
will get me indeed get some food this one is working just as intended
the difference now is if we have lots of options here for our mood we could be
hungry bored thirsty tired and whatever else you want
for each of these conditions we would have to add
another l if statement to check for all of the
possibilities which does eventually get kind of
cumbersome to write and because of that we have
match and then we want to look at the variable
mood in my case now you need a colon
and if i press enter we are again indented by one line
and now i have to specify a case that could be one scenario for this mood
for example the case could be hungry if i add a color now
and press enter we are once again on a separate line and now i can print
get some food
if i run all of this we are again back to get some food this
result here is basically a simple if statement the
difference now is that we can specify other cases for example a case first d
and then let me copy this one get some water
i could specify a case for
tired and continue like this forever there
really isn't any limitation how many cases you can have let me just write it
out get some sleep with that established i can now change
the variable and get different outcomes i suppose there's one more thing that
you could include here and that would be case
underscore still needs a colon and now you can
print in here any other mood
because an underscore is run when none of the other cases are correct for
example right now if i write in here something like
board a case we haven't accounted for yet
if i run this we get any other mood if python doesn't find any of these it
is going to run the underscore one and with that we have match case covered
and i am fully aware this is about as efficient as an if-else statement it
really isn't that much of a difference match case really is not something you
absolutely have to use if you want to stick to if else statements this would
also be perfectly fine but all right let's do an
exercise what i want you guys to do is this one here
create a variable with an integer between 1 and 5 and this should be a
great a grade you could be getting at school
and then create a match case statement for all of the values that this grade
could have one would be very good and five would be
very bad and print something like this for each of these cases
and i mean all of them from one to five also don't forget to include some
default behavior if you get the value you didn't expect like a 10 for example
pause the video now and try this one yourself
let's get started and i want to comment out all of this
and then we can start by creating the great
variable and let's start with number one i want to start by writing my match and
what i want to look for is the great variable
then i need a double colon and now on an indented line i want to check for one
case and the case right now could be a one
now i need a colon again and once again on an indented line
i want to print very good i can now run this and we get
very good indeed with that we have one case now we can do
case 2 print let's say
still good case 3 would be print
ok case 4
would then be print needs improvement and finally case five
i want to print very
bad i think i said yeah very bad up here and this would already be a working
match case statement i can run this again we get very good the same we had
earlier let's say if i use a 3 we get ok and if
i use 5 we get very bad the one thing we haven't done yet is if
i have a 7 a value we don't have accounted for nothing is running in here
i guess i haven't specifically mentioned that but if the match case doesn't find
a value it just doesn't run we do not get an error message just keep
that in mind it's a specific behavior of it
all right but i want to add case underscore for all the other values i
haven't accounted for and for this one i can print let's say
great not recognized
if i run this now we get great not recognized
this would also work with i don't know something else python
doesn't really care what the value here is
all right with that we have match case something fairly similar to an if else
statement but it could be useful in very specific scenarios
a really important concept in python is the while loop and this one is actually
quite simple all it does is it repeats some code as long as the condition is
true for example this could look like while
true i want to print an infinite loop this infinite loop here
would run forever unless we manually break the code
not exactly the most realistic scenario but something we could be doing
i suppose something slightly more realistic would be something like this
we are starting with x being 0. then we are checking
if x keeps on being smaller than 10 and
inside of this while loop we want to print a certain thing and we are also
going to increase the value of x on this line here this condition now is only
going to run 10 times and this is how often we are going to
print this loop here and with that we have some basic theory
out of the way let's actually have a look at all of this in code
i guess we can start with the examples i just talked about
we always start with the while keyword once we have that we need some kind of
boolean statement this could either be true
or false although if you have false this while loop is not going to run it will
only run if the value is true if that is the case in here you can print i think i
called it infinite loop if i run this now we get
an infinite loop that keeps on running forever
it's not particularly exciting but it definitely does work the way you would
exit this one is by just pressing escape and it would stop although you really
want to be careful with while loops it can
not crash your code but it can make your code not work anymore
let's say if you have some kind of game and you end up in a while loop that you
can't escape from anymore your game might just stop because your computer is
stuck in this while loop and it doesn't continue from it
let me get rid of this one and let's do something a bit more reasonable instead
i want to create a variable x and by default this one is going to be 0.
and now i want to check while x is smaller than
i want to print x
look at this code if i run it what do you think is going to happen
what we get is if i run this we have a whole bunch of zeros that keep on
running forever and the reason here should be fairly
clear this boolean condition x smaller than 10
is always going to be true because x is always zero and we are never changing it
the consequence being that this print statement is going to run forever it is
never going to stop
to overcome that we would have to do something like x plus equals 1.
and now if i run this we get the values from 0 to 9.
i suppose what you could also be doing is combine this with an if statement for
example if x is equal to 5 and this has to be indented really important to tell
python that this if belongs to this while loop here
but once we have that i want to colon again and on another level of
indentation i want to print x is 5.
if i run this now we get the values from 1 to 9 and at the
value 5 we have x is 5. and this way you can repeat code quite easily that being
said there are two ways to make all of this a bit more complex let's talk about
it you can break an entire while loop and
you can also skip one iteration of the while loop and let's do this by example
this is a bit difficult to explain here's the example i've shown you
earlier and this one would just print the word loop 10 times on the screen
but what you can do let's say with one if statement
you could for example add the break keyword and just a keyword
no brackets just break and if you write this
the entire while loop is going to end whenever x is equal to 5
you would never get to this 10 here at the end
besides that you also have continue continue doesn't
break the while loop instead it just skips to the next iteration of the while
loop meaning in this case if x is 5
this print down here would be skipped over because after
continuing this line here we would go back to the while loop and then continue
with the next iteration i think i added a bit more text here
there we go so break ends an entire while loop while
continue skips to the next iteration of the while loop and that's basically all
you have to understand about it let's play around with it
i already have an if statement inside of the while loop and this one i want to
use let's start with the break keyword and you can already tell sublime is
coloring it differently so we know that it has some kind of special
functionality if i run the code now
we get only the numbers from 0 to 4 and this happens because of this break
here it ends the entire while loop as soon as xs5
the other keyboard we have seen is continue
and this one right now is not going to work
and maybe you can figure out why let me run it actually in this case we are
getting all of the numbers and try to think of why we didn't skip over one of
them after we are running continue we are
skipping the rest of the current while loop in our case though we don't have
anything after continue continue is on the last line of this while loop
which means it doesn't actually do anything
we could change this though by putting the print statement after continue
and let me add a bit more white space here this looks a bit cleaner
if i run this now we would expect this print statement to be skipped if x is
equal 5 meaning we shouldn't see 5 in the output
let's try it and indeed after 4 we skip straight to 6. we do not
have 5 because of this continue here
and with that we have a while loop let's do an exercise and then we are
done that is horrible spelling there we go
what i want you guys to do is to use a while loop to create a list with only
even values from 0 to 100 i guess as a tip here create an empty
list first and then from the while loop append more values
i haven't covered yet how to only get even or odd values
maybe try to do some research it should be fairly doable but let's see if you
can figure this one out
i guess this one was a slightly more challenging exercise but let's try it
together i first need some kind of list let me call it my list and this is just
empty brackets for an empty list and there's one more thing that i am going
to need and that is some kind of counter by default i want to set this one to
zero this is what we are going to use to
control the while loop like the x we have used up here
actually let me comment out this earlier stuff so we are not getting confused
what i want to do with that is run my while loop again
with counter is smaller or equal than 100
because this is the maximum number we want to go to and we are starting from
zero which is the value here and let's start by adding every single
value to the list for that we need my list
append and then the counter once we have that i can just print
my list and let's see what we get and we are getting nothing
the reason here look at this again
i have actually made the mistake i warned you about earlier
right now the code is stuck inside of the while loop
let me end it with the escape button this if this was an actual code example
would have been really bad the reason here is this counter doesn't increase
it always stays at 0 and as a consequence this condition will always
be true and as a consequence we keep on adding
the value 0 to this list and besides that we would do pretty much
nothing else i would spend my entire processing time just adding zeros to a
list which not only would break my code it
would also be a waste of resources the way around it is i want to increase
the value of the counter by 1. and now if i run this
we are very quickly getting the values from 0 to 100
already a pretty good start but now i don't want every single value i only
want the even ones meaning i want 0 2 4 6 and so on
for that we are going to need an if statement inside of the while loop
all you really need is the percentage sign
and this we want to use with the number 2.
if this is 0 we know we are getting an even number
if i run this now i am getting only the even numbers
this operation here if you forgot about it is the remainder
for example if the counter was at three i think early on i used dots and that's
a really good system to explain it let's say we have three
dots here representing this three and if we're dividing this number by 2
we have one full block and this would be 1 unit after division
and what this percentage sign here gives us is the remainder so this one here
and if this is any value besides zero we know we have an odd value
on the same line if there is any value so if i use different from zero we are
only getting the odd values and this is the most common use case for
this remainder operation it's a really easy way to get even or odd values
i guess while we are here we should also practice
skipping one while loop so let me extend the exercise
i also want you guys to do not add the value
58. for some reason i really do not like
this one try to add this one as well
all right this is turning kind of into extra practice for the if operator but i
suppose that can't hurt we can approach this in two different
ways we could either add another if statement in here or add an end keyword
after the original if condition i guess let's start with this one
i want to check if my counter has a remainder of 0
and my counter
is different from 58 this is the number i want to avoid
if i run the code now i get let me find the value we have 54 56 and then we skip
to 60. we do not have 58. this would be one way to add it here
a different approach could be another if statement inside of this counter
i could check in here if counter is
different from 58 and then
this append here has to be on one more level of indentation to tell
python it belongs to this if statement here
and if i run this now we are getting the same outcome here with the 58 being
skipped all things considered while and if work
really well together and all right with that we have while
loops something fairly similar to a while loop is a for loop and this one
works in a somewhat similar way we are still running code a certain amount of
time so we are basically repeating code the difference now is that we are
running code for every item inside of a container
this could for example look something like this
we want to run a for loop for every item inside of the
list that contains one two and three the way this works is that python goes
through this entire list and picks every single value one two and three here and
then for each cycle it assigns the value to the x in this case but you could name
it whatever you want meaning if you added something like a
print inside of this for loop you would print
1 2 and three four cycles over every single item in
the list and then it stores the value inside of x and you can treat it like a
variable and just like with while you can also
use break and continue and that is basically it let's have a
look at it i want to create let me call it a basic
list and here let's use the example i have a
list with the numbers 1 2 and 3. and i want to run a for loop to access every
single item of this list the example we have used is for x in
basic list and then inside of it we have printed x
if i run this now we're getting one two and three
so what happened here i think it actually makes kind of sense
python is going to run this block of code here
for every item inside of this list and on every cycle it picks one of the
values starting from one then two and then three and it always assigns this
item to the variable we have specified here
but you could use any python variable name
and then inside of the for loop we are doing something with that value right
now we're just printing it we could also add it to a list or doing some math
operations or really do whatever we want and that way we can run code for every
item inside of a list and this would also work with the other types of
containers like a tuple a dictionary or a set
as a matter of fact there are lots of different things you could be cycling
over for example a string would also work inside of a for loop and there's
one particular case i do want to cover if you want to cycle over a number this
would also work but it does need some adjustment let's actually play around
with all of this and i have pre-written some values these ones here we have a
basic tuple a basic dictionary a basic set a basic string and a basic number
tuples and sets work exactly like the list if i replace the basic list with a
basic tuple we get the very same outcome and we
would also get the same thing with a set there we go we always get one two and
three python just really doesn't care what kind of container you have it's
fine cycling over any of them the basic dictionary also works but it
looks a bit different in terms of what you
get let me paste it in here basic dict and now we are still getting one two and
three we are getting all of the keys
which if you cycle over a dictionary is probably not what you want to do the way
around it is you would use either values to get the values now get one two and
three the strings attach to each key or we would use items
and that way you're getting a tuple returned with the key and the value
we are going to learn later on how to work with dictionaries in a bit more
detail but for now i think this is all we are going to need
for a basic string we can just paste it in here and now
python takes the string apart and gives us every individual letter including the
space finally
we have a basic number and this right now is not going to work if i run it
we get a type error into object is not iterable
let's talk about why this one didn't work
to loop over a number so the operation we have seen was for x and three and
this one didn't work the reason it didn't work is because python needs some
kind of iterable and integers cannot be iterated over that being said iterating
from zero to a certain number is such a common operation that there's a specific
python function for it it is called range
how you would use that is you would add a number in it and then it creates a
range object if you use something like range 3
we would get a range object from 0 and then all the way to 3.
and this we can iterate over it's fairly similar to a list although
it is its own data type meaning if you want to iterate over a
number you would use for x in range and then the number
and i guess let's implement this one as well here we are back in the example and
instead of using the number i have to put the number inside of the range
function if i print this now
we are getting the numbers 0 1 and 2 which if you pay close attention is kind
of different from these numbers here we are not even getting 3 we are again
starting at 0 and then going all the way to 3 but we are not including 3 and this
is why we are getting two a better way of illustrating this let me
copy this and comment out this entire for loop
and just print the range object
running this gets me a range object from 0 to 3.
it very much is its own data type and this one simply gives us something
we can loop over and it starts from 0 and goes all the way to a number we
specified but it doesn't include it which granted is a bit confusing to read
the range function actually works very similar compared to slicing
because inside of range right now we only specified one value which was
the end point but you could specify up to three values in here
you could have the start the end and the step size for the values
start by default is going to be zero and the step size is always going
to be one meaning if we don't specify them
we are getting those values most of the time you are only specifying
the end value which is what we have done ourselves
but in here you could specify something like 10
let's say 20 and 2. if i run this now we are getting range
object from 10 20 and a step size of 2 which by itself isn't particularly
useful but if i cut all of this out get rid of
this print statement and uncomment this for loop
and now i want my range object to look like this
if i run it now we get only the even values from 10 to
20 and again we are not including 20. but that is essentially the for loop
it is very often used alongside the range function they are very much
connected to each other and i guess with that let's do an
exercise once more
and what i want you guys to do is this one here
and this list contains other lists these are nested lists
you are supposed to cycle through this entire list using a for loop and then
only print the numbers below 50. although skip the values below 10.
as a tip here you will need one for loop to go through
this list and then another nested for loop to go through each individual list
inside of this list finally i want you guys to break this
for loop if any value is above 100 which is the case here for this one you are
going to need a for loop inside of a for loop and also throw an if statement in
there somewhere see if you can figure this one out
yourself
alright let's do it together now first of all i need for
and now i need a good name and since i know that each of these
lists here are nested inside of this practice list
i want something like for a nested list inside of my practice list
meaning i'm looking at this practice list here and i'm cycling over this
entire list what i'm getting from that is going to
be let me print the nested list i am getting these three lists here
we still get the earlier results let me comment out all of this to make all of
this a bit cleaner there we go now we have a couple of lists with
numbers inside of them problem is this still doesn't help us
figure out individual values for example i want to print this 10 here
but right now i can't access it because it's inside of a list
to overcome that we are going to need another for loop
with for let me call it value inside of the nested list
and now if i print this value and let me comment out printing the
nested list that's going to get confusing
if i run this now i am getting all of the numbers
basically what happens here let me use different colors for this
the first for loop this one here is going to go through this entire list
and it is looking at every item and an item is counted at anything separated by
a comma meaning this is one item this is another item and this is the final item
python doesn't care if the item is a list or a number it treats all of them
the same and to access every value inside of this
nested list we have this second for loop here
and this one is going to go for every individual list it starts with this one
then it does this one and then this one and via this for loop we are going
through every individual value inside of the list or the nested list to be more
specific the result being that this value here is
going to be every individual value from all of the lists and this is what we are
printing that is a really good start so now we
have to cover that we only want to print the numbers below 50 and we want to skip
values that are below 10. i guess we can start with if the value
is below 50 only then do we want to print the entire
value let me run this now and we are only
getting values below 50. this is going to cover the entire first
line now we have to cover the part to skip if
a value is below 10. and this again we could either do by
adding an end here or we could add another if statement
inside of here i guess i'm going to stick with the if
statement inside of here although it really doesn't matter i want to skip the
values if we are below 10 meaning if the value is below 10
then i want to use continue if this is the case
we are stopping this entire cycle and we are not getting to the print value
so let's try this and indeed we are only getting values that are at least 10
and the values two and 4 we have skipped now finally we have to cover the last
part that i want to end this entire for loop if we get a value above 100 which
is going to be this one here and now you might be very tempted to add
something like if value is greater than 100
then i want to break this entire code or at the very least the for loop
however now this is not going to work i guess to demonstrate it
the last value after 101 is going to be this 10 here and since this is not below
10 we do expect this to run although i just realized that since we have a 10
here enter 10 here it might be a bit hard to see
let me change the name here to a 12 so we have a specific number
if we run the code now we still can't see the 12
and i would recommend you to look over this and see why we can still see a 12.
the error here is because of one of the if statements try to have a look for it
the error happened on this line here this if statement checks if the value is
below 50 meaning we are never getting a value above that 50.
as a consequence when we are getting to this line here if
value is above 100 this line doesn't even run because we
never get to it after this line here we are only getting
values below 50. so this line here is essentially
pointless we can however cut it out and paste it at the top of
of the inner for loop let me fix this one
now when we are looking inside of this for loop if we find any value above 100
we are breaking the entire thing and none of this would run
i guess let me run it and now the last value is 10
this 10 here this does look confusing especially if
you're just starting to program but if you get used to indentation here this
should eventually make more and more sense this is definitely something you
want to practice in your own time even more
when it comes to python and the flow of the code understanding indentation is
really important to understand what's going on
there's one more topic i do want to cover before finishing this section and
that is flow and line breaks so far we always wrote code with a colon
and then with an annotation on the next line
you don't have to do that you could just write straight after the colon for
example for a for loop instead of the line break
after the colon and the indentation here you could simply continue writing the
print statement here this would also work with an if
statement it would also work with a while loop
as a matter of fact you could even use a semicolon to add multiple lines of code
all of these here would be counted as indented python is
totally fine with that that being said most of the time you do
want to indent your code because having multiple lines is easier to read but
that's not always the case sometimes if you have a very simple
statement it might make more sense to have it on the same line
for example match case very often has each case on an individual line without
a line break between the case and the actual code because the idea here is
each case should be fairly simple we're gonna have a look at that in a second
but much more important for the if statement python does have a special
operation here to have a one line if statement and this is called a ternary
operator this one works like this let's say we
have x equals 5 and we want to check something like
if the value is below 5 we want color equals blue and else the color should be
red a really simple if statement the problem is that we have four lines
of code for something that really is very simple
we could make this more space efficient by skipping the line break here
this way we only have two lines and this i think is more readable but this may be
debatable here however there is an even more efficient
way of doing all of this and this would look like this
this by the way is called the ternary operator
this entire line would be
this bit here then we have the if statement as always
but now the if statement this bit here with the condition
is this part here from the original if statement
we also have an else and then we have the else condition so this red here
would be assigned to the color if the condition this one here was false
and the way you would understand this ternary statement here is if you read it
like a sentence i want the color blue if the value of x is below 5 if that is not
the case so else i want the color red and that way if you have a simple if
statement you can cover all of this on a single line of code
once again we have a completely empty python file and i want to start with the
match case statement and here is the exercise we have done
earlier if you see this now with the
understanding that we don't have to do these line breaks i think all of this
starts to make a whole lot more sense this one we could write like this
let me get rid of all of the line breaks this here
is something incredibly readable especially if you have some kind of
statement where you would expect a lot of specific values you want to check for
this would be a very readable way to organize all of it
although granted using if-else statement wouldn't look all that different
the much more important operator is the ternary operator
and let me comment out the match case stuff because we don't need it
the example i've used earlier was x equal 5. from this value i want to
assign some kind of color and in here you first of all need the
value in my case red if the condition you want to check for
is true i want to have red if the value of x is i think smaller
than 5 i said doesn't really matter what it is
if that is not the case so else i want to assign a different value which in my
case is blue and that is all we need if i now print
my color run this we are getting blue because 5
is well this condition here is false
but if i change x to 1 run this again we are getting red
and this way if you have a very simple if statement you can cover it on a
single line i guess let me go over this a bit more
theoretically a ternary operator always looks like
this we have a true
value if an expression
results in true if the expression is false let me add a
cross here then we are getting the else value so the false value
and then either the true or the false value
will be assigned to whatever kind of variable
we are assigning all of this to that way you can cover an if statement
on a single line of code and this is really readable and very
efficient if you have a simple if statement if the if statement gets more
complex obviously you want to use a normal if statement the ones we have
already seen i guess one thing i haven't covered yet
is that this sort of operation here this ternary operator works in a lot of
different tools as well for example you can use it inside of an f-string or when
you are creating a list let's have a look at those two examples
let me get rid of this print statement and instead i want to print an f string
and in here i want to write something like the color is
and then i want to have an operation and in here
i could copy this entire thing instead of the
variable and it would still work so i can copy it although there's one
thing that we do have to take care of and that is that right now the quotation
signs are going to confuse python so it doesn't know where the string ends and
where it begins the way around it is to use double
quotation marks at the end and at the start
and this should be working now let's try it and there we go the color is red
and in here we have a fairly complex statement inside of a string this way we
don't have to assign variables before or after we can keep everything nice and
neat inside of one line finally we could also do something like
a is equal to some kind of value in the list
and in here i could once again copy all of this paste it inside of the list and
then have some other values like i know yellow and
green if i now print the entire list
we're getting red yellow and green all i really want you guys to take away from
this is that this sort of operation works basically anywhere in python
you could also put it inside of a function or a method python really
doesn't mind and this can give you a ton of power and avoid you having to write
extra code that you wouldn't need in this section we are going to cover
functions and let's talk about what functions are and what purpose they
serve so far we covered some basic data types
like integers and strings and we also learned how to change them using
functions and methods on top of that we also learned how to
change the flow of the code using if else match well for statements and stuff
like that so we are basically able to create
simple programs that work just fine but all of this only gets us so far and
to understand why let's do a metaphor
and let's say we want to build a car and the
tools we have learned about so far are the basic parts that you would need for
a car like screws pipes wires plastics and all the most basic parts you can
have for a car the problem is these parts don't really
make a car we don't build a car out of plastics and wires instead we build a
car out of an engine out of steering systems out of control systems batteries
and stuff like that meaning what we want to do in our code is to take these
simple parts here and use them to create more complex systems like a control
system or like an engine and once we have these more complex
systems we actually create the entire car
and in this analogy a function is one of these more complex systems like the
engine the control the battery they are just more complex parts but
they're still made out of these simple bits here and the main purpose of this
is to make our code more reusable and more organized
so what we are going to focus on for this section is to combine these simple
tools to create more complex parts and that is the main purpose of
functions later on we are going to learn even more
powerful ways to organize your code using classes but that comes later for
now we are just going to look at functions and the one really important
thing i already want you guys to understand is that a function is simply
a block of code that can be reused we're not really learning anything
fundamentally new instead we are just putting our pre-existing code into a
simple block or container and then we are using this container to execute that
code that's basically it although to use functions we need a two-step process
let's talk about that one and then we actually create some functions
for function we first of all have to create the function and this is where we
are adding all of the code to the function or while we are creating the
code inside of the function once we have that we have to do what is
called calling the code this is a very common word calling a function means you
are executing the function or you're telling the function to run and execute
the code inside of it and you can also add information into the function when
you called it we will see that in just a second
but with all of that covered let's actually create some basic functions and
this we should do in our code so let's have a look at that
and to create a function we need a special keyword and this is called def
short for define and now we need a name for a function
and in here we have the same naming convention that we have for variable
naming so for example a name for function could
be test underscore function and this would be perfectly fine
and once we have the name we need a pair of brackets and those you always need i
will explain in a second what they actually do i am going to leave them
empty for now though and now we need a colon and if i now
press enter i am going to be in one level of
indentation this space here
tells python or while this indentation that any code we have inside of here
belongs to this function really important to understand
it works like a for loop or an if statement same principle
and now in here we can write any code we have already seen for example i could
print hello
i could create a new variable let me call it test and test could just be one
plus two and then i could print test
we can write the very same code in here that we can write in normal code
and once i have this i have created a function so this is the first step
and now to call it i need my test function so the name of it and then add
brackets afterwards and this entire process here is called calling a
function essentially every time you're adding
brackets after the name of a function you are
calling that function and what that essentially means is
you're telling python you want to execute all of this code here
if i run the code we can see hello and free so this hello here and the result
of oneplus 2 printed in this line and what i can also do now i can
duplicate this call of the function and run this
again and we can see this code run or executed multiple times and i hope you
can already see why this is useful you can basically create some specific
functionality in here and then execute it wherever you need so if you had
some really complex code and you wanted to organize it better this is one of the
main ways you would be doing it and let's actually do another example
and for this one let's do something more specific i want to create a
calculator and again i need brackets and all i
really want to do in here i want to create a variable result and
this result should be the result of number one plus
number two and once i have that i want to print
my result meaning this would be an incredibly
simple calculator that just adds two numbers together
but for this to work we kind of have a problem and that is how can we get this
and this number here and for that we're going to need these
brackets here and those brackets are called parameters
and what they mean is let me add them actually i can add a parameter for
number one and a parameter for number two
and let's actually do the entire function now when i call this calculator
and execute it with brackets i have to add arguments in here let's say two and
three if i run this now i can see five
which is the result of two plus three now
why did this happen essentially this number one here and
this number two are both parameters and a parameter is essentially a variable
that you can only use inside of the function meaning this number one here we
can use as a variable inside of this function same for this number two here
and then the value for these two parameters or these two variables inside
of the function come from
the information that we pass into the function when we call it meaning this
number two here is going to be the value for number one
and number three is going to become the value for number two let's actually do
this the other way around when we are calling the calculator by
calling the name of the function and adding brackets afterwards python is
looking what happens inside of the bracket
and right now we are adding two numbers two and three
and next up python looks at the actual function and the parameters and right
now it has number one and number two and now what happens is that python is
going to add the first argument which right now is this 2 it is going to
assign the value of this 2 to the first parameter
and then the second argument so this 3 here
is going to be passed into the second parameter and that way num1
becomes 2 and num2 becomes 3. and once we have that we can use those
two numbers like variables inside of the function
although one thing you do have to be aware of is that both of these
parameters only exist inside of the function meaning if i try to print num1
outside of the function i would get an error and that error is name 1 is not
defined because this name 1 here only exists inside of this function
so in the code besides coding the calculator once i could also call it
twice and add different numbers let's say 10 and 20
and i would get the result again so again this function here we can call
multiple times and well with that we already have the
basics of functions so let's do an
exercise and what i want you guys to do is to
work on this calculator and give it some more functionality it should still
accept num1 and num2 for two numbers you can add but besides that the user should
also be able to add an operation so a third parameter and i want you guys to
add a plus and a minus operation here so for example if the user adds let's
call it the better calculator
in here we can add one two and then we can add minus
or we can add plus and obviously if the user does that we
get either plus or minus operations
now first of all i have to create a new function by writing better calculator
the name of our function and now in here i need three parameters
i want num1 and num2 again and besides that i need an operation or operator
doesn't really matter what you call it and one important thing really quick
since these parameters are always relevant only to the function we can
reuse names here quite easily meaning to python these num1 and num2 parameters
and these up here have no relation whatsoever
so don't worry about naming here now what i want to do inside of this
function is to add an if statement and in here i want to check if the operation
is plus and if that is the case
my result should be num1 plus num2
and once i have that i want to print let's do this a bit more fancy i want to
add an f string and in here i want num1 plus
num2 is equal to the result and we can actually try this so i
already call the function with 1 2 and plus
and the plus we have in this if statement here
meaning if i run this i get 1 plus 2 is 3. and let me comment out these two
lines here so it's a bit cleaner and one important thing here the
indentations continue on each additional level i guess we haven't talked about
this too much yet but inside of this function all of the code has to be on
one level of indentation and now if we use more code inside of
this like an if statement for example we have to add the code for this if
statement inside of another level of indentation
and that way python knows that this code here belongs to the if statement and all
of this code here belongs to the function
it's really important to understand indentation early on python uses it
extensively to organize the code if i add a minus to this calculator
we get nothing because we have no if statement or any of this
but we can add it quite easily because i want to add an l if statement
and in here operation i want to check for
minus and now for this one
i can just copy all of this and now the result should be num1 minus
num2 and then for printing all of this there
should be num1 minus num2 and now if i run all of this again
i get 1 minus 2 is negative 1. that seems right
and now i can copy this line change the numbers let's say i don't know some
larger numbers let's add a plus here this is not how
you spell that let's run this now and we are getting something that looks pretty
good and i hope now that we have some better
examples you can see the value of functions
this is a really good way to organize your code because when we actually
execute the code we just have one line but this one line executes a whole bunch
of code and in actual programming examples you
might have hundreds of lines inside of one function
and what you see most of the time is that programmers create all of the
functions at the top of the file and then a bit further down the actual code
logic is written and that way you create some pretty good logic that is quite
easy to follow and you can just change some functions here if you wanted to
now with that we have basic functions although you can do quite a bit more
with functions and the next part we have to talk about
is arguments and parameters so let's talk about that in the next
section so let's talk about parameters and
arguments and let's do a quick recap because it's really important to
understand these names when we are creating a function we are
setting some parameters this would look like this for this function we are
creating parameter one and we are creating parameter two and these
parameters we can use like variables inside of the function so for example
inside of the function we could print perimeter one and parameter 2.
and again remember these parameters only exist inside of the function and now the
next important step is when we are calling the function we are adding an
argument to give the parameter a value which means when i call the function and
i pass in hello and 42 then the first argument is going to be
assigned as the value to the first parameter and the second argument will
become the value for the second parameter and after that we are using
those two parameters like variables inside of the function
and the output we would get in this example would be hello and 42
and the basic thing you have to take away from this is that a parameter is
basically a slot for an argument we are only using arguments when we are calling
the function here and the parameters are the slots that we add the arguments to
now there's one thing that we also have to talk about and that is how this
ordering happens so how do we assign this hello to parameter one
and by default arguments are being assigned to parameters via their
position meaning the first argument is going to be assigned to the first
parameter and the second argument to the second parameter and so on but there is
another options and that is called keyword arguments and for this one you
specified the specific parameter you want to add an argument to
and let's have a look at this in practice that should explain this the
best here again we have a completely empty
sheet of code and i want to create another function that i called test
function and right now i want to have argument 1
argument 2 argument 3 and argument 4. and then inside of the function i just
want to print all of these arguments so let me copy it
a few times three and four
and now when we are calling this test function
i can add for example one i can add hello
i could add true and let's say for a list i could add
one to
and test
you can essentially pass anything you want as an argument inside of a function
if i execute this function we get one hello true and a list
now the problem we have here when we are using position to assign this argument
to this parameter for example is that this can get messy really fast
and i think you can already see this one here
where it's kind of hard to tell where things belong to it's really starting to
look messy and for arguments still is a fairly low
amount imagine we had 20 arguments in here which isn't impossible so we want
to have something to organize this a bit better and for that we have keyword
arguments and what those are is well we're adding
the name of the parameter in this case arg1
and then we are assigning it a value like we are assigning values to a
variable this in this case i want to do for all
of these different arguments this would be
argument 3 and this would be argument 4. and if i run this now we can see the
very same result although here when we're using keyword
arguments python does not care about the order for example
i could assign argument 4 here and at the end
i assign argument 1. if i run this now the first item so argument 1 that we are
printing here is going to be this list and this would then be a clearer way to
call your function what you can also do
is to add this over multiple lines so i can do something like this
and call all of this again and it would still work python here is quite smart
and it understands that all of this is one function
and this one here is actually fairly readable so even if we had more
arguments this would be workable quite easily
now what you can also do is combine positional and keyword arguments
although you do have to be careful here and let me do one example
let's say i want to assign argument 1 argument 2
and argument 3 via keyword arguments
and then the final argument should just be a
positional argument if i run the code now python is going to
complain and the complaint here is positional
argument follows keyword argument and this is a general rule you have to
follow that positional arguments always have to come before keyboard arguments
meaning this positional argument here would have to be before all of the
keyword arguments let's say now i only want to have
argument 1 as a positional argument and all of the
other arguments this one is arg4 i want to have as keyword arguments if i
run the code now this is working just fine
and the basic reason why we have this is let's say i want to assign this argument
here via position and right now this would be the fourth
argument because this is the fourth item when we are calling the function
problem is if i
change this argument to to argument four then
this keyword argument would also be
referencing this argument for here and as a consequence python would get
confused and if we have positional arguments
before the keyword arguments this is somewhat mitigated
although you could still mess this up for example if this first argument here
is argument 1 and then the first keyword argument also references this arg1 and i
run the code we are getting an error the test
function got multiple values for arc 1. so you do have to be careful here but
it's generally quite doable now with that we have positional and
keyword arguments there's one more concept that i do want to cover and that
is default arguments and the concept here is really simple
let's say for this argument 4 if we don't get a value i want to assign a
default value and this i do by simply adding an equal sign and now adding a
value let's say for argument 4 i want argument 4. if i have this set up here
i can get rid theoretically of this argument 4 comma function and now
argument 4 is going to be argument for here or the parameter value is going to
be this string and what you could even do if you really
wanted to you could assign a default argument
to all of your parameters that would look like this i hope i
didn't forget anything and now you could call the function
without a single argument and it would still work just fine
although this again becomes kind of hard to read but sometimes this can be quite
useful now let's do an exercise
and let me copy in what i want you guys to do it's getting a bit long
so i want you guys to create a greeter function with free arguments oh well
free parameters we have person greet and weekday person and greed should have
default arguments person for the person parameter and hello for greet
and inside of the function use an f string to print the greet and the person
and also print the weekday and when you're calling the function use
at least one positional argument and one keyword argument
and pause the video now and implement all of this yourself
i want to create my function all the way at the top below my test function
and the function name is greater and in here i want three parameters let
me actually fix this one three parameters
i want to have person i want to have greed and i want to have the weekday
and with that we have covered the entire first line
now next up for person and greed we want to have default arguments for person
this should be person and for greed
this should be hello
and now inside of the function i want to print
an f string and that is the third line of the exercise
and in here i want to print
the person and i want to print the greet and i
guess on top of that we can print another f string and in here let's say
it is the weekday
and now with that we only have to call the function and let me comment out the
test function and instead
i want to call my greed turf and now we need one positional and one
keyword argument let's say the first argument has to be
positional because remember position arguments come before keyword arguments
and let's say the person then is going to be bob for me now next up we need a
keyword argument and for this one i want to go with weekday
and let's say it's tuesday and now since greed has a default value
this should be all we need so if i run this we are getting an error
and the error here is that non-default argument follows a default argument
meaning python is unhappy that we have a default argument a default argument and
then no default argument and this again can cause confusion in
terms of what argument we are assigning to what
parameter and i guess in our case to fix it
for the weekday we can also assign a default argument let's say monday is our
default weekday so now if i run this this function is
working just fine and i can assign arguments via keyword
arguments so i have person weekday and for greed let's say i can say
welcome this would also work
and i can also use positional arguments to assign the values like so
and if i run this we would get something slightly weird because now we are
assigning this tuesday here to this greet so you do have to be careful
but at the very least this is working and i guess let me put this exercise
on top of the greeter so it's a bit easier to read
and right with that we have some default arguments and keyword and positional
arguments the main thing you should be taking away
from this video is how you assign arguments to parameters understanding
that is really important to use functions
we can actually do some more things with arguments so let's put this in the next
section okay so let's talk a bit more about parameters and arguments and the
main question we have to answer for this part is what if you don't know the
number of arguments can you still make a function
and the answer for that is absolutely yes although we do have to learn some
new things and let's do this trading code
here i have a completely empty file and i want to create a new function that i
want to call print all and this function
should take an unlimited number of arguments
and then inside of the function i want to print all arguments
but the problem is i don't know how many arguments i am going to get now one
thing that you might have already figured out you could add some parameter
called arguments and this arguments would be a list
meaning if i run print all and add a list in here with let's say
one two three four five and hello now inside of the function i could run
for argument that is not how you spell that
in arguments and i want to print the
argument and this is indeed working
via the list we can basically add as many arguments as we want
and this would still be working just fine there's no limit on this
although this is kind of annoying to work with
and because of that python has a special way to work with unlimited arguments and
this is called let me add a comment here it is called list unpacking
and how this works is we are adding a star
before the parameter that we want to unpack
and now what i can do when i'm calling the function i can remove this list here
and just have unlimited values and if i run this now we are getting the same
result so what is happening here and i think
the best way to understand this is just to print what we get so let me print the
arguments and run the code again
and now you can see we have a tuple with all of these values
here and then later on inside of the function we are just looping over this
tuple and printing each item inside of it that's all that's happening in here
and that is essentially all the unpacking operator does it looks at all
of the arguments we potentially have and then return all of them as a tuple and
we can use it along with other parameters
for example if i added another parameter here let's call it first
i want to print my arguments and i want to print first and let's see what we get
we get one and then we get all of the other items
meaning what happened in
this function call here python sees that this one here
is the first position argument and we have one parameter so python is putting
this one in there and then it sees we have
a list unpacking arguments and we have a ton of arguments here so all of these
are being stored in this arguments as a tuple
and once we have that we can work with them inside of the function
and this would also work with a parameter after the list
unpacking although for this one here we would need keyword arguments so let
me print the extra parameter here the one that
comes after the list unpacking if i run this now
we have print all is missing one required keyword only argument extra
and python here is quite specific we want a keyboard argument for extra
and this extra here since it comes after the unpacking has to be a keyboard
argument the reason for that is that python by
default doesn't know when this list unpacking ends and when this parameter
starts but well we can fix that quite easily
let me remove the error message i can assign extra another value let's
say 12 and remove this 12 here if i run this now this would be working again
and here are the values we are getting and with that we have simple list
unpacking and now we can essentially add unlimited
numbers of arguments inside of our functions
now this you can actually make even more powerful
and how this would be working is with
keyword unpacking and for that let's create another
function and this let's call it print more and here i again want to have my
arguments and those i want to unpack
but now i want to unpack them again and those i want to unpack but now i
want to use two stars and you see in a second why
and i guess inside of this function let's just print the arguments of what
we are going to get and let me comment out print all
and let's call print more what this double star arguments does is it looks
for keyword arguments and then unpacks all of them inside of a dictionary
so we have arg1 could be one then we have arc 2 is going to be test
and finally we have arg3 is going to be let's say a list with 1 2 and 3.
if i run this now we get a dictionary with three key value
pairs we have arc one with the value one arc
two with test and arc three with a list and those are the three arguments we
passed in here or keyword arguments to be more specific and we're getting this
dictionary because of this double star here
now so far we haven't really learned how to work with dictionaries so we don't
really know how to use this dictionary but we're going to learn about that in
the next major section so for now don't worry too much about this but we are
going to work with this quite a bit more later on when we learn more about
dictionaries for now all you have to understand is if we're using double star
and arguments then we get all of our keyword arguments as a dictionary
returned in our function and what you can also do finally is
combine these arguments or the list unpacking arguments and the keyword
unpacking arguments inside of one function
and for that let's create a final function let's call this one print
even more
and in here i want to have my arguments and i want
to have my keyword arguments and these arcs and quarks is what you
see quite often it's just a shorthand for arguments and keyword arguments
and now inside of this function we could basically pass in whatever we want it
would all be captured by these two parameters
let me print the arcs and the quarks
and now i can comment out this function call and
add print even more and now in here i can just add whatever
i want let me add hello and
true and then besides that i can also add i
know test is going to be one test two is going to be five whatever
you want in here and now if i execute the code we get a tuple from the arcs
parameter and the dictionary from the quarks parameter
and even if you didn't add anything in here
so if i didn't have any keyword arguments
it would still work i would just get an empty dictionary and that means if you
have this kind of setup as long as you add any kind of parameter that is valid
python code into the function you are going to execute that function or at
least you're not going to get an error in this stage of the code
and well with that we have covered some really powerful stuff
and let's practice it actually and what i want you guys to do let me add an
exercise down here and what i want you guys to do let me
paste it in here i want you guys to create a calculator function that prints
the sum of an unlimited number of numbers or what a limited amount of
numbers so pause the video now and try to figure this one out yourself
all right let me paste this exercise here so we have all of our function at
the top of the code and i want to create a new function that
i'm going to call calculator and in here we want to have an unlimited
number of numbers so i want the tuple or the list unpacking operator and let's
call it args and now essentially what i am going to
get in here is a list let's actually print it so i want to print my arguments
and now let me comment out this function here
and i want to have my calculator and add a random amount of numbers
if i run this now we are getting a tuple with the numbers
we are passing into it that's a really good start
what we have to figure out now is to get the sum of all of these numbers
and this we can actually do quite easily but let me do it over two lines so it's
a bit easier to read i first of all want to create a new
variable let's call this one the result and the result is going to be the sum of
my arguments remember here this argument or these
arcs is going to be a tuple and tuples can be used with the sum function and
the sum function is just going to return the sum of all the numbers inside of
that list this list here in our case and once i have that i want to print the
result so now if i run this and we are getting
21 this seems accurate if you wanted to be more efficient with
your code you wouldn't actually need this result here
so you could just print some of the arguments and not the result
at all let me comment it out this one would also work just fine
although the earlier one was a bit easier to read so let's stick with this
one and with that we have a function that
uses list unpacking alrighty welcome back in this part we
are going to talk about functions and scope
which can be a really annoying but very important topic
basically what it means is that variables created inside of a function
are only available inside of that function
and this is called a local scope and if we are creating variables outside
of a function we are creating a variable in the global scope
and the problem a lot of beginners have is to combine the local and the global
scope and i think all of this is going to sound a bit cryptic so let's do this
in a bit more of a practical way here we have a completely empty python file and
i want to create a variable i called a and assigned a value 10. it doesn't
really matter what it is and after that i want to create a
function let's call it test func we don't need any parameters and in here
i want to print a
and this is going to work if i print test func i can run this we get 10 all
of this is working perfectly fine and there are no problems whatsoever
however now we can do something weird
let's say i want to get a and add some kind of value to it let's say 2.
if i now run the code we are getting an error and the error we get is a local
variable a was referenced before the assignment
now to understand that we have to understand the local and the global
scope and this a here is a global variable
and we know it is a global variable because it was not created inside of a
function it is just there by itself however this test function has a local
scope and the reason why we got an error is
because when we are creating a variable like this a inside of the function
we are creating a new variable inside of the scope of this function only here
and since we are now adding a value to it when we are creating it python gets
confused because there is no original value at least according to python what
we could be doing is set this a just to 2 and now run this again and this is
going to work and now this might be even more confusing because now we have an a
inside of the function and an a outside of it and to python
those two are completely separate variables there
are no connections for python and the reason why there is no connection is
again because this is a local scope of the test function and all the variables
we are creating inside of it only exist inside of this function
meaning what i could also do now is create another function let's call it
test func 2
and in here again i can create variable a again let's give it another value 200
and print a again and now i can run test func 2
and run all of this and now the value for this a here
is going to be 200 the one we are getting down here
and again the reason why this works is that each of these functions have their
own local scope and on top of that we have this global
variable here and understanding scope does take some
time but there's one really important thing i do want to cover
and that is that functions are supposed to be separate from the rest of the code
this scope isn't a necessity it's by design
and the reason is that once the code becomes more complex it is really easy
to run out of variable names which can be very annoying for example for the car
we have we could have one function for the battery and one function for the
tank and both might have some kind of capacity variable
and because of the local scope this is perfectly fine we can reuse that word
if we didn't have functions we would have to play around with that like
capacity battery capacity tank but then if we have more more capacities this
gets really annoying and this is one of the main reasons for scope inside of
functions that we want functions to be separate from each other so we can focus
on one function at the time so let me put it in red local scopes
inside of a function help us keep things organized especially later on when we
are writing more complex code this is becoming incredibly important and
incredibly useful as well but right still when you get started
with this it's very very annoying so let's talk about the rules of scope they
are not that complicated the first one is that every function has
its own local scope and every local scope is separate
and let's play around with that one and this we have actually already seen
in practice we have test func here and testfund2 and both of those have the
variable a inside of them and this variable a is completely separate for
each function and i guess just to keep with the
example from earlier this could be something like capacity
and i could print that capacity as well and we will get different numbers
and i am probably repeating myself but this capacity here for example only
exists inside of this function here and this also means i couldn't print
capacity or well i could but python would give me an error that name
capacity is not defined and the problem here
is that this capacity we are trying to print in the global scope
but capacity does not exist in the global scope so i can't do that i can
only print capacity inside of the local scope of the test function because in
there it does exist and well that is the first rule of scope
inside of a function for number two we have global variables
and those can be accessed in the local scope but they cannot be changed or
created at least not by default and let's have a look at this one and
practice a bit more this one is really important
and let me comment out all of this so we have an easier example
and this is actually what we have seen earlier so let me run
test func let's call it test function to keep things a bit more organized
when we started this part i just printed a and this did work meaning now
if i run test func 3 we get 10.
and what happened here is we are creating a variable inside of the global
scope and then inside of the local scope of the test function we are printing
this and if we are running all of this we don't get an error and we are
printing the global variable this is working just fine
and the reason why it is working is because we can access global variables
inside of a function however what we cannot do
is update the value meaning we couldn't do something like a
plus equals two because then we are updating the value which python doesn't
like now with that we have the problem of
scope the question now is how can we solve it
and for that we can use parameters global and return
and parameters we have already seen it's just normal function parameters and
those allow us to pass global variables inside of the local scope of a function
the more interesting ones are global and return
and i do want to emphasize straight away that global is a very easy solution to
scope but not a good one you will see in a second why but the one you want to use
the most is return this one is much better and global you generally want to
avoid but let's actually have a look at how
they work the first way to overcome the local
scope of a function is by declaring a variable to be global and this you do by
just typing global and then the name of the variable you want to declare as
global in my case a and now if i run this this is working
just fine the reason why it is working just fine
is because when python now sees this a plus equal to
we are telling it that this a is a global variable
which means python is now looking in our global scope for the variable a
and then we're using that value and if you really wanted to
you could declare global all of your local variables inside of every function
you ever write and then never worry about scope ever again
which i guess would be possible but a really bad solution you are supposed to
be using a local scope and keep variables inside of that
which is why global is not really used that often and when it's used it's not
really looked at favorably upon you generally want to avoid it
a better way would be using parameters and return
and parameters we have already seen so for this test function we can just
create a parameter let's call it a as well and now when i'm calling this test
function free i want to pass in my and if i run this now we are getting 12
again meaning if you want to update a global
variable inside of a function you would want to use a parameter
that is generally how you get global variables inside of a function and then
work with them and to get values outside of a function
you usually want to use the return value and in my case for this function i want
to return the value a and this return is the same return that
basically anything in python does it's just a custom implementation of that
principle meaning if i have that
i can comment out my print a and now when i run this function it is going to
return the value of this a i could for example print it and if i
run this i get 12 again or 10 plus 2.
and just to go over what's happening here
i first declare a 10 inside of the variable a inside of the global scope
then this a i pass into the function so we have a parameter inside of the
function that is local to this function only
and to this value we are adding the integer 2.
and after we are doing this we are returning this new value
and then this value is being printed with the print function and we are
getting 12 and all of this is working really well
and if you wanted to update this value here you could even do something like a
equals the test function with a and now we could print a
and get the same result and this is then how you would actually
want to work with functions that you're using parameters and a return statement
to keep everything inside of the function organized and separate from the
rest of the code and especially for beginners this is
generally something kind of confusing so i guess when you are just getting
started using global can be okay sometimes but you generally want to
rather use return it is a much cleaner way
all right let's do an exercise on all of this and let's see how well you
understand it and basically what i want you guys to do
let me copy all of it i want you guys to create two global
variables called multiplier and has calculated
multiplier should have an integer and has calculated should be set to the
boolean false what integer you set is entirely up to you i really don't care
after you have done that create a function called multiply calculator in
this one should take one argument and then calculate the multiplication
let me put this on another line it simply multiplies that number that's
just about it all you really have to do is inside of
the function multiply the parameter with the global variable multiplier
and once the calculation is done set has calculated to true and that is this
global variable has calculated then store the new number in a variable
called result and return it from the function and finally print a return
value of the function after it was called with the number
okay um probably read for this a couple of times it's a tiny bit longer but
pause the video now and try this one yourself
alrighty let's do it together now and let me comment out all of this at the
beginning so we don't get confused first of all i have to create two global
variables one is called multiply
and this one i want to set to an integer let's say 5.
and after i have that i want another variable called has calculated and this
one by default is going to be false and with that we have these two parts
already covered next up i want to create a function
called mold
supply calculator
and this one takes one argument so it needs one parameter
let's call it number meaning now we are basically here
so next up i want to do this step here i want to multiply
my number with my multiplier
and this is perfectly fine for python because remember
we can use global variables inside of the local scope
so this multiplier here is from the global scope so we can use it but we
couldn't update it but next up we have to take care of the
has calculated and set it to true this part here
and for that i want to set has calculated to
true but here now we have the problem this is
the local scope so we cannot update this global variable here
and i guess for now the easiest way of doing this would be to set global has
calculated and well with that we have this part
covered here now next up we have to store the new number
generated inside of a variable called result and return it
and all i really want to do in here is the result
is the result of well this operation here
and let me put this below has calculated that feels a bit
cleaner and now what i want to do is to return
that result meaning whenever we call this
multiplication function we are returning this value here
and this i want to use with print and i want to
multiply calculator and in here i can add any number i want
let's say 10 and let's see what we get 50
which is 10 times 5. so this is working just fine
and what i can also do now i can print as calculated and this is now true
so as soon as we're calling this function
this is being updated although there's one really important
thing about the return statement that i forgot to mention earlier and that is
that return ends the execution of the function
for example if has calculated is after return and i run this again has
calculated is still false because this has calculated is equal to
true is not being executed and that happens because return ends
this function call the function essentially ends here
this is something you do want to be careful about
but right with that we have scope and again scope very early on can be kind of
a tricky topic so i hope all of that makes sense
but for now don't worry too much about it just play around with different
examples of code and come back to this video when you get to something more
complex it will become more important and i hope
eventually starts to make more sense for this part we are going to cover lambda
functions and lambda functions are fortunately fairly simple
all they really are are single line very simple functions
and the syntax for them looks like this we have
the lambda keyword then we get whatever parameters we want to use
and then we have a colon and at the end we have an expression and
this is the actual code that's really all it does it's a single
line function if you have some very simple functions you want to work with
and you don't really want to write a whole function
this for example could look like this where we have lambda then we have an x
parameter and inside of the function we are just adding x plus 1. and an
important thing about lambdas is that the result of this expression this one
here is returned automatically meaning when we are passing 10 in here this
lambda function returns 11 automatically and i guess let's have a look at this in
practice this shouldn't be too hard all right once more we have a completely
empty python file and i want to create a lambda function
and let's use the example i've just mentioned
so i have a lambda function and the one parameter i want to use is x
and what i want to return is x plus one
and this is then the entire function how you would use this is by assigning
it to a variable and this variable now contains a
function meaning we can call it by using brackets again and passing in any number
we want let's say a 10 and if i run the code now we don't get
anything because we have to print this value
let me print it and we get 11. and that is the main idea of lambda
functions it's basically very very simple functions that only consist of
one line of code i guess a slightly more useful one could
be let me copy this one here let's call this one simple calculator
and for this lambda i want a and b and all i really want to do is return a
plus b meaning now i can call my simple
calculator and pass in let's say two and three if i run this we get five
obviously right now these examples are so simple that you wouldn't even create
a function for it in the first place i guess instead of this simple
calculator you just write 2 plus 3 and you would get the same result if you can
type properly so why would you ever use these kind of
lambda functions and there are two main reasons that we
don't really are going to cover in too much detail
the first one is that some functions want our functions as
argument and this is something we are going to
see later for example python has a sort function and this one sorts any kind of
list for example a list like one two three four and five
and we could sort this if it was unordered let me mess it up a bit
to something like this to order this function python is
expecting another function to tell it how to order this list
and this function would usually be a lambda because we
don't want anything too complicated we are going to cover this later on the
other examples where you see lambdas fairly often is with graphical
user interfaces and essentially what happens in there is
that every button gets one lambda function because a button would only
return a value like 5 for example so you don't really want a full function you
just want some very simple line of code that executes some basic thing when a
button is being pressed so this could be really useful but for
this introduction to python we are not going to cover it
but alright with that let's do an exercise and then we should be done with
it and for the exercise
i want you guys to create a lambda function that accepts one argument that
should be an integer and if the integer is greater than 5
return hello and otherwise return by and then obviously
when you have created this call this function and print the result
let me comment out these lambda functions here and i want to create a
new lambda function that accepts one argument let's call this one x for the
parameter name and now
i want to return hello if this x is greater than 5
and by if it is below 5 and for that i want hello
if x is greater than 5 and if that is not the case so else i want to print by
and this lambda function i now want to assign to a variable let's call it x but
it doesn't really matter what it is and now i can print my x
and pass in a free we get by and if i pass in a 10 we get hello
and with that we have covered lambdas they honestly aren't that difficult and
you really aren't going to use them that often so don't worry too much about them
all right next up we have one final topic for functions that is actually
really important although it might not seem that much
for this part we are going to talk about documenting functions
and this is incredibly important although we are not adding more
functionality all we are doing in here is explaining
what our function does and this might not seem important but it
really is because functions can get really
complicated so you want to explain them and this is something you are going to
notice when you are starting to code where you are writing a function and
then don't look at it for a couple of weeks
you probably have absolutely no idea what you did
and when you look at other people's code it might be even worse and well
explaining what your function does is just good form and really helps you when
you work with other people and there are two things you can do to
your functions to explain what they do the most common one is you just add some
explainer text and this is called a docs string
and besides that you can also add what is called type hinting and all that
really means is you indicate what you expect for the parameters and for the
return value of the function and if you have all of that your
function should make quite a bit more sense
so let's implement all of this all right
here we have a very simple example of a function if i run this we are just
printing two arguments so obviously this isn't complicated but i
just want to keep it simple and to explain what your function does
you can add what is called a dog string at the beginning of a function
and a dog string you create with quotation marks like any other string
and for a dog string you always want three quotation marks on each side it
looks like this and sublime essentially turns this into a comment by default
and now for this dock string you can write whatever you want or well whatever
explains your function the best let's say i could call this one a simple
function that prints two parameters
and if i run the function we don't see any difference
however now what you can do you can print
the name of the function test in my case then dodge
underscore underscore dock and underscore underscore again
and if i run this i get the docs string of the function or
a simple function that prints two parameters
now why we're using two underscores before and after this dog you are going
to understand later on for now just write it like this it really isn't too
important for you right now just remember how it looks like
i suppose another way you could be accessing this is by writing help and
then test and if i run this
we get some more information about the function
and in here we also can see the docs string a simple function that prints two
parameters and it is fairly common to use either of
those to understand what a function does meaning if you write code with a team
you really want to use this but well that's basically it it isn't
that complicated now besides that what you can also do is
to hint what you are expecting for these parameters and what the function should
return and right now this function doesn't
return anything so let's add return a plus b
and now i want to indicate that for these parameters i am expecting integers
all you have to do for that is to add a colon after the parameter and then add
integer if you wanted to you could also set a
default parameter for this and this you do in a normal way by just adding an
equal sign and let's say 10 for this value
and all this really means i am telling other programmers that for this a
parameter i am expecting an integer and by default this parameter is going to be
10. and for b i also want an integer but i
don't have a default value and with that we have some default parameters where we
are indicating that we are looking for integers
and let's say for b i want the default value of 0.
and with that we are indicating to other programmers that we want two integer
values that both have a default parameter
meaning if i run the code now we can't see well not much of a
difference because this isn't supposed to influence
what the function actually does and besides that we can also indicate
what is being returned from this function so this line here
and this could do by adding an arrow after the function but before the colon
that's really important and then here you again add the name
of the type
and here again use the name of the type you want to return for an integer this
would be int i guess other data types could be str for string
bool for a boolean list for well a list
and dictionary for a dictionary but in my case i want to stick with an
integer and now i can run this again and we
again don't see any kind of difference and a really important thing you have to
understand about type hinting is that all of this is optional and it can be
ignored so for example what i could be doing
is add a string in here
and also a string in here i know let's say test
if i run this now the function is still going to work let
me comment out those two lines here to make it a bit more readable
so now we have indicated for the function we are expecting an integer but
when we actually call the function we are adding two strings and python
doesn't really mind it still works just fine
so you don't have to follow it it's mostly indication of what is being
expected but alright with that we have covered
all you need to know about functions in this section we are going to cover
more advanced data operators and this is one of the parts where
python is incredibly powerful there are lots of ways to manipulate data and get
a certain kind of outcome there is a reason why python is really popular for
data science and machine learning it is because there are lots of
different ways to work with data so let's have a look what we can do
what we are going to cover in this section is more advanced ways to loop
over data we are going to sort data we are going to learn list comprehension a
really important topic even though the name here is probably a bit weird and
finally data handling if we want to import or export data
let's get started by looking at more advanced ways to loop over data
so in this part we are going to manipulate lists to get stronger for
loops and this is a super powerful topic because very often python you want to
merge a list and then loop over this merged list and for this for example
python has a zip function that zips together two lists and you could also
get the index for each of the lists when you use a for loop and i suppose all of
this is going to sound a bit abstract so let's do all of this a bit more
practically here we have a nearly empty python file
and i already have two lists we have inventory names and inventory numbers
and the scenario we have here is you are running some kind of warehouse and
people gave you two lists one with the things in your inventory
and then how much of that thing you have and for the order here you are looking
at the index meaning the first item and the first number belong together
then we have the second item and the second number then the third one and so
on we are sorting things here by their order
this could for example happen if somebody copies a column from excel it's
very easy to get the problem for you is if you want to
write a for loop and you have two lists you kind of have a problem if you want
to access both of these lists at the same time so the scenario here might be
you have some kind of website and on this website you want to display all of
this information for customers so you want to loop over both of these lists
but this you can't do right now you can either do for name in inventory names
or you could do for let's call it num in inventory numbers but both of these for
loops are going to be independent of each other so you have no way to connect
the two python in this case has one specific function and that is called zip
what zip does is it wants two lists we want inventory names in our case and
inventory numbers if i
print the result we are getting a zip object some point in our memory not
particularly useful we're going to see how to use this in
just a second but for now what you can do is to convert all of this into a list
with the list function if i run this now
we can see something much more useful we have a list
with tuples inside and each tuple is right now the combination in this case
of screws and of the number
and these are again sorted by the index which is what i want in this case
that being said this zip you hardly ever use in the list and inside of a print
statement instead you would usually use it inside
of a for loop and the follow-up here could be let's
say for thing in and now i want to have the zip of
inventory names and inventory numbers and this i can now print as the thing
and let's see what we get there we go this is looking not too bad
we have a tuple with our screws and how many of these we have
but the issue still is we want to have each individual value to work with we
don't want to have an entire list i guess what you could be doing here is
use indexing to get one value from this tuple
0 would give you the items and one would give you the inventory number
and you could access both
like this and you would get the name of the item
and how many you have this would work but it's kind of hard to
read thing here really isn't too specific
for that python has some really interesting functionality
basically what we have seen earlier when we assign two values to two variable
name instead of writing thing
we could write for example name and number
and now when python goes through this list
and it sees a tuple let's say for the first example we have screws and we have
43 so this screws here and this 43 this
would be the first item we get inside of this zip operation here it's kind of
hard to read if you have a tuple and you write more
than one variable name here python is going to unpack this tuple into these
separate variables meaning in this case
screws would be stored in name and the 43 would be stored in number
and that way we can access them much easier inside of the for loop so name
and number if i run this now this is still giving us the same result
except now this is much easier to read and this is an operation you do
surprisingly often i guess what we can do here to make all
of this a bit easier to read we could use an f string
and then i want to write something like let's say
name and
current index
with the number if i run this now
we get screws current index 43. i guess index isn't ideal let's use
inventory that's better so we have screws current inventory 43
and this information if you give it to somebody designing a website would be
very easy to work with another thing that you could be using
here is
called the enumerate function
and this one is basically used to get the current
index inside of the for loop i guess an example here could be if you are cycling
over this list and when you get halfway into this list
somewhere here you want to run some other code the
question then would be how do you know when you are halfway into the list
and for that you would have to know the current index
i guess let me demonstrate how this actually works that should make much
more sense we need enumerate and this is a function
what it wants is some kind of list or something you can iterate over in my
case i want to go with my inventory names
and now if i print what this is giving us
we are getting once again an enumerate object
doesn't help us too much but if i convert all of this into a list
i am getting the index
and the item from the list this zero here is the index of this
screws inside of the list wheels would be number one metal parts
would be number two rubber bits number three and these are the numbers we are
getting down here and again this enumerate you would basically
always use inside of a for loop let's say again for thing
in and now i want to have the enumerate
function and inside of this let me print the
thing if i run this now we are getting again a
tuple with the index and with the name of the item
and just like we have done up here we can unpack this again what you usually
see is index and then the name of the item or whatever you want to call it
this is entirely up to you but index here is
the common name for what enumerator returns
once i have that i could do something let me print an f string again
and here index with the name of the thing
and there we have the current index and the screws
and this i could for example use if the index
is let's say the example i had earlier if
we are halfway into this list i want to run some other code
maybe i want to notify my boss that my operation here is halfway done something
like that i want to check if the length of my
inventory names is equal to the index and this will give
me the whole list but i only want half of that
and then here you do want a flow operator so you're getting an integer or
a whole number because the index is always going to be a whole number in and
of itself and if that is the case i can print
something like half way done now if i run this
i am getting the first half and then the second half although you might have to
tinker around with this to get exactly to the halfway point
the most important part here is that enumerate gives you the current index
where you are inside of the list when you are using a for loop and with
that we have two functions you see very often alongside four loops
the other one we have seen earlier was the range function which also is almost
always used alongside the for loop we can do an exercise and then finish
this part and what i want you guys to do is to
combine zip and enumerate to get some kind of string like screws then in
square brackets id 0 and then inventory and then the number of inventory items
for each of these numbers from this list here
so pause the video now and try to figure this one out yourself
let's go through it step by step first of all we need some kind of for
loop and let me start by just writing thing
we can refine this in a bit and i want for thing in let's start with inventory
names in here i can already print
something we definitely didn't have string
and i want to have my thing this should be in curly brackets
let me run this now i forgot
we got lots of stuff because i have to comment out all of this
if i run this now we get the different items from this list
not a bad start we have the first word but well we're getting there
i suppose next up i can put all of this inside of the zip
function and then combine
inventory names and the inventory numbers i called it
if i run this now we're getting a tuple we essentially
create a new list full of tuples and each tuple will be captured by the
variable thing and this is what we are pasting inside of here
this we can unpack i want to have my name and i want to have the number
this is basically what we have done up here
i want to have a name and then i can add
my inventory with a colon now i need curly brackets
and the number running this now gets me screws
inventory 43. we are definitely making progress
finally we need to get the current id of each of these objects and for that we
need enumerate what that means is i want to wrap the
entire zip function inside of a numerit i find this one very hard to write you
might struggle as well and before we work more on this
i want to check out what we actually get returned from
this thing here it's quite a complex one
so let's see if i print thing in here we have one tuple and inside of
this tuple we have two values the first one is the index the second one is
another tuple that we got from this zip operation here
unfortunately now this thing is kind of annoying to unpack we can't do this
easily what you might be very tempted to do
here is something like index name and number but if you run this
python is not going to be happy because
we have not enough values to unpack what that means is that python here returned
two items inside of some kind of data structure in our case this is a tuple
with the index let's say 1 and then the other value is a tuple with the let me
call it the name and let's say 43 for the number
and don't let me forget the closing brackets that is important
now python looks at this tuple and it's these two items this one and this one
but we are telling python inside of the for loop down here that we want to
unpack all of this into three parts but python doesn't know how to do this
because it only sees two items as a consequence we are getting an error
what is most efficient here is to only use two unpacking variables we have
index and then we have let's call it the inventory
to pill let me print the index here
and the inventory tuple
now we're getting all of this not ideal but definitely something you
can work with let me get rid of this one here and
uncomment all of this now what we want the name
is going to be part of the inventory tuple and it is the one with the index
zero because remember this one is just a tuple nothing else
after we have that i want something like this square brackets with id and then
the current id meaning i need square brackets inside of
that the word id a colon and then curly brackets with my index
finally i want to have my inventory
tuple and now i need the first item inside of
this tuple and with that let me run it
we get all of the different items properly
formatted i suppose the most important part here
is to understand this and what different values are being returned
definitely play around with this one and understand how these things interlock
with each other zip first of all returns a new list with
tuples inside that are zip values from names and numbers and then enumerate
creates a whole new tuple by adding an index and then adding the original tuple
it got from the zip operation for this part we are going to cover one
of the most powerful parts of python and that is called list comprehension
a very strange name but it is for a super powerful concept
basically what a list comprehension is is a way to create a list on one line of
code and this can get surprisingly powerful
you can either use it to create a list or to manipulate existing lists like to
filter out values for example but let's keep it simple for now
and let's say you want to create a list with the numbers from 0 to 99
for that right now you will probably write something like this you start with
an empty list then use before loop so for num in range
from 0 to 100 because remember we only go up to this number we don't include it
and we want to end at 99 and then inside of this for loop we are
getting our list and we are appending the number we are getting from this for
loop fairly simple operation and since it is
so simple wasting three lines of code on it feels
kind of pointless as a consequence we would use list
comprehension this one would look like this
it's kind of comparable to a ternary operator actually
we still keep most of the words here so we have four
the same four we had here then we have num we still have the num here then we
have the in in both of them and also the range stays the same as well
we pretty much put the whole line here after the number the major difference
now is instead of writing my list dot append we
only need num inside of this this one automatically gets appended
to the list you are assigning it to and that way you can write all of this
much more efficiently and this is only a very simple example
this can get significantly more powerful but let's have a look at some easy
examples here is the operation i have just shown
you in the slides and this if i print my list
we are getting the values from 0 to 100 inside of a list
and again here this is three lines of code for something that ultimately is
kind of simple so let's do all of this in one line and
let me call it my list comprehension or just comp
and in here we always need square brackets this
always has to come in there and then we again need this entire line
here as a matter of fact let me actually copy it
so we have four num in range 100. the difference now
is we don't add a colon and then the operation we want to do like my list dot
append none of this is going to happen instead
the value we want to return to this list comes as the first word inside of it
and this will automatically be appended to this list
as a consequence we would just need this we need num for num in range 0 to 100
if i print this now we are getting exactly the same outcome
all we really have done is condensed this entire line here into a single word
with the entire rest of the for loop staying identical
that being said now you can make more changes to this part
here for example you could multiply all of this by two
run this again and now you have every value multiplied you could also put all
of this inside of let's say a tuple and then add num num and num
and now python would automatically assign each value inside of the number
basically what we are doing is this num
looks at the range and gets the values from 0 to
99 and then it assigns each of these
numbers to one of the values inside of the tuple and this is then what we're
getting here so we'll get 0 0 0 1 1 1 2 2 and so on
and this is only the most basic kind of list comprehension you can do and
there's one way to make this significantly more powerful
you can combine list comprehension with the ternary operator which is just a
fancy way of saying you can add if to a list comprehension
there are actually two ways of doing it the first one would be at the end
so num for num in range 0 to 100 if a certain condition is true
although an important thing here is else does not work i don't actually know
why but you just get an error if you add an else after this
however the other way would look like this where you first add the value you
want to return and then the conditional statement so if num is 10 else 0 and
then the for loop we have seen up here and choose whichever works better for
you both are totally fine just keep in mind the second one is a tiny bit more
powerful i honestly have no idea why the first
one doesn't work with else statements it might be something internal
and this is something really powerful because you could be using it to filter
other lists let's have a look at this in practice
actually and let's do some basic examples first
i can add an if statement here at the end and i only want to get
these values here if the number
is let's say below 20. if i run this now my list comprehension
stops at 19. although again keep in mind else 0 for
example would not work i would get an error that says invalid syntax
so this is not good but what i have to do to get around that
i would have to cut all of this out and paste it
here now if i run this this is working just fine
we get all of the two bits from 0 to 19 and then for any other value we are
getting 0. and that is basically a trade if
statements in here one example how you could be using this
here are the two lists you have seen from the last part
and i want to clean them up let's say i want to create a list
with all of the parts that have less than 25 items so i want to select wheels
because they only have 12 items and i want to select the screwdrivers because
they only have 23 items and for that list comprehension could be
really really powerful along with the other stuff we have
already seen let me call it the
replenish that's not how you spell that replenish
list and now in here
we want to look through all of these items
and for that first of all we again
need square brackets and let's start with thing for thing in
and i want to again use my zip list because i want to access both of these
lists and here i need inventory not numbers but names
and now inventory numbers
if i print now my replenish list i get the entire list
inside of the square brackets so far this isn't helpful at all
but now what i can do first of all this thing here instead of thing i want to
name let's call it name and number
and to get the same outcome again i would need my name and my number
so far again we are still going to get the same outcome
but now i only want to do all of this if a certain condition is true and in my
case the condition is if the number is below 25.
if i run this now we are only getting two items with the
name and the number attached to it which is a very nice way to get data out
of this list here and this is a kind of operation you would actually do fairly
often in python and list comprehension for that is what you would use very very
often now what you can also do is to combine different list
comprehensions let me add a comment here let's call it combine list comprehension
although this one is going to get a little bit more complex but let's go
through it in a really simple example let me create a new variable combined
comprehension and in here first of all i want to have
something really simple let's say x for x in range 5
then i'm going to comment out all the stuff we have done so far and print what
we are getting from the combined comprehension
we are getting the numbers from 0 to 4. this should make sense it is fairly
simple at least i hope it is but now what we can do is put all of
this inside of another list comprehension
so all of the stuff we have seen so far for y in range
let's say 10. if i now run this
we're getting something that possibly looks a bit weird
i think there's a better way of presenting this instead of printing the
list by itself i want for row in combined comp
print row
and now if i run this we can see the entire output like this
much easier to read and let's go through what happened here
that is probably kind of confusing right now
i think the best way to go over this is to separate these two lists we have an
inner list this x for x in range five and then we have an outer range the
entire list comprehension that's a terrible line let's do it like that's
still a terrible line let's do it like this
the yellow part is always this inner part here and this we now got multiple
times we have one here one here one here and so on
they are all x for x and range five the reason why we got this multiple
times is because of this part here we basically created this
list 10 times and that way you can create a list that
contains other lists although
still not particularly useful but where this system becomes incredibly powerful
is you can put this yq for example
into the original list let me actually demonstrate
instead of just having the x as the value for this
list i want to have instead a tuple with x and y
if i run this now we are getting
let me use different colors for this we have a tuple this tuple here
and this tuple is inside of a list this list here
that is the list we are getting from this inner list comprehension
finally then we have a list of lists and this is the entire list comprehension
and i suppose inside of the tuple we have the x and we have the y value
x increases on every column and y is increasing on every single row
e is y0 y1 y2 and so on with the system you can create
incredibly complex data structures you could theoretically even add a third
and a fourth list comprehension but by that point things are a bit overkill i
think i would not recommend overthinking this
it can get really complex and it doesn't have to be as complex
if you really wanted to make something more complex you probably want to use a
for loop but alright with that we can do an
exercise and then we are basically good to go
and what i want you guys to do is to create the fields for a chess
board and just in case you had actually fun
hobbies at school a chessboard has the fields a b c d e f g and h
which is eight letters in total and then we also have the fields from
one let's say one two three four five six seven and eight
which basically means the first field you are going to get is a one
and then you keep on creating more fields and at some point all the way at
the bottom you should have h8
and if you want an extra challenge this is not actually a chess board because a
real chess board would have the a1 at the bottom and the h8 in the top right i
guess i can cover both see how far you get but pause the video now and try this
one yourself
let's get started by commenting out all of this
and then i want to start let me call it chess
board and in here i want to start with the
square brackets for my list comprehension
and i guess we can start with the numbers so num for num
in and now we want range
and let's start with 8 and let's see what we get
i want to print my chessboard and i get the numbers from zero to seven
which is not a chess board we need the numbers from one to eight
for that i'm going to specify a start value here and now the end value is
going to be 9. if i run this now we get the numbers
from 0 to 8. we have the inner
list comprehension now for the outer
and now this might have been the one part where you struggled that was how to
get each individual letter here and the solution is actually really
simple all you need is to type the string a b c d e f g and h
if you have this and i run this again we get this entire list except it's very
hard to read so let me do it again for row in
chessboard print
the row there we go this is much easier to read
the problem now is that we want to have the letter and the number this happens
inside of this part here i want to have the letter
and then the number if i run this now
we have a 1 in the top left and h8 in the bottom right
that's a good start although i guess doing this as a tuple isn't ideal
but you don't have to you could totally create an f string here
and in there i want to have the letter and i want to have the number
now running this gets me something like this i think that looks a bit more
appropriate the difference here really doesn't
matter all that much and now if you wanted to invert all of
this meaning that instead of the
a1 here you would want this top part to be
h1 and then this part down here would be a1
in a chess board the bottom left field is always a1 and the top right one this
one here would be h8 to achieve that
you could just type out this string here in reverse but that would be kind of
annoying and not exactly scalable if you wanted to make something larger
but here we can do something really clever we can use slicing
remember this from quite a few videos ago we are specifying a start an end and
a step size now the start and the end
if we leave them empty is giving us the entire string
but now if we specify for the step size negative one
then we are going to go backwards over the string
now to understand this part you have to understand return statements basically
what happens here is originally we just returned this string but now because of
this slicing operation the four letter in
is looking at the entire operation here because this is what gets returned
this is really something you eventually understand when you play around more
with python it does take some time but now if i run this we are starting with
h1 in the top left and a8 in the bottom right
and with that we have a proper chest field
i hope that wasn't too bad list comprehension especially early on can
get very confusing besides a list comprehension we have
other types of comprehension as well one for each type of container at least kind
of and before i cover them i really want to
emphasize that list comprehension are by far the most common comprehension you
are going to do i am going to include these mostly for
completion sake but you probably aren't going to use them very much
comprehensions work quite easily with dictionaries and sets this would look
like this for a dictionary and like this for a set set is actually super easy
all we are doing here is we are replacing the square brackets with curly
brackets and then we are done that is literally the only difference
for a dictionary the one thing you really have to keep in mind is that we
always need the key then a colon
and then a value in this case
both of them would be num meaning we would create a dictionary that would
have key value pairs like 1 and 1. then 2 and 2 three and three and so on
not exactly useful but it's something you can refine
and that brings us to the final type of comprehension a tuple comprehension this
one works a bit differently in here you are still using num for num
in range 10. the problem is for python this kind of operation was already
covered using the normal brackets as a consequence this operation gets a bit
weird to create a proper tuple out of it you
would need the tuple function but after you have done that
you are back to a normal tuple with whatever operation you have in here so
not that much of a change and that is basically it
let's have a look at all of this in code and let's get started with a set
comprehension this one we are creating with curly
brackets and now in here we can just do the
normal comprehension stuff for example num for num in range
let's say 100 and if i print the set comprehension
i am getting all the numbers from 0 to 99
this is basically all you have to know and well let's get to the next one the
much more interesting one the dictionary comprehension
for this one we again need curly brackets
but now the important thing is we need a key and we need a value
but once you have those two you would still continue with four x in some kind
of list in my case let's go with num in
range 100 and now i have to define values for key
and for value i guess from the example i could name
both num and then print the entire
dictionary comprehension and now we are getting a dictionary although i do want
to fix the typo that is annoying me there we go
now what we are getting in here is a dictionary with lots of key value pairs
this is one this is another this is the third and so on
and in here we have set the key and the value to the same number as a
consequence they both have the same number which really is not useful
to make this a bit more interesting we could for example
get the power of num and run this again now we can see a bit
more of a difference the key is 2 for this one and the value is 4. 3 gets us 9
and so on this way you can at least see different values
that is basically it for dictionary comprehensions finally we have tuple
comprehensions and in here you would use normal
brackets and now you would still write something
like num for a num in range 100. if i print this tuple comprehension
we are getting a generator object at some
location in our memory which well is really not useful
that being said you could work with this super comprehension for example in a for
loop i could write for let's say value in tuple comprehension
and i want to print the value if i run this now
we are getting all of the values inside of it
meaning this object is working as intended we just can't really see the
result to actually see it we would have to
convert it to a tuple and then we are done
if i print the tuple comprehension run this again
now we can see the result we would expect
the reason for this is that these normal brackets are used quite often in python
and in this case they are in conflict with the tuple comprehension but that's
not something you have to worry about too much
i have never ever seen anybody use a tupel comprehension to be honest
the one thing you see once in a while is a dictionary comprehension but most of
the time you see a list comprehension and nothing else
and i guess with that we can do an exercise
what i want you guys to do is to create a dictionary with the keys a b c d and e
and each key should have a list as a value with the values one two three four
and five that should be one list for each of
these keys pause the video now and try to figure
this one out yourself
all right let me start by creating an exercise comprehension or whatever you
want to name it since we are creating a dictionary i
want to have my curly brackets now in here let's get started by
creating the keys we need to format key and value
then for x in
some kind of iterable and since these are the values that
change the iterable here should be a string with a b c d and e
for proper naming here let me rename this x to a letter
and now my key should be this letter and since the value doesn't change it is
always one two three four and five i can just type the value in here and now all
i have to do is to print the exercise comprehension run all of this
and we can see we have the dictionary here
this one worked pretty well let me comment out the earlier part
there we go this looks much cleaner in this part we are going to cover
functions that take functions as argument which is probably going to
sound a bit weird but let's talk about it
when you pass arguments into a function it is perfectly fine to pass a function
as an argument into another function and let's do this by example to actually
illustrate what i mean and for that i want to use the sorted
function this one sorts some kind of iterable in some kind of way it looks
like this the name of the function is sorted we
have to pass in some kind of iterable most of the time it's going to be a list
but it doesn't have to be and then we need some kind of function
to tell python how it needs to sort this list
for example do you want to sort the list from the smallest to the largest number
do you want the opposite of that or if you have for example a list that
contains strings how do you want to sort that do you want to go by the character
in the alphabet do you want to go by the amount of characters inside of each
string it really depends here python doesn't
know by itself meaning you have to write a function to
tell how to sort this iterable and this is the function we have to
create ourselves which well isn't that difficult but you
do have to understand the system so let's have a look at this straight in
code in my code i already have one list and
this list right now is kind of unsorted it's a bit random and to sort it i need
the sorted function and in here at the very least i have to
pass in one argument and that is the list i want to sort
what i get returned from this let me print it
i am getting the list sorted and this you usually do with a list as a
matter of fact a list even has a sword method that sorts the entire list
if i run this and let me comment out
this line here list.sort after i run this i can print my list1 and now the
list was sorted as well this method and this function they are
basically doing the same thing but this is not what we are here for
we want to look at sorted via the other arguments and there are
two you can pass in here one is really easy and one is the
function i just talked about but let's start with the easier one
the one argument you can use here and let me use a keyboard argument we want
to specify a reverse and then here python expects a boolean
if i set this to true it reverses the entire list
now we go from the highest to lowest instead of the lowest to the highest
that's basically it what is much more interesting is the key
argument or parameter because in here python is expecting some
kind of function and let me actually demonstrate a use
case where you would need it for that i have another list that i want
to store in let's call it list 2. in here i have a list that contains two
builds in each tuple we have for example a and 3 we have b and 10 c and 6 and so
on and this would be
really difficult to sort if i print sorted and list 2 let me comment out the
first part and run this again we now get well no change in the list
python just doesn't know what to do with this list
but in my case i want to sort this list by
the integer inside of each tuple meaning this one here should be first
then the second then this third and then this last
and for that behavior i have to tell python which value to access
and for that we have to create a function
let me do it straight below the list although most of the time you would do
it straight at the top of the code but in my case i'm going to keep this a bit
more readable i want to create let me call it a sort
function and this is always going to need one
argument let me call it item and now how this is going to work inside
of my sorted function i have to specify a key
and for this key i want to have my sort function
and really important now you do not call this function
there should not be any brackets after the sort function except to close sorted
and print you are only passing in the function you are not calling the
function python or well sorted does this one
internally so you don't have to do it and basically what is happening is that
sorted goes through each of these tuples in this example and passes each tuple
inside of the sort function as an argument
and then this function has to return some kind of integer
let me write i n t and the size of this integer is going to
determine how we are ordering this list so in my case
all i want to do inside of the function i want to return item and then 1.
for example if i'm getting this tuple here as an argument all i really want to
do is to pick this integer and return it and then python knows what to look for
inside of this list for the sorting algorithm
and that is literally it if i run this now we can see the list is sorted now
via the integer inside of the tuple so we have 3 5 6 and 10.
and of course inside of this function you can be really fancy and add a whole
bunch of stuff the thing is most of the time you are
not going to do that in almost all cases you simply want to
tell python a bit more in detail what kind of value you are looking for this
is very rarely becoming complicated as a consequence you hardly ever write a
dedicated function instead you use lambdas
let me actually copy this line
and now i want to have my list 2 and for the key now
i don't want a function instead i want a lambda function
and for this one we again as the first argument here we have to specify what
kind of parameter we want that is this item here this one would be equivalent
to this item here inside of this
we have to tell python what to do with this item
in this case all i want to do is get the item and then pick the first index
and since this item here will be returned automatically this is
equivalent to all of this and with that we are done i can run this
now and we get the same result so this is
working just fine and that is essentially it now with that
we can do an exercise and for the exercise
i want to stick with the same data we have used earlier this one here we have
inventory names inventory numbers and i already used zip to zip these two
together meaning now let me comment out all of
this
i want to print my combined list
run this one now and we have a list with tuples inside and inside of each tuple
we have the name of the item and the amount of how much we have of that item
and i want you guys to do two operations actually
number one is sort this list by inventory
numbers for this list the first item
should be this 12 year with wheels
next up should be 23 with screwdrivers and so on
and number two sort this list by length of
the inventory name
this means that the longer the word gets the later it should be in the list i
guess what should be first and screwdrivers should
be last we are looking at the length of each
string here and well pause the video now and try
this one yourself
let's start let me call the first one sorted
comp by numbers
and here i want to have the sorted function and inside of list i have to
first of all pass my combined list now i have to specify a key and for this
one i want to have a lambda function let me use
a num here as the parameter name since the argument we are expecting is
some kind of tuple let's call this one the inventory tuple
all we want to do with this one is to get the inventory tuple
inventory tuple and get the item with index number one
we should be done let me print this sorted comp by num
and there we go the first tuple is now with 12 then 23
43 43 95 and 421 this is working just fine
so next one we get the sorted comprehension
by name
once again we are going to need sorted i want the combined list
and now we have to specify a key i guess here again we are still going to
get the inventory tuple inside of this
we still want to look at the inventory tuple but now we want to have the index
0 because we want to look at the strings and we don't want to return the strings
we want to return the length of the string
meaning we want to have the length function and then the result of that is
going to get returned i can now print the sorted comp name
and we get the first item is wood there are four
letters in here then we have screws this is six characters
wheels is also six and metal parts is definitely more than six
meaning this seems to be working just fine and with that we have the sorted
function but there are two more functions like it
that i would like to cover for this part we are going to look at
two more functions that take functions as arguments besides sorted we also have
map and filter at least for basic python now that being said
you probably are very rarely going to actually use or see them they have
basically been replaced by list comprehension
which is a more elegant way to do all of this but let's have a look at all of
this in practice once again i have an empty python file
except now i have my list that contains a list with the numbers from 1 to 5.
the two functions let's start with map all that this one really does is it
changes values with a function inside of a iterable
just like we've sorted we have to start by using the map function name and in
here we need two arguments we need some kind of key and then we need an iterable
in my case the iterable is going to be my list
for the key i want to create some kind of function
and in my case i want to create a power function
so basically what map does is it cycles through this list which in
our case is going to give us one two three four and five
every single one of these values will be passed into the power function
as an argument and then whatever the power function
returns will be used to create a new list
instead of sorting it we are just changing every single value
map in a way is simpler than sorted i want to create a power function
and this one again is going to need some kind of parameter in my case i'm going
to call it num and now we have to return
what we want this new value to be in my case i just want to take the power of
this num and that is all we needed
now i can print all of this and let's see what we get
we are getting a map object cool completely useless
but we can convert this to a list and then we can actually read it if i
run this now you can see we have taken the power of
every single value inside of this original list
one remained a one but the two became a four and the three
became a nine and so on we went through this list and we applied
this function to every single value and that is literally all that happened here
once again since it's kind of annoying to write a
whole function for something so simple we are usually going to use a lambda
function we need the lambda keyword and now the
name of the parameter in my case i want to go with num all i want to return here
is num and the power of that if i run this now
we get the same outcome if you compare this to list
comprehension it really should look kind of familiar we're going to talk about
this in a bit more detail but first of all
i want to look at the filter function and this one filters out values
from a condition
for example let's say in this list here i only want to get the values that are
smaller than four one two and three we would need the filter function and in
here again we are going to need some kind of
key and then an iterable we want to change
the iterable in my case is going to be my list
and for the key i guess we can create another function
let me call it get below
4 that is not an underscore and for this
function we are going to need another parameter
once again i'm going to stick with num i want to check if this number is below
4 so if num is below 4
i want to return true
and if that is not the case i want to return false
and this is the function i want to pass in here
and this let me comment out all of the stuff we have seen earlier
now i can print my filter and you might already expect what we are
going to see we are getting a filter object which is
useless for us but we can convert it to a list
and then we can see now we only have values smaller than four
essentially what happened in here is that filter looks for every item inside
of this list we are again looking at 1 2 3 4 and 5.
each of these numbers is going to be passed into
this get below 4 as an argument and depending on what python gets
returned here this item either stays inside of a list
or it gets filtered out if python is getting true from this
function the number is going to stay inside of the list one two and three all
have the function returning true however four and five
had the function return false as a consequence they were filtered out out
of the list that is literally all that filter does
i guess once again i can duplicate the entire line because we don't have to
create a whole function we can use lambdas for that which is kind of how
this was intended to be used i want a lambda in here i want my number
and in here i want to run num is smaller than 4
and this works because python is going to convert all of this into a boolean
value so if i run all of this now we are
getting the same outcome except this line here is much easier and shorter
than all of this and with that we have filter and map
basically two functions you very rarely see nowadays
why that is we can actually see from the exercise
what i want you guys to do is to convert both of the power
and the filter function so this one and this one here let me uncomment all of
this i want you guys to convert this one and
this one to a list comprehension and see how much you remember
let me copy the two functions first and now i can comment out all of this here
so we are not getting confused the first one is the map function
and for this one let me do it straight inside of a print statement
in here i need to square brackets for the list comprehension
and now i want num for num in my list
this is the list we have gotten all the way up here
all we want to do is to get the power of it
and with that we are actually already done if i run this now we're getting the
same result except i think it's pretty obvious this
is much easier to read than all of this which is why map is very rarely used
nowadays if you really wanted to you could even
use a function in here as well and this would imitate map even more
so there's very rarely a reason nowadays to use map the main reason why you are
still learning it is because some older code examples might use it and you know
what they mean but chances are that you aren't going to use it yourself
all right now besides that we can do the same thing for filter and
let me comment out those two for this one again i want to have my
list comprehension and i want num for num
in my list
which if i run this is giving me the entire list
but now i only want this number if the number is smaller than four
and running this is giving me the exact same result and again this is much
easier to read than this one here which again is why filter is very very
rarely used nowadays in this part we are going to cover file
handling meaning we are going to open a file and
we are going to write into that file which is surprisingly simple
python is very capable of opening simple file formats the one we are going to see
in this video is dot txt which is the simplest form of storing
text on windows computers also works on a mac they are kind of universal
besides that you could also open a picture and there are a couple of other
basic file formats you could be working with but i'm going to stick to txt
now that being said python could at least in theory open
basically any kind of file let's say a blender file an excel file a
word file a pdf document python can open all of them but most of the time you are
going to need external modules to do that
what those are and how to use them we are going to cover later in this series
i guess as a good example here for some self-promotion a while back i made a
video on how to create a snake game in excel using python
totally doable kind of fun although very strange but
anyway let's have a look at all of this in code
before we start coding i want to look at my folder this one is looking like this
let me extend it a tiny bit inside of the code i have the python file itself
and i have a txt file called test if i open this one
i am getting a simple txt file with a bit of text inside nothing complicated
but well we don't want to over complicate things
this is the file i want to open and this is also the file i want to write in keep
in mind here both the python file and the text file are in the same folder
that is important to open it you have two ways
you could either open and close it manually
this means i want to create a new variable let me
call it file and the function you're looking for here is called open
and this open wants a file path and the name of the file in my case this is
going to be test.txt let me actually print what we get so i
want to print the file we are once again get some random thing
that we can't read but this we could convert to a list
and now we have the document as a list with all of the text inside
notice here at the end of each line we have a line break the one we have
seen all the way at the beginning this way the document knows where to end
one line the one thing you want to be aware of
right now is that we only need the file name because both files are in the same
folder if that wasn't the case
you would have to specify in what folder you are for example if the text was
inside of a folder you would need folder then a slash and then the name of the
file and if you want to go up one folder you would need two dots and that's
basically it this way you can create file paths and
find specific documents you want to open besides that there's one more thing that
you do want to keep in mind and that is
we have to close the file again if we had a longer code example and kept
it like this we would keep this file in memory which
wouldn't be necessary to do that you would need file.close
if you run this again now you are not going to see any difference
but this line removes the file out of the memory which is more efficient
and with that you can open and close a file
that being said this approach isn't really used that often
because the better way is let me call it open and close it
automatically
the way you would most of the time import a file is with the with statement
in here we need with open and then the file name this is still
going to be test dot txt and now
you have to write s and give this a name in my case i am going to go with file
what's happened here is basically the same that we have done
up here we opened a file just like we have done
here and this file we are storing in a
variable called file the same thing we have done up here
the difference now is we have to write some indented code in here
and as soon as this indentation is over then we are closing the file
automatically that way we are not going to need this line here this is also more
deliberate and possibly easier to read it's basically up to you both approaches
are fine but this is the one you are going to see more often
in here we could for example print and let me use the same line
i want to print the list of my file and we get exactly the same outcome
let me comment out the earlier part because this is the one i want to work
with the most now python has a few functions that you can use to read
documents especially txt files the one you're probably going to use the
most is file.read don't forget the brackets if you're
calling this you get a proper output from all of the stuff
read basically converts this into something that you can work with more
easily although keep in mind this read
is going to return if i use the type function it is going to give me a string
which means if i convert all of this to a list
i would get a whole bunch of individual characters that don't help me that much
the way you want to use this read function is just to get an overview of
what you have it's kind of difficult to cycle through this
but for that you could use something like for
line and then i want the list of the file and
now i can print the line and i want to comment out this
part here and now i get basically the same thing
since i'm not going to use this too much i'm going to keep it short but this is
kind of all you need to know about it if you had other kind of data you could
work more with this but that's beyond this video
what is not beyond this video is write some
file let me comment all of this out
and to write a file we again need with open
and in here i again want to open my document
but now i have to specify another argument
and this has to be a string most of the time this could be r it
could be a or it could be w
r stands for read a stands for append and w stands for write
the default one is r meaning we are just going to read the document
but the one that we could also use is a for append
and now i want to keep this as a file and in here now i could use file dot
write as an argument in here i can now
write some more text and just to make it a bit more visible
let me add a whole bunch of axes
so we know what we're doing if i run the code now
we cannot see any kind of difference that being said if i now
open the folder again open the document we can now see
the end the one we already had and then write some more text with axes around it
the kind of annoying thing here is at the end we don't have a line break
this one you would get by adding a line break character manually and now
if i run this again and open the folder
with the document we now have all of this on a whole new line
and you do want to be careful here because this a means append if you write
w you're going to write a whole new file
with this content here let me run it
if i open the folder again test file is still there but if i open
it we only have write some text with a line break on the first line the reason
here is that this w tells python to create a whole new file if there already
is a file python is going to write over it
and this you could also use to create new files
for example if i renamed this test to new
file that is terrible spelling
if i run this now with proper spelling and open the folder we now have new file
python has created a text document and that is basically all you need to
get started with reading and writing into text files
let's do an exercise i want you guys to create a new text
file and draw a tree in it kind of like the tree we have seen all
the way at the beginning of this entire series
so pause the video now and try to figure this one out yourself
i first of all want to comment out all the
stuff i had earlier and now i want with
open and let me call this tree dot txt
for this one to work i need w as an argument
and i want to call this one as let me call it the tree
file inside of here let me save the tree
inside of a string and this i want to do
with the triple quotation marks that are going to be assigned to the
tree string i have to work with white space and
access to create a tree so
three axis i hope i can still get it just right
something like this should be good and i realized i have one quotation mark
too much now that i have that i want to have my
tree file and i want to write in it what i want to
write is the tree string now i can run this
we don't have an error that's a good start and if i open my folder once again
we now have a tree file and inside of that we have a tree although i messed up
here a tiny bit i think if i put this x on the next line
run this again and open my folder run this now and
there we go now we have a tree or an arrow but you get the idea
and all right with that we have file writing and file opening for this part
we are going to look at deleting stuff which is something you can do but you
rarely need to let's talk about it the way you can delete something in
python is with the del keyword this one here all you have to do is
specify what you want to delete and python gets rid of it this would even
work with variables if you delete them they are going to be gone thing is
you basically never need it that way it hardly ever happens that you absolutely
have to get rid of a variable instead most of the time you only need
to delete values from a list and this is what i am going to focus on for this
part let's have a look at it
i want to start by just creating a basic variable let me call it a and give it a
value of 1. inside of my python file i want to
create one variable let me call it a it really doesn't matter because we are
going to delete a if i print
a now hyphen is going to be unhappy because a
is not defined which is python's way of saying a does
not exist which makes sense because we just
deleted a that's kind of all you need here
the thing is this kind of operation you basically never do there just isn't a
need for it although if you are going to learn other
languages they are much more aggressive about clearing memory after you used
something so you might see something there
but in python all you ever really are going to do is
remove items from a
list i guess let me reuse a and i want to
assign it one two and three and i want to delete
individual values from this one here delete is where you are going to
see it the most it removes an item by index
so for example i could write delete a and then the index 1.
if i now print a we are getting an error message because
up here we still have the problem if i comment this one out run this again we
now can see one and three the reason we can't see two anymore
is because we deleted the item with the index 1. inside of a we have index 0
index 1 and index 2 and we have told python to delete the 1
with the index 1. that's all that happened here what you could also do let
me comment this one out you can remove an item by value and this
should be a comment so let's say in this list
you want to get rid of any value that has a free but you don't know what index
that three is on for that python or while a list has to
remove method all you need is a dot remove and then
specify what you want to get rid of in my case a free
if i now print the list we only get one and two the three has
disappeared besides that let me comment this one out
you can also use the pop method
what this one does is it removes an item again by index although the default
value here is negative one after i have run this i can print my list again
and we again get rid of the three all the way at the end
the difference between pop and remove is that pop pops out the value we have
deleted meaning we could print this one as well
so if i run all of this i get free the value that was deleted and then the list
itself with this line here and finally
you can just clear the entire list and this i think we have actually
already seen all you need is a dot clear and if you then print the list
it is going to be empty most of the time this is kind of
overkill but well it is something you can do
and with that you have a couple of operations to get values out of a list
or well remove items from a list in this tutorial we talk about objects
and classes and well more specifically i will talk
about what objects and classes are i will cover how to create and use them we
will cover dunder methods and also simple and complex inheritance
and finally i will cover how to use classes in practice and well let's get
started by talking about what objects are in the first place
and well an object is just a container for variables and functions
for example we could make a video game with lots of
monsters and i think video games are really good way to explain objects so i
will stick with that for this entire video
but basically for the monster we are going to create we want to have
variables and functions and in this case i want the monster to
have some health some energy stamina and damage and you could add whatever else
you want in here it's really up to you and then besides that the monster should
also be able to attack to move to animate and again you could add whatever
else you want in here and what you have to understand here is
that these variables and functions only exist inside of this monster object
it's very similar compared to the local scope of a function if we tried to get
this health outside of the container it wouldn't exist because this health
exists only inside of a monster object although in terms of naming there's one
minor complication and that is special names
all that really means is that variables inside of an object are called
attributes and functions in an object are called methods
and that is more or less the only difference
the only reason why this exists is so that we are a bit more specific with our
language for example when you talk about health
with somebody else for your game you really want to emphasize that you don't
talk about a global variable you talk about the specific attribute of one
object and one more thing methods
should actually be familiar to you because you are using methods very very
often in python anyway for example when you call the upper method on any kind of
string you are turning every letter inside of that string to an uppercase
letter and that is also a method and that is the same kind of method we are
seeing here essentially a string in python is just another object with
functions inside of it or methods to be more specific this also
applies to integers floating point numbers booleans all of that stuff is
basically just other kinds of objects that python creates but that's something
we don't have to worry about for now now another thing that is really
important to understand is that it is possible to have multiple objects for
example i could create three different monsters
and each of these monsters could have customized attributes
these red
pieces of text here so my first monster has 90 health 20
energy the next monster has 60 and 40 and the final monster has 40 and 10.
so when you create an object you can give it custom attributes however this
does not apply to methods and as you can see here monster 1
monster 2 and monster 3 all have the same methods
and these can be customized to an extent but not nearly as much as the attributes
that's something you do want to keep in mind
but still each object has its own attributes and methods
meaning that this attack here and this attack are not the same function or well
the same method they always apply to their respective
object and what you can also do is have objects
interact with each other for example
if monster 3
attacks one stat 2
we could run some code to reduce the health of monster 2 from 60 to let's say
20. and that actually brings us to a really
important topic and that is object oriented programming or oop in short
and all that really means is that you are organizing your code via different
objects and then you make these objects interact
with each other and this approach is basically how
almost all large projects are made in any programming language or at the very
least any modern programming language meaning if you don't understand classes
you will be very much lost and well you will have no idea what you see when you
look at larger examples of code here we have a couple more objects
we still have monster 1 and monster two but now we also have a player we have an
obstacle and we have a menu and all of these have slightly different
attributes and slightly different methods
and just to talk about how these different objects can interact with each
other the one we have already seen is that monster 2 could for example attack
monster 1 and then monster 1's health be reduced from 90 to 60.
and if monster 2 is attacking it might reduce its own energy from 40 to 20.
so attacking isn't free for the monster what we can also do
is have an object without any methods like the obstacle here and all the
obstacle is is well an object with a position and a size
and this we could use for example with the move method of any of the other
classes so the player and the monsters
all have a move method and this could interact with the obstacle
and let me clean this up something even more interesting if you look at the
player this one here and the menu those two do look very much connected
because the player has one method called menu
and what this one would do is to create or the very least open a
menu and then when we create the menu we are
passing in the player itself so this player here
is going to be passed in as one attribute of the menu object and this is
totally fine to do you can totally add a function or an object inside of another
object as an attribute and then
this select could for example change the weapon of the player
and we could close the menu as well and i hope this makes sense the main
thing you have to understand is that objects can interact with each other
and this is how you want to organize code it makes it very easy to work with
and especially for larger bits of code this approach is essentially mandatory
or at the very least it's the easiest way to organize it
and let's actually do a practical example here is zelda like game that i
made a while ago and basically everything you see on the screen is an
object for example right in the middle we have
the player and that's one object and we also have this raccoon here and
this spirit and each of those are one object
and beyond that each of these flames here is its own object and these are
only created when the player is attacking with some magic
and finally in the top left the
bottom left and the bottom right you can see some ui elements
and they are all part of the same object and this object is very much related to
the player so those two work together very closely
and besides that each of these pillars and trees
and rocks and statues they are all objects that i created just for this
game so i hope that illustrates how useful
objects are that make it really easy to group together code chunks that should
belong together and for a bit more detail the raccoon
for example has three attributes health speed and damage and the methods attack
and move and all the other objects would have
similar attributes and methods and with that we have objects now the
next question is what are classes and this is fairly easy to explain as
well the class is basically a blueprint for an object
meaning whenever we create an object we first have to create a class
and a class can also accept arguments to customize the object we are creating
for example this would be a class we have a class and this class has two
attributes health and energy and right now the value for both of these is not
being set this we do when we actually use this
class to create an object but this class also has two methods
attack and move and those do not change
and basically what we're doing is use this class to create the object
and in the process we are giving it the specific values for
health and energy so in this case the monster is going to have 90 health and
20 energy and this process we could do as many
times as we want for example earlier you have seen monster 1 we had monster 2
monster 3 and we could continue with monster 4 5
up to an unlimited number of monsters and that is essentially the main idea
all you really have to understand is that we always need a class to create an
object now what we can also do with classes is
that one class can inherit from another class and the resulting objects will
have attributes and methods from both classes
for example let's say we want to create a shark
class and this one right now only has speed for the attribute and byte for the
method and this class will be fairly limited
because we well don't have any attribute for health or for energy and we also
don't have any kind of method for move or attack
but we don't need to because what we can do is have this shark class inherit from
the monster class and this means this shark is going to get the health
and the energy from the monster parent class
and that is also going to get the attack and the move
from this class as well meaning when we actually use the shark
class to create a shark object we are going to
get health energy and speed for the attributes and attack move and byte for
the methods and i think i should use better colors
here in the shark class health and energy
are coming from the monster class same with attack and move
those two are coming from the monster class
and then speed and byte
are from the shark class and this would allow us to reuse code
quite extensively for example we could have a lot of different monsters we
could have a shark some flying enemy some armored enemies lots more and they
all inherit from this one monster class and with this approach
we would save a ton of writing in terms of code and on top of that if we change
the move method for example it would affect every single other class
as well which is very useful if you want to make
some changes and make it affect every single other class
and especially with larger projects this is just about the only way to manage
them and let's do an example again
here is the screenshot from earlier and we have a monster class we have another
monster class and those two have the same attributes and methods although
with different values and besides that we also have the player
and what is really important to understand here is that all of these
inherit from the entity parent class and this for example contains the method
for movement because all of the monsters and the
player move in the same way so they could share this method quite easily
and just to emphasize it i do want to go over the advantages of classes and
objects and the first point here is that classes
and objects help you organize complex code
and the second point is related classes and objects also help you to create a
reusable code and just from these two points i hope it becomes obvious that if
you want to create some really large projects let's say a really good looking
game you need objects and classes without them it's still possible but
significantly more difficult besides that
classes are also used everywhere meaning if you don't understand them you
will be very much lost as a matter of fact in python there are
quite a few modules that require you to use classes
for example pygame tkinter and matplotlib respectively the model you
use for games for guise and for data analysis they all work with classes
primarily so if you don't know how to use it you
pretty much cannot use these modules or at least you could only use a very small
part of them and there's one more point that i
haven't mentioned yet and that is that classes make it much
easier to work with scope i will talk about this in more detail
later but if you struggled so far with getting
information in and outside of functions you will really like classes that make
it very easy to work with different levels of scope
so these are the arguments where you would want to use classes and objects
however you can write code without using objects
at all and this is very common especially for beginners and let me
illustrate the problem here the yellow line is the need for classes
and especially when you start writing code let's say you are somewhere here
and your average program is something like 50 lines of code
in this case there really isn't any need for classes because well your code is
very simple and there isn't any need to organize complexity
however the longer and more complex your code is becoming the more you will need
classes and this ramps up really really fast
but as long as you are in this area here it well it's very tempting to never use
a class and ignore them entirely and this especially as a beginner you really
want to avoid so even though when you are here
i would really recommend you to use classes even though it's not strictly
necessary in your example just to practice for more complex code
because when you are an actual software developer you are never going to write
just 50 lines of code most of the programs you are going to work are
somewhere here with a few thousand lines of code let's say 2000
and if you are up here and you don't use classes
you are going to be in a lot of trouble but all right with that we have the
theory of objects and classes and for the next part
we are actually going to create and use objects
so let's have a look at some code here i have a completely empty sheet of
code and the first way i want to do is to create a class and this you do with
class and then the name of the class in my case i want to go with monster
and here already we have to cover something important and that is the
naming scheme so far in python what you probably have
written is something like monster and generally you always used the snake
case styling for any kind of text so why is this different here
and well in python by convention last names are always written in the camel
case so camelcase looks like this where you don't have any spaces between
words or well any underscores but any word starts with an uppercase letter
and this is different from normalpython where variables are written in snake
case where everything is lowercase and a space is an underscore
and this isn't strictly necessary you can call a class
monster with a lowercase m just fine this is purely convention
but all the other python requirements for naming still apply for example a
class couldn't start with a number and we also couldn't have a space in
between so we don't have to learn any new naming scheme now next up what you
have to do is a colon and now in here
we can work on the attributes and methods of our class
and for now i just want to create some basic attributes
let's say i want to give this monster some health and for now i want to have
specific numbers let's say 90 i want to have energy and this one
should be 40. so now we have a class
and what we have to do now is turn this class into an object
and this we do by typing the name of the class and then calling it by using
brackets again very similar compared to functions
and this is going to return the object so we have to capture that in a variable
and this very often is written like this
and here i hope you can see why we have the different naming schemes
to python this name here and this name here are
two completely different things because one starts with a lowercase the other
with an upper case although to us as the programmer
we can tell that those two are related because they basically have the same
name and for that reason we are usually
writing class names in camel case and variable names in snake case it makes it
very easy to connect these two and clearly indicate that they are connected
although you don't have to do any of this you could totally call this i don't
know hamster and this could be
lowercase it's totally fine all of this is just convention
although you should follow conventions they are there for a reason
but i can run the code now and i am not getting an error that's a good sign
and now what i can do i can use print and
monster dot let's say health
and now if i run this we are getting 90. and this knight here is coming from this
health and the same would also work for energy
in just the same way so we get 90 and 40.
now just to emphasize that both this health and this energy only exist inside
of this class let me print health by itself that is horrible
spelling health and if i run this python is going to
give me an error and we have name health is not defined
meaning python cannot find this health anywhere in the
global scope which makes sense because there is no health in the global scope
we only have health in the scope of this monster class
and let me add some comments here to make this a bit
more readable we have attributes and besides that i
also want to create methods and those work kind of like functions we
again need the define keyword or def and now we need a name for our function
and for that we have the exact same naming scheme for normal functions
for example attack would be a perfectly fine name
and after that you need a colon and then let's say for this attack method i want
to keep it simple and just print the monster has attacked
and now i can call monster dot attack and don't forget the brackets and now if
i run this we are getting an error
and this error says that monster.attack takes zero position
arguments but one was given and this is probably very confusing
because when we called this method here we didn't pass anything inside of it
and the method itself doesn't have any parameters so why is python being so
weird here now the reason why this is happening is
that whenever we call a method so a function inside of a class
what is going to happen is that python automatically passes a reference to the
object created by the class as the first argument into the method
in this first argument we always have to capture with some kind of parameter
meaning a method always needs at very least one parameter
for example i could just write monster in here
and if i run this now we get the monster has attacked
and let me just print what we actually get so i want to print the monster we
get as an argument in here and what we get is main monster object
at somewhere in our memory and well in my case i don't really care
about this monster so let me remove the print statement but i do have to keep
this first parameter however once we have the first parameter
i can add as many custom parameters as i want
for example i could add the amount of damage here
and i could let's say print the amount with an f string
and i want to say
the amount
of damage was dealt
and now when i call this method down here i can pass in any number i want
and i get the monster as attacked 40 of damage was dealt that does not make
sense in terms of grammar let's try this again but the damage was dealt that
feels much better what is really important to understand
here is that this monster or more specifically the first parameter of any
method always references the object created by the class so this
class up here creates an object and then this monster
is a reference to that object the monster is not a reference to the
class itself and this is really important because
that way you can create multiple objects that always work with the first
parameter here for example i could have monster 1 that i'm creating from the
same class and now call monster 1 dot attack let's say with 10
in here and now the first argument passed in
here and the first argument passed in here are different
essentially we are passing this monster in here
and this monster one in here that way this first parameter is really
flexible it can target any kind of object or more specifically any kind of
object you are using it with i don't want to do this one right now
but what you could also do if i add another line here you could for
example print monster dot energy this once again
would target this first parameter and then this first
parameter targets the object itself which in this case is going to give me
the energy here the one i've just drawn over
but if i run this we are getting 40 the 40 we have
seen from here and this right now is created in a class
but later on when we use this class to create an object every single object
would have this energy attribute and this is what we are referencing here
and what you could also do is increase this amount
so monster.energy minus equal 20 and if i print it now we
get 20. and i hope you can tell how useful this
can be because if you imagine that this monster here is the global scope and
these attributes are global variables if this attack was just a normal
function then this would not work
because you would be creating a local variable that wouldn't work with the
global ones but because of this first argument that the method always gets
we can influence variables or well attributes outside of this function
which is incredibly useful so i hope this kind of method here makes
sense as a matter of fact let's practice this
one i want you guys to create another method for this monster and this one
should be called move and it should accept one parameter
besides the reference to itself and that is the speed of the movement
and then inside of the method you should just print that the monster has moved at
a certain speed it doesn't really matter what you put in here as long as it is
working so try to figure this one out yourself
alright let's try together now i want to create a method called move
and in here i want to have speed as a parameter
however what we have learned from the attack method is that we always need a
reference to the object as the first parameter
meaning the first parameter here should be
something for the monster and it really doesn't matter what you
call it so i could even write something in here
it would still work and now in here i can print
the monster has
moved and let me add another line with an f
string
that says it has a speed of and then
the speed and let me fix the typo
and now i can call monster dot move and add let's say a 10 in here and let
me comment out monster.attack and let's see what we get
the monster has moved it has a speed of 10.
so all of this seems to be working very nicely
now obviously calling this first parameter something is a bit confusing
and as a consequence in python there is a convention that this first parameter
is always called self and this applies to all of the methods
meaning this is what you are going to see most of the time and what i am going
to use as well you don't have to do it but i think it
makes the most sense although i do want to emphasize that
this parameter here and this parameter here have no relation whatsoever they
are entirely separate but it is totally fine to call self here
and self here the names are not in conflict with each
other and all right with that we have the very basics of using classes and
objects although right now we do have a problem
that our monster always has the same health and the same energy
so even if we created multiple monsters so what i could be doing
is monster 1 monster 2 monster 3
and let me get rid of this one here all of these monsters would have the same
amount of health and the same amount of energy
and they all have the same attack and move method
which is fine to an extent but i do want them to have different amounts of health
and different amounts of energy and to implement that we need another
concept and that is called dunder methods so let's talk about that one and
the dunder here just stands for double underscore meaning we are talking about
a double underscore at the beginning and at the end of the method
but it's important here we are still talking just about methods
so essentially we are calling a specific kind of function
and let's talk about why it's special a dunder method is just another method
the thing that makes it special is that it is not called by the user instead it
is called by python when something else is happening
for example there is the done therein method and this one is called when the
object is being created another example is the lan method and this one is called
when the object is passed into the len function
and besides that we also have done the apps and this one is called when we are
passing the object into the apps function
and that is really the entire idea it honestly isn't that complicated the most
important dunder method you have to understand is done their init
this one you are going to be calling all the time
but let's actually do all of this in code that should make the most sense
all right here we have the class i created earlier
and what we have seen earlier as well i can
create monster one and that is just going to be the monster
and i can also have monster two and if i now print
monster 1 dot health
and monster 2 dot health we get the same number
because we always set health to 90. there's no way to customize it
and basically what i want to do is as soon as the class is being created then
i want to create these different attributes
and instead what i want to do is when this class is being created i want to
create this health and this energy with custom values
and for that to work we need to define a dunder method and
the one we need is called dunder init and this is just going to be another
method like attack and move we are just calling a method meaning the first
parameter here has to be a reference to the class itself
and for now let me just print the monster was
created and do pay attention i am never calling
the init method myself but if i run this we get the monster was created the
monster was created and then 90 and 90. and what that means if i minimize this a
bit every time we are creating a monster so
first here and then here
then we are calling this dunder method and this standard method we can also
give some parameters for example we could specify in here the amount of
health and the amount of energy we want and well i hope you can see where this
is going basically what we can do now is we can
set self.health to whatever health parameter we pass in
and we can do the same thing for energy and the names here might be a bit
confusing so let me add a bit of white space and explain
this self.health here is referring to
this self.health of the monster class whereas this health here
refers to this parameter and the important point here is self
because this one specifies where health belongs to
i hope this makes sense this is something you see fairly often
let me remove the white space again and now when i am calling the monster i
can either pass in arguments or named arguments
let's say for the first monster i want health 10 and energy 20
and for the second monster i could specify health being 50
and energy being 100. now if i run all of this we get monster
1 health is 10 and monster 2 health is 50.
and this 10 here refers to this 10 and this 50 is referring to this 50 here
meaning now we can have custom attributes
and what is even better since this self
is a reference to the class itself we can just create the attribute in here
which means we don't need those lines at all it would still work without them
if i run this now this is still working just fine
and this is what you see most of the time where the class by itself doesn't
have any attributes we only create attributes when we are creating the
class with the init method or the done therein method
and then inside of the other methods we are calling self all the time to refer
to the class and i just realized this should be
self instead of monster so we're capturing this self here
and what you are going to notice is that you are going to write self all the time
it is a little bit annoying but well it is manageable
and well with that we have the first init method
but there are quite a few more although those you wouldn't use that often
and just to keep things simple let me get rid of monster 2
and i don't want to print anything at all
another danda method i talked about in the introduction is len
and this one needs self and no other parameters
and in here we just want to return something
let me return
the number 5 and what this one is going to do
is if i call len and pass in monster1 in there and this len just as a quick recap
if i pass in any kind of string into len let's say test
and if i print the result i get 4
or the number of characters inside of the string
i guess i could also pass a list in here that might make a bit more sense
so i have a list with 5 entries and the length of it is 5.
but what i can do now if my monster has a len method i can pass monster 1 in
here and it would return 5 as well
and any number that is being returned here
is going to be passed into the length function
and i guess for something slightly more relevant
instead of returning a number i could return self.health
and now if i run this i'm getting 10 or the amount of health my character has
which is 10 right now and another example we have seen in the
introduction that works in the same way is abs and we need dunder on both sides
and in here self and again i have to return something so
return and for this case let's say self.energy
and if i copy this and pass it into absolute
i get 20. now usually absolute is if you have a
negative number and you want to make sure it's always
positive that's what it does but well you could theoretically do
whatever you want with it
now what you can also do is one specific function in python and
that is called dir short for directory i think or directory listing or something
like that basically what it does you pass in
an object and then you want to print
the result and what you get from that
is all of the dunder methods and at the end
the attributes and the normal methods and in here you can see
a lot of stuff actually and what you have to understand here is
every time we are creating an object python already gives it some dunder
methods for example here we can see the dir
method and this one is necessary for the ear function to work
it kind of works like the len method the one we have created ourselves or the abs
function and i guess the one we have just created
is the init method this is the really important one
and most of those you really don't want to worry about because well they're just
there to make the class work but we don't really have to worry about them
although some dunder methods in here can be very useful
for example dander dict is well it's kind of a dictionary but
not in the way you would expect basically how you would use that one
let me print it right after the monster i want to print monster 1 and then dot
dunder dict
and in here this is the one exception where this is not a method this is just
an attribute so no brackets afterwards and this one gives us all of the
attributes of the method inside of one dictionary
can be quite useful sometimes although you wouldn't be using it too often
now another way to get this dict here is to let me duplicate the entire line you
can call the varus function and pass in monster1
and this one is giving us the very same thing
although i have hardly ever used either of these most of the time you just don't
need them and with that you should understand
dunder methods reasonably well now there are quite a few dunder methods
that get a bit more advanced i only covered the really fundamental one some
other examples of thunder methods is for example dunder call
and in here we only need one parameter self
and in here we can return something else again
and let me dissipate dunder on both sides
let's say the monster was called and what this dunder call does
is it essentially turns our object into a function
meaning i can call monster1 and then add brackets afterwards and if i do that
we are not getting anything because i would have to print what i get
so i have to put brackets around it and call print and now the monster was
called i guess a cleaner way of doing this is
to return nothing and just
print this string
so now if i call monster1 we get the monster was called and
nothing is being returned and when you create a function in python
it basically behind the scenes creates an object with this standard method here
and this we can just create ourselves it really isn't that complicated
and what we can also do is to add and subtract numbers
and this you would for example do with dunder add
and in here you need two parameters first of all self as always and then you
need some other number and what you can do in here is return
something let's say i want to self.health
and then plus whatever other number i get
and now that i have that i can
print monster 1
plus 10
and if i run it i get 20 which is if i find it
so the health of my monster is 10 and i add 10 towards it so i get 20. and i
guess to make this a bit more understandable let's add 55 in here
and i get 65 which is 10 plus 55 and well that is a couple more dunder
methods they can be incredibly useful although
most of the time you are only going to use thunder init this is the one you
absolutely have to understand but i guess they don't really get that
much more complicated so it shouldn't be too hard
all right now for the challenge for this part i want you guys to do some research
because there's another dunder method that is called
str and i want you guys to look up online what it does and how to use it in
code
alright here we are in the official python documentation and there you can
see dunder string or dunder str and basically what it does it's called
by the str object built in function format and print to compute the informal
or nicely printable string presentation of the object
basically what it means is that this object is going to return some text so
let's have a look at it here we are back in the code and i only
need one parameter and that is and now i have to return some kind of
string and the string i want for this one let's say a monster
and what i can do with that let me get rid of this print statement and instead
i want to print str or monster one
and this is going to return a monster and we don't even need this str because
print is trying to find a string so let me duplicate this line and remove
the str and just have monster 1. if i call this now i still get a monster
and this can be a really nice way to look at your objects and see what they
are doing because if we didn't have this done
their method let me comment it out and run this again
all we get is a monster object which really isn't that useful
and obviously this str can return a lot more than just a simple string for
example we could have an f string with
health that says self dot health
and energy
that says self dot energy and now if i run this
we get quite a bit of information by just passing the monster or the object
into the print statement so this str can be really really useful
and with that we have covered quite a few dunder methods if you look online
you can find even more but well most of the time you are not going to need them
this is very often a fairly advanced topic
except thunder init this is the one you are going to use a lot
all right with that we have dunder init methods covered
and if you understand all of this so far you can actually understand python
itself quite a bit more let's talk about this one in the next part and the one
thing i think that confuses beginners quite a bit is that every single thing
in python is an object meaning every time you see a string or integers you
are going to see an object just like the objects that we have created so our
monster and this even includes functions which
are just objects with the called under method
and i'm going to show you some examples in just a second but most of what i will
cover here isn't really important i just want you guys to understand how it works
so you don't get confused later on and there's another thing that i believe
is very often confusing and that is the difference between a function and a
method and the reason why this is confusing is
both just execute a block of code so in terms of functionality they
basically do the same thing however the difference is that a method always
belongs to an object it doesn't matter if the object was
created by us or by python and a good example here would be using a
string so if we have a function this would be
len for example and we can pass a string into it this will return four
and a method would be something with dot and then upper for example for string
returns uppercase letters for this string
and that really is the entire difference that's the main thing you have to
understand and it doesn't matter if we create the method ourselves or the
function ourselves or if it's created by python
and the reason why these are different for example is that the lan method could
work for lots of other things as well for example you could pass in a list in
here you could pass in a dictionary or a tuple
it would still work with different data types whereas upper
only works for strings you couldn't add a list with upper that one would not
work so it makes sense in this case that
upper only exists as a method for strings whereas the ln should be a
function so you can pass in different kinds of objects in here and they would
all work you could perfectly find create some
kind of len method for test and it would work just fine although then you would
also have to create a lan method for lists for dictionaries for tuples for
all of that stuff and it would be quite labor intensive
so all we're doing here is to keep things more efficient
but all right let's have a look at some code and let's have a small deep dive
into python here i have a completely empty sheet of
code and what i want to create for now is create a test variable and this one
should have a string let's call it a doesn't really matter what it is
and what i can do now i can call my print
dir and pass in my test in here and if i run this now
i am getting a bunch of dunder methods and after they
are over starting from here i get a couple of methods and attributes
now the dir method doesn't separate between methods and attributes so we
just get one big list but
well basically what we get here is an object
and anything in here you could just call like upper or title or strip all of
these are very simple methods and along with that we have the len
dunder method and this is what's being called when we are passing this string
into the len function and besides that what you can also do
let me get rid of this test and instead create define test
and then here i let me just add pass
so this is a function with the name test and i'm still printing dir test so if i
run this i am getting another object and this
object is special because it has a call dunder method
meaning when we're adding brackets afterwards it is being executed and
that's basically what a function is in python it's just an object with the
dunder call method it really isn't much more than that although we do have a
couple extra things that make this a bit more special but that's the main idea
and if you really wanted to you could even store this function inside of a
variable and this works because the function is
an object so this is just going to be an object
meaning if i now print a we are getting the same outcome
although what we can even do now let's call it another attribute that is
not how you spell that and this could just be 10
and now if i run this our function has another attribute
and again this is working because functions are just objects
although in practice you wouldn't really do this there's no reason for it
but what is much more common is that you are
passing functions or methods into other objects
so what is much more common let's say for example a simple add function and
this one takes a and b and is going to return a plus b
obviously this still isn't particularly useful but i just want to illustrate
what it does and now i can create a class and let's
call it test and in here for the dunder init method
i want to have self and i want to add an add function
and now inside of this dunder init add function
i can set an attribute self dot add function and this should be the argument
we get from the parameter add function and now
when i create this test i have to pass in
one function and i want to have this add function here so i'm going to add it in
here and let me use a named argument so it's
a bit easier to see what's happening and in here it is really important that
you don't add brackets because we don't want to call this function we want to
get the function itself so the object of the function not what's being returned
and if i run this now this is working just fine
and even better what i can do i can call test dot
add function and i can pass in let's say one and two
and this is not doing anything because we're not printing anything we're just
returning something so
if i put all of this into a print statement now we are getting free
and i hope all of this is making sense this is a really important thing to
understand right now this here is creating an
object of a function and this object we can pass around
for example we could pass it inside of a class and this would work
just fine and then inside of the class we can store it inside of an attribute
and then call it from outside of the function this is working just fine
there's no limitations on this and this is something you really want to
practice because passing around functions is a really important thing to
understand and i guess since this is really
important we should practice this with a slightly larger exercise
and let me add some comments that should help quite a bit
first of all i want you guys to create a monster class with a parameter called
funk and this funk should be stored as a parameter that's the first step
after that i want you guys to create another class
and this one is called attacks and this has four methods we have let me put it
on another line we have byte strike slash and kick and
for each method you just print some text basically whatever you want i would
recommend to print kick slash strike and byte but it really doesn't matter
and let me add proper white space here and then for the final step
i want you guys to create a monster object and give it one of the attack
methods from the attack class and remember here that methods are
basically just functions the only difference is that they are part of an
object so this should work kind of similar compared to what you have seen
here but well it's going to be slightly
different so experiment with this and see how far you get
all right let's try together now first of all i want to create a monster class
and this i do with class monster and in here i want a dunder init method
that needs self and a funk and this funk i want to turn into an
attribute so self dot func and i want to capture the parameter or
the argument we get here in there and this is covering all of this
next up we have to create another class so class and this one is called attacks
and in here we don't need a donderended method instead i want to create define
let's start with byte and we need self as always and in here i
just want to print byte
and since we need four attack methods let me copy this
a few more times
and now besides byte i also want strike
then i want slash
and finally i want kik and i think you can already tell why
this might be useful it's a very neat way to organize all of your different
functions if you have a really large game with
hundreds of different attack methods this may actually be really nice to
organize all of this all right
now finally i want to create an object of my monster
so monster in lower case and then here i want to have my monster
and now we have to define a function now this you could approach in a couple
of different ways although there's one way that is definitely wrong and it's
very tempting to go this way you could write something like attacks and then
dot byte and if i run this code
we get a 3 and this 3 comes from up here so let me comment out all of this
and if i run this again now we can't see any difference
but if i run monster.funk
we are getting that attack.byte is missing one required positional argument
and that is self and this is a reasonably common error
the reason is that this here is not returning an actual object it's
returning a class and this is confusing python now an easy
way around this is to actually turn this class into an object by calling it so
adding brackets afterwards and now if i run this we are getting
byte and basically what is happening here
think of this in terms of return statements
when we are calling this attacks it's returning an object
and then inside of this object we are getting the byte method which is this
byte method here and if you don't like how this looks
what you could also do is create a separate object let's call
it attacks and in here i could add this attacks
and then call attacks.byte and we will get the same result
and this is something we are going to explore quite a bit more that you pass
different things around different classes
so that in this example we are taking
the byte method and passing it into another object
and this is getting incredibly powerful and really important to understand if
you want to understand more complex code because a key part of object oriented
programming is that you work with different objects and make them interact
with each other and this example here so this part down here is one example to
make classes interact with each other and i would really recommend you to
practice this in your own time it's really going to be helpful
but all right with that we have covered a really basic deep dive into python
although i do want to practice this a bit more and there's one important topic
i do want to cover and that is going to be scope in terms of objects and classes
let's talk about that one in the next section alright so let's talk about
classes and scope and this is one of the really powerful parts of objects that
make it really easy to work with this scope but let's talk about it
basically every method so every function inside of a class has a reference to
that class and because of that it's really easy to get and change class
attributes and because of that methods are much
easier to work with than normal functions
meaning they rely much less on parameters the global keyword and return
statements although you can still use them if you really want to and sometimes
that does make sense but you are going to do this much less
often and what is even better objects can be
influenced from outside of the object itself
and even from the local scope of a function
basically objects you can change wherever you want there is no limitation
on the scope for them which makes it even easier to work with them
but i guess let's have a look at all of this in code that should illustrate this
the best here i have a completely empty sheet of
code and first of all i want to illustrate the problem so let's talk
about scope again let me add a comment scope problem
and let's say i have a game and i have some kind of health that right now is
10. and for this health i want to have a
function let's call it update health and this one takes an amount
and what it really does is it adds that amount to the health
a super simple function just about the simplest function you could write
now what i want to do let me say i want to print health
then i want to update my health with 20 and then i want to print my
health again and if i were to run this what do you
think is going to happen just think about it
and well if i print it we are getting an error and what python is unhappy about
is that we have a local variable health referenced before assignment
and what is happening here is that this
health to python is a local variable let me remove the error messages they
are getting a bit annoying that's easier to work with
essentially this health only exists in the scope of this function here
or in other words this health here
and this health here to python are two completely separate things
and then when we are trying to update this health with some amount i even
cannot find any starting amount for this health as a consequence we are getting
an error and there are a couple of ways to get
around this for example we could use global health
that's probably the easiest one and now this would work although
you could also use return statements but it really isn't the cleanest way to work
with this so this is not great so let me comment it all out and let's
do the same thing with classes so let me create a class monster again
and in here i want to create a dander init method that needs self
health and energy and then as always i want to set
self.health equal to health and self.energy
is going to be energy and now let me create an object from
this class and let's give it a health of 100 and energy
50. it doesn't really matter what values you put in here
so now i can print monster.health and we are getting a hundred
so this one works just as expected and now what we can do we can just get
monster.health and add let's say 20 to it and if i now print
monster.health again we're getting 120 ie the sum of 120.
and what is even more powerful let me uncomment this function up here
and now instead of the health i want to get my monster.health and update the
amount and this would still work if you are
using an object so let me get rid of these two lines
here and instead call the function update health
and let's say i want to raise this by 20 again
and now if i print monster.health after calling this function i get 120
meaning even inside of the local scope of a function
you can still update anything inside of an object but the simple reason that
here python is very clear about what kind of object you are talking about
this monster is not going to become a variable in the local scope
and this monster could be updated anywhere it could be in the global scope
it could be the local scope of a function it could be in the scope of
another method it could even be inside of the object itself so this monster
python just doesn't care which makes it really easy to work with
so i guess one thing you do see fairly often is inside of a
class you have something like let's call this one update
energy and then here we need self and let's add
an amount in here as well and all i really have to do to update
this self.energy would be
to first target the attribute itself so self dot energy and then plus equal
amount
and now i could just run monster dot update energy pass in anything i want in
here and then print
monster.energy and we are getting 70.
and again here this is a very easy way to work with scope you don't have to
worry about return statements you don't have to worry about global all you do is
target the attribute and then you set it to a new value or update whatever you
want that's it it's super easy to work with
although if you wanted to you could use a return statement as well
for example if i wanted to set energy
and then here i want self and energy and let's say for this one i want to
create a new local variable that i call new energy
and this is going to be energy times two and then i want to return
this new energy and now in my init method
instead of setting energy straight as the attribute i want to call self.set
energy and pass in the energy and now let me comment out this line
down here to update the energy and just get the energy now we're getting 100
which is this 50 here
this 50 we are passing inside of this energy here from that energy we are
passing it inside of another method inside of the monster class
and this method
is down here we are getting one parameter and this we are doubling and
assigning it to new local variable inside of this method
and after that we are returning the new energy and this new energy is going to
become the attribute self.energy
kind of a roundabout way of doing it but it is possible to do
all i really want you to understand is that you can still use return and
parameters just like with any other function although most of the time you
don't really need it a better way for this one
would be to
remove this part entirely just call set energy and then
self dot energy is going to be new energy this would work in exactly the
same way although it is much cleaner to read so if we run this we are still
getting a hundred and i hope you understand why self is really really
powerful it essentially bypasses all of the scope
issues very efficiently all right let me get rid of all of this because i don't
really care about it and instead i want to set self.energy
back to energy all right now with that let's do an
exercise to practice this and what i want you guys to do first of
all create a hero
class with two parameters
one is damage and the second one is a monster
which is going to be this object here so this object you want
to pass into another class as an argument
and second of all the monster class
should have a method that lowers the health and i guess you can call it get
damage and this one should take an amount
and then this amount you would reduce from the health of the monster
and finally the hero class should have an
attack method that calls the get
damage method from the monster
and let me put this on a second line and the amount of damage
is hero dot damage which is going to be the damage you
specified up here which should be an attribute
so i hope all of this makes sense try to implement this yourself and see how far
you get
all right let's try together now first of all i want to create a new class and
this is going to be and the hero needs a dunder init method
and here we need self and besides that i want damage and i want a monster
and let me add a bit more white space there we go
now i want self.damage to be damaged and i want self.monster
to be monster and let me spell this correctly there we
go and this would then be step number one
and for step number two let me move it up a bit so it's easier to see what's
going on the monster class should have a method
that lowers the health and this i want to call get damage
so define get underscore damage
and then here i need self and i need the amount
and all i really want to do in here is self dot health minus equal
whatever amount we specify and this get damage i want to call from inside of the
hero and this brings us to step number three
and this right now we are still inside of the
hero class which you can see by the indentation
i probably should have actually mentioned that for the class we always
define something by one level of indentation
a in here i want to now create let's call it an attack method
and this one itself and nothing else and all i really want to do in here is
get myself dot monster and this self.monster is the monster we
specified up here and on this monster we want to call get damage
and all we really have to do for that is call get underscored damage
and now we have to specify how much damage we want to cause to the monster
and for that i want to get the damage of the hero
and all we need for that is specify self dot damage and we are done
and if you just read through this i hope this really illustrates why this makes a
ton of sense it's basically a normal sentence we want
to get the monster we want to cause the monster some damage and the amount of
damage you want is self-dot damage so the damage of the hero
and now with that all we have to do is to actually create the object of the
hero meaning i want to create a hero object
and this is going to be hero and in here we need damage let's say
damage for the hero is 15 and then we need a monster
and the monster is going to be the monster object we created just a
second ago this one here and this we're just passing in here
and now let me print monster.health
and if i run this we are getting a hundred
which is this 100 here but now
if i call hero dot attack
and this one doesn't need any arguments and afterwards i can print
monster.health again
and now if i run this we get 85 which is 100 minus 15. this is how this
85 comes about and to get to this point to lower the
health of the monster we just had to call one method and that's it
all we are really doing in here is we are passing different objects around and
make them interact with each other and since we don't really have to worry
about scope this is very easy to implement
and again this is something you really want to practice on your own and try to
work on this more to make sure you understand it
but right with that we have covered scope and i guess for the next part
let's talk about inheritance
and inheritance really just means that one class gets the attributes and
methods from another class or multiple classes
and i have already shown an example earlier and that was we are the monster
that we have already seen multiple times with health and energy
and this right now is called a parent class
and the reason why it is called the parent class is because there's a child
class and this one was the shark and this shark by itself only has a
speed and a byte method and what i want to happen is that the
health and the energy of the monster parent class
comes into the child class and the same for the method
so attack and move should also be available inside of the shark class
so that when i actually use this to create an object
the shark object has health energy and speed for the attributes and attack move
and bite meaning we are combining the monster and
the shark class to create the actual shark object
and the reason why we are doing this is this makes it very easy to reuse code
let's say this monster here could be the parent class to every monster in our
game and if we have this we never have to set
the attributes health for energy for any other monster they are always available
for every single class because they all inherit from this monster
and obviously this is still a very simple example in an actual game the
monster class might have a few hundred if not thousands of lines of code
and then it really makes sense to reuse code as much as we can
because then we don't have to create new classes all the time with all of these
methods that we have to type over and over again
and then on top of that if we wanted to make changes to how things move in the
game so this method here if we didn't use inheritance and we want
to make change how things move in the game we would have to change possibly
hundreds of different move methods for every single monster but if we use
inheritance we don't have to if we change one move method we are changing
how every monster in the game moves so i hope that makes sense
and one important concept here is that the class can inherit from an unlimited
number of other classes this could look like this
in here we could have a parent class 1 a parent class 2 and a parent class 3
and then the child class would have the attributes and methods of all of these
parent classes and you can also turn this around where
you have a parent class and this parent class is being inherited from by an
unlimited number of other classes and this would look something like this
you have one parent class and you have one child class a second
child class and a third child class and all three of those would have
the methods and attributes of the parent class
and this here for example could be the monster class
and then this one here maybe the shark class and let's say this one here
could be i don't know like a bird class or something
now there's one thing you do want to be aware of though and that is that
inheritance can get very very complex
up to a point where it really doesn't become fun to work with them
and this is also the part where beginners really start to struggle
because well i'm going to show you an example later on but this can get very
very complex and really hard to work with
fortunately this is fairly rare most of the time you just need simple
inheritance and this one is really easy to implement
and this one might be something like this the example we have already seen
and this one should be very easy to follow so for this section i just want
to focus on implementing this part here and i guess let's actually implement
this one in code and let's see how this is going to look like
alrighty so here once again we can see our monster class and from this monster
class i want to get
a shark class and this one should get the health the
energy the attack method and the move method of this monster class we want to
put all of this inside of the shark now
passing in the methods is very simple but the health and the energy are going
to be a bit more complicated so for now let me simplify things a tiny bit by
commenting out the dander init method and instead
setting health to something constant let's say 50
and energy to 100. the reason being that init is a bit more
complicated for inheritance so i'm going to ignore this part for now just to keep
things simple but we will implement this in just a bit
all right now for this shark i want to create an
init method by itself and this one needs self
and in here i want to set this speed and now what i want to do is
self.speed is going to be speed
and this way we are getting our attribute and besides that i also want
one method and that method i have called byte and in here we just need self and
let me print the shark
has bitten or whatever you want to put in here
and this by itself would be a functioning class but also a very
limited class because it only has a single attribute and one method it
doesn't really do all that much so how can i get all of the monster
attributes and methods inside of the shark
and to get inheritance what we have to do is
add brackets after the shark or the name of the shark class
and then here we have to pass in what class we want to inherit from in my
case this is monster and for start this is all you need
meaning now i can create my shark by calling shark
and i have to pass in a speed for the shark and let me just say i don't know
120. and now if i print my shark
all of this works just fine and we are getting an object but what i can do now
is get my shark dot health and this is the 50 we have set all the
way at the top here i can also get my shark speed
this is the 120 we set for the shark in here
and besides that i can also call shark dot byte
we get the shark as bitten and besides that i can also set shark dot
attack and this one needs an amount so let's say 20
and this is the attack method we have gotten from here so the parent class
and if i run this we get the monster has attacked
and well with that we already have super simple inheritance
just by adding this brackets monster we are getting all of these attributes and
these methods here so that's a pretty good start now
what you can also do let's say let me remove some white space here
let's say for the shark this move method here doesn't really work because for the
shark i want something else i want the shark to swim and for the speed i want
to set since i have a speed i want to use self.speed meaning i want to
overwrite this speed from the parent class
and to achieve that all you have to do is define a method with the same name in
the child class so in here i want self.move
and now i can add a print statement in here
the shark has moved and let's say print again
the speed of the shark is and then self.speed
and this should be an f string and now if i call shark dot move and we
don't need any arguments if i call this the shark has moved the speed of the
shark is 120. and what happens in here is we are first
getting the inheritance from the monster and then this move here is being
overwritten by this move here which means you can overwrite what you
get from the parent class very easily and this you could also do with
attributes although we actually have to talk about
attributes let's do it right now the problem we are facing right now
is that the monster has an init method let me remove this health and energy and
uncomment the init method essentially the problem we have right
now to give the monster the attributes this self.health and self.energy
we have to first call the init method
and if we don't call the init method we don't get these attributes so what we
have to figure out inside of the init method how to call the parent init
method so this would have to happen in here
and for that we have two ways one that is a bit outdated but still works and
one you actually want to use and let's cover both but you don't really need the
first one anymore but just in case you see it let's cover
it now what you can do you can call the parent class so monster
and then call the dunder init method and now in here
you have to pass all of the arguments so these ones here that you want for the
parent class so we need self health and energy
and these we have to get from arguments so when i initiate the shark besides
speed i also want to get health for the shark and energy for the shark
meaning when i actually create the object of the shark
besides speed i want to set health to 100
and energy to 80. now what i get let's go over this
actually the first step happens down here
i am calling the shark class and i'm passing in three arguments
i have the speed i have the health and i have the energy
and these three arguments are being covered in speed
health and energy and inside of this init method we are
calling the parent init method and into this init method we have to
pass in three arguments self
health and energy and self originally for the parent class
was the class itself so this self here which refers to this monster
however now the self is going to refer to this self here which is the shark
meaning when we are setting self.health and self.energy we don't talk about the
monster we are talking about the shark class
and this is why the self here is important
and then besides the self we also need health and energy and these are just
going to be arguments we have to pass in here so this health and this energy
and these two we get from these two parameters here which is health and
energy and those are being passed in here
and with the left to move method i don't care about this one instead let me print
shark dot let's start with speed let's actually print all of them so
besides speed i want health and i want energy if i run this we get 120 180
the numbers we have specified here and
well this can get a bit complicated but look at the init method here and the
init method here and
if you didn't understand what i talked about in the last part practice this
yourself and then go over this a couple of times
if you get used to this it's eventually going to become fairly easy although i
suppose in the beginning this can be a bit overwhelming
the one really important thing you have to understand is that we are calling the
init method and we are passing in the arguments that we want to set in this
case speed health and energy and then inside of this init method we
are right now calling the parent init method
and then passing health and energy so these two
in there as arguments so for example we first set the health
here when we are creating the object this health goes into this health for
the parameter and then this parameter goes into
the init method of the parent and then the init method
sets self.health or the actual class
and that way you can connect the init methods of different classes now this is
how python used to work and this still works but there are some downsides to
using it this way so this isn't really used anymore
instead what we use is called super and this is a function
and this super all it really does is it gets the parent class
so if we have that we can just call the init method on it as well
and in here we don't need self all we have to do is pass in health and energy
and then we are done if i run this now we are getting the very same outcome
meaning those two approaches here are functionally identical at least up to
this point when we get to multiple inheritance or
let's say more complex inheritance super is the much better method
and this is why we don't use this initial approach anymore and i guess
this one is also a bit easier to read it kinda is up to you but this is the one
you do want to use and super you can actually use for a lot
of other things as well for example
i could call super and then call the move method of the
parent and in here i have to pass in a speed let's say 10
so now when i run the code i get the monster has moved at a speed
of 10 meaning when we are calling the init
method of the shark class we are also calling the move method of the parent
and this way even if you overwrite a method from the parent class you can
still call it with super if you really want to
which adds even more flexibility to all of this
and this is simple inheritance
which is something you definitely want to practice this is the one kind of
inheritance you are going to use fairly often and the one you have to understand
let's practice this one and let me add comments one more time
let's do an exercise i want you guys to create a scorpion
class that inherits from the monster
and it should get health and energy from the parent
and then besides that there should also be a poison
damage attribute and i want you guys to overwrite
the damage method to show poison
damage kinda like what we have done for the
move method for the shark pause the video now and try to implement
this one yourself and see how far you get
i want to start by creating a class called scorpion that is not used for
scorpion there we go and this one should inherit from monster
and now in here i want to create a dunder init
method and this one itself and besides that i want poison
dammit and now inside of the scorpion i want to
set self poison damage as poison damage so we are getting an
attribute and then besides that
i want to define or well overwrite the attack method
let me minimize the shark class so we can see the code a bit easier and i want
to overwrite this attack method here and in my guess what i want i just want
self because i already have the poison damage
and all i want to do in here is print the
scorpion has attacked and
print it has
dealt and then we want self dot poison damage
and poison damage and this should be an f string
all right so far this should have been fairly easy
what i can do now let me delete all of this and let's delete a shark as well we
don't need him for now and what i want to do is to create an
instance or an object from my scorpion i am really bad at typing scorpion
and here i bought my scorpion and right now we have a poison damage i don't know
of 50. and now if i type scorpion.attack
this is working the scorpion has attacked it has dealt 50 poison damage
this shouldn't have an underscore there we go it has dealt
50 poison damage this looks much better meaning what we have so far we have a
scorpion with poison damage and we have overwritten the attack method
and since we are inheriting from monster we're also getting this move method here
meaning my scorpion can also move at a certain speed let's say 5 if i run this
and let's make this a bit larger we have the attack method for the
scorpion and we have the move method but what we don't have let me get rid of
those two we don't have
scorpion.health for example this attribute doesn't exist right now
because monster
only gets these two attributes once we're running the init method
so what we have to do in the scorpion called the init method of the parent
class which we get with super and then dunder
init in here and if i scroll up
the monster class for the init method needs two arguments health and energy
so let me comment those two and in the united method i want to pass in health
and energy now these numbers have to come from
somewhere although they don't necessarily have to
i could for example just set static numbers in here let's say 50 and 10.
if i run this now we get 50 for health because all we are doing here is calling
a function that is under init and we're just giving it different
arguments
although this lacks a lot of flexibility so i don't want to do it but we could if
we wanted to instead i want to get this health and
this energy from the init method of the scorpion
class and in here just to be specific about
what we are doing let me name this scorpion health
and scorpion energy and somehow my brain always wants
to add a tea to scorpion i have no idea why
and now when i call the init method for the monster my health should be my
scorpion health and my energy should be my scorpion energy
when i am creating the actual object i want to have let me use named
arguments that makes it a bit easier to read my poison damage should be 50
my scorpion health should be 20 and my scorpion energy
should be 10. and now if i run this we get 20 for the
health of the scorpion because remember we are only calling scorpion health the
parameter so this is scorpion health here we don't actually set this
parameter as an attribute instead what we do
we are using the health attribute of the parent class and this gets the value of
the scorpion health so our scorpion doesn't have scorpion
health as an attribute it just has health
and along those lines we also have energy if i run this we get 10.
and i hope this starts to make a bit more sense this is definitely something
you want to practice if you only partially followed along this is a
really important concept to understand and definitely something you are going
to see all the time and this you can actually make quite a
bit more complex with well more complex inheritance so let's talk about that one
and basically what that means so far we always had one parent class and then a
child class so a pretty immediate connection
something slightly more complex is you have a child class and two parent
classes this is something we are going to build
in this section but if you really wanted to you could do
something like this and it would still work
now maintaining something like this is going to be a ton of work
although once you have it this child class is incredibly powerful because it
gets information from a lot of parent classes
so especially if you create something really large this is something you do
want to be able to understand but for now especially if you're a beginner and
this is the first time you've really engaged with objects
i wouldn't recommend to worry about this too much because it gets overwhelming
very fast instead make sure to understand this
scheme if you understand that one you should be able to follow along with this
one as well but for now just practice objects in the first place and once you
have a better grasp of objects engage in this one so let's talk about how we
could create something like this and this i think is best done in actual
code so let's have a look how we can work with this
now here i have some code already i have the monster class we have seen
quite often by now this one i hope is familiar at this point besides that i
also have a fish class now and this one is a very simple class all we have is an
init method and this one sets a speed and has scales
and besides that we have a swim method and this one just prints swimming at the
speed of whatever the speed of the object is going to be
and what i want to do i want to create my shark again
but this time the shark is not just going to be inheriting from monster it
is also going to be inheriting from fish so the first thing for multiple or
complex inheritance is that
all the objects you want to inherit from should be here in the brackets after the
name of the class and in here you could add as many other classes you want
there could be class 3 class 4 class 5 as many as you want there isn't really a
limit and now inside of this shark i want to
set a dunder init method and in here we always need self this one
should make sense by now and besides that for the shark let's say
i want to set a byte strength and then
inside of this init method i want to self dot byte strength is going to be
byte strength this one should still make sense it's quite straightforward
but the more complex one is if i now want to call super and then dunder init
now we have a problem because i have no idea what to put in here
and the question here is what arguments should go into this inhibit method
should i add the arguments for the monster class or for the fish class or
both how would this work and there are a couple of things you
have to understand to solve this problem the first one is called the mro or the
method resolution order and what this really means is
let me add a comment here mro or
method resolution
order what this basically means is in what
order the parent init methods are being called
and this you can get by just printing and i want to get the
shark class not the object the class itself and call mro on it and this is
still going to work and if i call this we are getting invalid syntax because
the question mark here is not something python likes so let me comment it out
for now and now let's run this again and now we can see the mro or the resolution
order and basically what it means is in what order python is going to go through
the classes we start with the shark itself this one
should make sense this is the class that we actually work in so this is where we
want to start next up we are looking at the monster
class then we look at the fish and finally we
look at a generic object and this generic object you don't have to worry
about because this is something inbuilt into python it's the thing that makes
all of the objects work you don't have to worry about it
so what we have to worry about is the shark the monster and the fish
and how this order comes about is from the order of these arguments here
and basically how this works is that the leftmost item monster in this case is
always going to be the first in line with the class itself being the very
first item so shark is going to be 0 monster s1 fish is 2 and then every
subsequent item is going to be next meaning what i could be doing is turn
these two around and call fish first and then monster if
i run this now we are still starting on our shark but now fish is the first item
of inheritance then we have monster and we still have object finally but in my
case i do want to keep monster as the first item
so the first thing you do have to understand is if we are calling the
super dunder init method we are looking at the first item inside
of these arguments here so in this case monster
meaning for now i can minimize the fish class and just look at the monster and
let me minimize these methods as well so it's a bit easier to see
and basically what i can do now let me comment out the mro and i actually want
to create a shark object from my shark and this is something you should be
familiar with from simple inheritance right now we only have the byte strength
so byte strength and this we can set to whatever we want let's say 50.
but now for this superintendent method i need the arguments for the init method
of the parent class in this case health and energy these two i want to pass in
here now for these two i again i am going to
need some numbers so for the init method of the shark class i also want health
and energy meaning when i create the object i also
want health and energy and let's set those to
i don't know 200 and energy could be 55 and with that we are essentially back to
simple inheritance i first call the class itself and the first one we do
after calling the class we are calling the init method
and inside of the init method python knows
that the first item of inheritance is the monster class
and then after that python knows we have one
parameter for byte strength and this we're just setting as a parameter and
then we are done with it so this is as far as this one goes
besides that we also have health and energy
and these two we want to pass into the init method of the first parent class so
the monster and those we are getting up here
but now we have another problem and that problem is what happens to the fish
let me run the code and let's see what happens
are not getting an error that's a pretty good sign
now if i run shark
and the methods we have here could for
example be attack and for attack we need an amount let's
say 10. the monster is attacked 10 damage was
stealth so this attack method works just fine
besides that i can also print shark.health
and let me print this this one is working 200
we also get shark dot energy with 55 and we are also getting the byte strength
so far we have the shark itself and the monster
what we don't have is the fish let me minimize the monster class and open the
fish in here we have speed and has scales
and this our class doesn't have right now
so if i type shark and speed
and run the code we are getting that the shark object has no attribute speed
which means that the inheritance from the fish is not working right now
and let me reopen the monster and hide the monster methods so we can see all of
the classes quite easily basically what is happening
the mro is important here again this one here
essentially how you have to think about it
we first of all call the shark and then we call the init method of the shark
and then python knows the first item of inheritance is the monster
and since we are calling super.init we are calling this init method up here
and passing the arguments in there the consequence is that we have health
and energy for the monster and the normal inheritance still works so we
also have attack and move but now the problem is that the init
method of the fish is never called
and as a consequence speed and has scales doesn't exist inside of the shark
and what we have to figure out is how to call this init method
and since we still have to worry about the mro we have to figure out how to
call this init method with the arguments
from inside of the init method of the monster
and for that purpose we are still going to need this super
and then the dunder init
method and this function is very smart because
it follows the inheritance that we have set by the shark to begin with
meaning if we call the monster from the shark it knows it has to look at the
fish next in line however if you call the monster by
itself this init method wouldn't really do anything so this is a very
intelligent function in the simplest terms basically what
this init method has to do is to set the speed and hash scales
of the other class which is the fish again
let me set some static numbers for the speed let's go with 75 and for scales
this should be false and now if i run all of this again
i get for speed let's try this again now for speed i get 75 and for hash scales
i get false the arguments we have set in here
and this is especially if you are starting with objects probably going to
be really confusing but the one thing that makes all of this work is the order
of the indent methods we are first calling this one here this is number one
then we are looking at the monster which is this one here this init method
is number two then and then finally we are looking at the second item in the
inheritance which is the fish this for shear so this init method is called
third and we always need
the super init method to go to the next item
and what we would want to add in here as well
is a super and then dander init method for the fish
as well so if there's going to be another item in the list of inheritance
or in the mro we would also call that one
and for that reason you very often see super init in most classes because it
enables inheritance to work across multiple classes
and well i hope you can still follow along this is getting quite complicated
and it is just going to get worse because right now we do have one problem
and that is that this speed here and the hair scales
are constant right now but i want to be able to set them
dynamically when i am creating the shark meaning what i want to do when i create
a shark i want to set this speed
let's set it to 120 and i want to set has scales to
false and this would then be all the stuff i
have for the shark and i think it makes sense to put all of this on separate
lines to make it a bit easier to read all right but now if i run this
we are getting an error that shark init got unexpected keyword argument speed
basically what pipeline is complaining about that this speed and this has
scales don't exist in the parameters for the
init method of the shark class we can fix that by adding a speed
and has scales in here if i run this now this is going to work
but we're not doing anything with either the speed or the hass scales we are
still up here setting the speed and has scales as
constant numbers and now we kind of have a problem
because if i try to in this superintendent method at this speed and
has scales then let me fix the typo first if i run
this now we are getting the other problem that
monster.init down here is the error we're getting
right now monster.init takes three positional
arguments but three were given meaning
python in the monster class wants three arguments self health and energy
and those we do get let minimize the fish for now so we can see what's going
on we are getting health and energy and
this is what this init method wants but besides that now we are also adding
speed and has scales and for this the init method doesn't have any parameters
so python is very unhappy because it gets too many arguments and it doesn't
know what to do with them but this is a problem for us
because we need those two arguments to pass into the init method for the fish
but the init method of the monster doesn't have as many parameters so we
have a problem here and to overcome this we need one special
concept and that in python is called keyword unpacking
and basically what it means is in my monster class
after i have added all of the parameters i definitely know i need
i want to add star star and then keyword arguments
and that way any argument i get after the parameters i am going to store those
in a separate dictionary let me actually print what we get so i
want to print my keyword arguments without the stars
for now and for these double stars python is
expecting keyword arguments so all of the arguments for the init method here
need to be keyword arguments meaning health.health energy is energy
speed is speed and has underscore scales is has scales
and now if i run this we are getting a dictionary with speed
and has scales and this faults here we are getting from
printing shark has scales let me remove that and try this again now
so now we can focus on just a dictionary and that is something really useful
because this we could use in here now and essentially what you have to do is
call the unpacking operator again and passing in the keyword arguments
and now if i run this again we are still getting the same dictionary
so we are getting speed and we're getting hash scales
what happens now if we are calling this star again
it turns each key value pair inside of this dictionary into a named argument
meaning this speed under 20 is going to become a named argument
and then this we are passing into the init method of the next class in the
method resolution order and with that if i now print
shark dot
speed and actually display what we get
i now get 120 the one we have specified in here
and this is how you would work with this now for an actual example you would add
a lot more quarks to all of these classes for example the fish would also
have double star and keyword arguments and
then you would pass this into the init method as well so in here
quarks as well now in this case
the keyword arguments is going to be empty if i print it keyword arguments
and run this we're getting an empty dictionary
because we don't have any additional named arguments that we have to worry
about so this dictionary here is going to be empty well this dictionary
actually but if we had more named arguments they
would all go in there and this is then how you would deal with
multiple inheritance and if again you are just starting with
inheritance this really isn't something you want to
worry about too much probably if you're watching this for the
first time and you're still struggling with objects in general this is going to
be way too much i would recommend just practice objects
and simple inheritance for now and once you are more comfortable with
them come back to this this sort of inheritance is only really
something you are going to see once you get much more advanced
especially for making games or for making gui's you probably don't need any
of this whatsoever all of the games i have made so far have
never used multiple inheritance they all use simple inheritance and they worked
just fine but well at this point we have covered
all the main parts of classes i guess at this point there is some more
smaller things i do want to cover but they're all going to be fairly simple so
let's talk about them in the next section
alright for this part i want to talk about some extra parts for classes and
those are things i couldn't really fit in in any of the other sections but
they're all fairly simple but they can be quite useful
and well let's do all of this straight in
code i think that's going to be the easiest
all right once more we have the monster class and this is just something i want
to use to illustrate what we are going to do
and let me create an instance of this monster with monster and for the health
i want 20 for the energy i want 10. it really doesn't matter what number we go
with here and now there are three things i want to
cover the first one is private attributes
the second one is has utter and set utter
and the third one is going to be the dog string
and once we have those we are basically done with classes
and the first one is going to be private attributes which is just going to be an
attribute inside of a class that cannot be influenced from outside of the class
which may be something like an id number that you really want to make sure of
cannot be changed from outside of the class to be sure that it doesn't mess
with some other code and this actually isn't possible in
python we are always able to change the attribute of a class
so python developers came up with something else
and this let me copy this comment here and in the init method of the monster
class i want to create
a private attribute and how you would do this is first add
an underscore and then the name of the attribute let's say in this case i want
to have an id and the number i want here could be 5
but it could be anything it really doesn't matter
and now this id by convention is not supposed to be changed
but this is just a convention basically what you do with this format
is you tell other developers that this attribute should not be worked on but
you totally could work on it for example what i can do i can print
monster and then underscore id and i get 5
meaning you can work with it but there's a very clear indicator that you
shouldn't so if you ever work with somebody else and they added something
like this you probably should not change it
and well that is all you need to know about private attributes you could do
the same thing for methods you are essentially following a naming scheme so
this works with both attributes and methods
all right next up we have has utter and set utter and what those two are doing
is they allow us to check if a class has an attribute and we can also use it to
set an attribute and the first one is going to be has
utter and that is just going to be a normal python function
and this one wants two arguments it first of all wants to have an object
and besides that it wants a string with an attribute name
and let's try this one i want to look at my monster
and for my monster i want to check if the monster has health
and this is then going to return a boolean that either says true or false
meaning i can print all of this and i get true so this monster has the
attribute health if i check for something that doesn't
exist let's say a weapon i get faults because the monster doesn't have a
weapon and
this you could then use an if statement for example if has utter monster health
and if it has health i want to print the monster has
and i guess then we can use an f string monster dot health
and that is terrible spelling and let's turn this into an f string
and add health at the end
and now we run this the monster has 20 health and that is what we have set here
and this is has utter it's a really useful way to check if a certain class
has an attribute you are going to use this fairly often actually it's a really
useful function and besides that set utter works in kind
of the same way so let me call it set utter
and in here we need three arguments first of all we need an object
then we need a string of an attribute name let's call it attribute again
and then we have to set a new value and this could be a string it could be a
number it's really up to you i guess let's say again i want to look
at my monster the attribute i want to set is a weapon
and for the value let's give the monster a sword
and now i can print monster.web
pin and i get sword
and this set utter is basically the same thing as calling monster dot weapon
and setting this to sword these two things essentially do the same
thing and now you might be wondering why do we
have this kind of redundancy that this is
kind of pointless at least seemingly that we have this entire function that
does something very obvious but the reason for it that this allows
us to very efficiently create new attributes
for example what we could be doing let me
comment those two out and i could run a for loop
and let me add a let's call it new ad reviews
and this is going to be a tuple with lists
i want to have for example a weapon and there i can have an x
besides that i want to have another list with let's say
armor and the armor could be a shield
and finally i want to have one more list and this could be
potion i could set something like mana or
whatever you want to go for and now
i can use that as a for loop so
for attribute and
value in new attributes i can call set utter
i can pass in my monster in here and then i want my attribute
and my value and if i run this
we are not getting an error which is a good sign and now i can print
my vars for the monster
and i get the new weapon the new armor and the new potion
and this way you can set a lot of new attributes and
values for class by using this if you just used monster.weapon this one
here this would not be possible and this is why set utter exists
although you probably would want to create all of these attributes when you
actually create the object itself so this isn't something you want to do too
often although in some situations it can be really useful
alright with that we have set utter and has utter
and finally we have doc
and doc is just there to explain what your object does
that's really just about it you are getting doc or the doc's string
to be more specific by calling monster and then dunder dock
and in this case if i run this we get none
for the simple reason that we have to create a dock string for our object
and this you do first thing in the object and all you do
in here is you set a triple quotation mark like this
and then in there you are setting what you want for the monster for example i
could write in here a monster that has some
attributes and i am really bad at spelling monster
for some reason and now if i run this print again
and now i get a monster that has some attributes
and this you could make significantly longer depending on what kind of class
you have but this is usually what you want to set to explain your code to
other people and especially if you work in a team
with much larger projects it's really helpful to set something like this
because well somebody else might have no idea what you're talking about
what you can also do is let me comment out this print
statement here and instead call help and i want to look at my monster
if i run this i am getting a long list of different
things and in here i can see lots of useful
things for example i can see
monster and its parameters i can see the dog string
and i can see all of the methods inside of it
and if you just find a new object you don't really know much about the help
function is really useful as a matter of fact
you can also pass normal python code in here for example
what i could pass in here is just str for string and now python gives me the
help function for strings and if i go all the way to the top
there you can see basically that we have another object
and the object takes one argument which is going to be a string
then we have the dog string and this one explains what this object does
and afterwards we have all of the methods and there are quite a few
because strings are very complex objects
and with that we have covered objects and classes i hope that wasn't too
difficult but this is definitely something you do want to practice
so hope that was helpful and i will see you around in this part we are going to
be talking about modules this is the part where python really becomes
powerful so let's talk about it essentially modules are just extra parts
that we can attach to our programs for example if we wanted random numbers
we would add the random module that's basically what it is
there are quite a few modules that we can use that come with python by default
and random is the one you are probably going to use the most but i will cover a
few more in just a bit besides that we can also create our own
modules to make our code more organized and each module would be in a separate
file which makes it really easy to organize larger programs which is
something we're also going to cover in just a bit
but the much more important part is to use modules for extra functionality and
let's start with that one and in here we have two different
options we can either import from the python
standard library all this really means is that these modules come with python
when we install python so we can just import them and then work with them it's
super easy besides that we can also import additional modules
made by other people but those we have to install on our computer first
these modules here can become incredibly important for example if we want to make
games or work with machine learning or do data analysis or run databases
we would basically install additional modules to make all of this work
but let's not get ahead of ourselves and let's start with the python standard
library and by just talking about basic modules
here we once again have a completely empty python file and what i want to
create is a random number the problem we have is that there's no
way so far to create random numbers but we can do it by importing a module and
this we do with the import command and then the name of the module and the
module we want here is called random and this one is giving us random numbers i
think the name makes sense here and random has lots of different sub modules
that we could be using and the way you would access them is
first the name of the module and then the methods inside of it and one here
is called randint which is standing for random integer and
this is just a method we can call it although this one is expecting two
arguments a minimum and a maximum number but once i have those two i can print
the random number and now if i run this i get different
random numbers every time i'm executing this code and now you might be wondering
how do you know what else is inside of the random module and that's a really
good question usually what you do is you just google
the module and then you find lots of information for example for random
we have a whole documentation that is actually incredibly extensive so all of
the stuff in here would be part of the random module
the one we have seen already is random.rentend
and all it does is it creates a random integer between two numbers and this is
a function you are using all the time it is really popular
another one that you are seeing fairly often is choice
and this one picks a random item from some kind of sequence this could be a
list it could be a dictionary something like that and let's actually implement
this one here i'm back in the code and i want to create a test list
and for this test list i just want to have a couple of numbers it really
doesn't matter i guess let me put the print on top and
now i want to select one item from this list
and for that i would get my random again and i would add choice
and now this choice is expecting one argument and that is the list so test
list in here and now all i have to do is print the
result and let me comment out this stuff up
here so we're not getting confused and if i run this we get different items
from this list i guess to make it a bit more visually
appealing let's add a few different data types in
here this one is looking better so now if i
run this we get all of the different values
and that is in the most basic sense how you would be using modules
and there are a lot of different modules that come with python already
if you look this up online you are going to find this list calling the python
standard library and those are all of the modules that
come with python and in here we have a lot of different
options that we could be working with for example the one i'm seeing right now
is called tkinter and this is the most common way to create guise or graphical
user interface in python it basically gives you buttons
besides that we also have a ton of modules that work with the internet
and if i go up a bit more we can see i hope i find it there should
be random in here somewhere
there we go there is random and there are quite a few more modules that we
could use with numbers chances are you are only ever going to
see a very small part of all of these modules
even i have only ever used a very small part of them
for example i have no idea what rl completer is i have never used it even
once but some modules in here are incredibly
useful and you do want to have a basic awareness of them
and you basically learn all of them by just using python and then discovering
more and more of them now if you want to import multiple modules you can do it in
two ways you could either on another line import
something again let's say what i could also import is
the string module and what this one does let me comment
this one out i could for example print string and in
here i could print the s key underscore lowercase
and be aware this is not a method this is just an attribute and if i run this
i get all the lowercase letters of the alphabet that's really it string is a
very simple module if you are importing two modules just
like that to save a bit of space you can put all of this on the same line like
this and
then i can get rid of the second line run all of this again and we get the
same output the random module would still work just fine
i guess one more module that we could be looking at that you do see fairly often
is called math and this one is giving us a few more advanced math functions
for example what we could do in here is print math dot sign curve
and add like a 1 in here and if you have no idea what this means don't worry too
much about it it's just a sine curve not something you use too often unless you
are doing some fairly specific tasks i suppose a more common operation for math
would be floor and this one gives us the floor of an
integer meaning if i have
4.9 this one is giving me 4.
we are basically just rounding down that's all that's happening in here and
with that we have a couple more modules now there are a few more things you can
do with the import statement and those are mostly to be more specific in terms
of what you import for example for my math
i only want to import math.floor and nothing else
and if that is the case you can just type from math
import floor and this way we are only importing floor
and we don't have to worry about the math part in front of it
meaning now when i'm calling it down here i can remove it and call floor like
any other function oh and let me get rid of the comma all the way up here that
shouldn't be there now if i run this
we get the same outcome and this flow now works like any other python function
if you really wanted to you could also rename this floor
function and this you would do by adding s and then the name
and you could name this any valid python name i could for example call it get
floor and then this one here would be get
underscore floor and there we go same outcome
i guess what you would mostly do in here is to shorten method names if they get
too long for example i could shorten this to f
and this would then save me quite a bit of writing
and some modules do get very long so this isn't actually as rare as you would
think it is and finally there's one more thing that
we can do let's say for this random here i want to
use all of the methods but i don't really want to write this random at the
beginning every single time and to achieve that we would use from
random again but now when we import individual
modules we are typing a star and this tells python we want to import
every single method and function from the random module and then use it in our
code and this allows us to use all of them without writing random first
really now i can run this and i still get the same outcome although this you
really don't want to overdo because if you import all of it you are well
importing all of it and this could add a ton of functions and methods and
variables that you don't want to use and that could clutter up your program but
alright with that we have covered the basics of modules and let's do an
exercise and this is going to involve a bit of
research on your part what i want you guys to do is to get the current time
from the date time module so do some google research and try to
figure out how to get this it should be doable in a single line of code
i guess two lines of code if you include the importing part as well but pause the
video now and try this one yourself
i suppose the best way to start this is by doing the research ourselves
here again we have the website with the python standard library and what i'm
looking for it's already in here i am looking for date time the module
and this i get here if i click on it i get a lot more information
and in here if you scroll down you can find a ton of different things
it's actually quite an extensive module but i'm just looking for one specific
thing i hope i can find it for example here we would have today
that is kind of useful but i want to find the current time
and the current time i
can find
ah in here class method daytime now this is what i was looking for and this gives
me the current time now you obviously didn't know that this
one even existed so this probably took you a bit more googling but most of the
time this is how you discover new modules you just google a problem then
you in some form find a new module and this solves most of your issues
that's basically how everybody learns python or any programming language in
general let's implement it here i'm back in the
code i want to import date time although day time is a bit weird because
what we have to do is from date time import date time
and what that means is inside of the date time module we have
one object called datetime they just happen to have the same name
which can be kind of confusing but well it is what it is
and i guess just to be a bit fancy here let's abbreviate it as dt
and now to get the current time i need my datetime dot now
and this i can just print
and if i run the code now i get lots of stuff let me comment out
all of this and now i get my current date and my current time down
to some nanoseconds with that we have covered all the basics
of modules meaning if you got so far you already
have a pretty good understanding although you can do quite a bit more and
that is going to be the next part in this part we are going to cover
external modules and external modules are just modules
that are made by other programmers and this is giving us a ton of extra
functionality for example
any kind of game development any kind of data analysis machine learning graphical
user interface and a lot more is essentially just a module made by
somebody else and we are using these functionalities and this is one of the
really strong parts of python there is a very active community that makes a lot
of extra modules that you can use for your own projects
almost all of them are free there are some very select ones that are being
paid those are usually more business oriented ones that you don't have to
worry about and these modules are imported like the standard modules the
only difference is that these modules have to be installed on your computer
first and this can be done in a couple of ways the most common one is in the
powershell or the terminal now what does that mean
the powershell is for windows and the terminal is for mac os and both are
command line interfaces and what a command line interface is is
simply a way to interact with your computer simply by typing text if you
ever watched any kind of old movies those always use command line interfaces
where people just write commands into computer there are no buttons no windows
you just write text into your computer and this is what we are doing here as
well and this is the way python is intended
to be used it's honestly the easiest way and sounds way more complicated than it
actually is but let's actually have a look at this
and let's start with windows both versions are identical bar a very minor
difference now for windows you just have to open
the start menu and type powershell and if you press enter you can see
something like this let me full screen it
and this is a command line interface for windows
and in here i can type a ton of commands to make windows do
something in my case i only want to do some very
specific things and what i want to do
is to type pip and install and then the module i want
to go for and pip is the python package manager
meaning this is what we are using to install any kind of external module and
the module i want to install now is called pi
auto gui and now all you have to do is press
enter and python is installing a bunch of different things there really isn't
that much we have to do ourselves but at the end you can see successfully
installed pi out to gui and then the version name
and that is basically all you have to do although i guess there are a few more
things i do want to cover in here one command that i found really useful
is called clear and this one clears the entire interface so things are a bit
cleaner and one more thing that can be useful is
called pip list and this one gives you all the modules
that are being installed and your list should be a good bit shorter than mine
but you can install a ton of different things here and finally if you want to
uninstall a module you will just run pip uninstall
and in my case i want to uninstall pi or to gui
then python would ask us if we want to
proceed i want to with yes and now it's uninstalled
now i can clear all of this again and since i do want to use pi to gui i
want to install it again and this could be a good exercise for you so install pi
or to gui yourself again and see how far you get
all we need is pip install pi or to gui if i type this we get all of this again
and we have installed pi or to gui and that is pretty much all we needed and
now that we have that let's do the same thing for mac os
you open all of your programs and in there you type terminal
once you do that you're getting a new window and let me maximize it
in here if you hold the apple key and plus you can increase the font size
which i really want to do you might not need it
and in here we can work with mac os using commands
just like in windows i could type commands here to control
mac os
obviously not like that but you get the idea
for example clear works just in the same way most commands do actually the one
minor difference here is we do not type pip install and the module
instead we would be writing pip 3 install and then the module
the only difference here is the free the rest stays identical
d3 here is needed because on mac os python comes pre-installed the problem
is the python version is really old and when we installed python on the mac we
installed a separate version of python and this three is to tell python that we
want to use the latest one which is python 3 we do not want to use the
original python but that is the only difference so in my
case i want to install pi auto gui i press enter
now python is doing a thing and at the end
we get successfully installed pi auto gui and
if you notice here this is the same version we have on windows
and with that we are good to go inside of our code editor there's not going to
be a single difference so let's have a look at that
alright here we are back in my python file and i'm using windows but this is
going to work both with mac and with windows the installing part was the only
difference between the operating systems but now i have pi out to gui so i want
to import it so import pi or to gui and what this module is doing is it
automates windows to a certain extent for example what you could be doing is
to move the mouse around or to write some text from your computer with python
and i guess let's get started with that now that we have pi out gui i just want
to call the entire module and then right and now and here i can tell it to write
some text for example this is written by a
computer and now if i would run this code we
would have this typed out although right now this would be kind of awkward
because i have no time to switch to another program like a text editor
meaning i want to import another module from the python standard library or
another part of a module and this is called from time import sleep
and all that sleep does is it pauses our code for a certain time interval
let's say i want to call sleep and one second
and now let me bring in a text editor
and let me run the code switch back and now we have this is written by a
computer the text you have just seen was just written by python not by me
i suppose to make the effect a bit more noticeable
is for this method here we can add another argument or a named
argument to be more specific and this is called interval
and in my case let's go with 0.5 probably a bit long let's say 0.25
and this is the interval duration between each letter that is being typed
out i guess let me write it again and switch back to the text editor and
now you can see this is written by a computer just very very slowly
i guess what you also could do is run the code itself
and now python is writing this code by itself in sublime this is also working
just fine prior to gui doesn't care where it's
writing it just starts typing these letters
let me get rid of them and with that we have one module
the only difference to standard modules is we are first installing it via pip
and then we're using it like any other module
and the main task for you is to understand what each module is doing and
for that you usually find documentations online
let's actually have a look at the one for pi auto gui
it is looking like this and if you scroll around here you can
find a ton of different things you could do
for example you could move your mouse you could add a click you could add a
double click you could write you could press a button
there are a ton of things you can do with pi or to gui it's a really fun
module and well this is then bringing us to the
exercise bit and what i want you guys to do is to do
a bit more research and what that means is create a graph
from any of the examples below
i should type these things out more but essentially here you have a link to a
website if i copy this and open the website
you can see a tutorial for pipelot in the matplotlib module and this is the
standard module you would use for data analysis it basically makes nice looking
graphs and i want you guys to look at any of
these examples and try to understand what is happening
or well you first have to install maploid lib and then you can follow any
of these examples so try to do that install the map.lib
module and try to copy or understand any of these examples it's entirely up to
you which one maybe go for something slightly more
complex this could be a really good challenge for you
i want to work on the simplest example here because i want to keep the video
short and the first thing we have to do is to
install matplotlib so once again
for windows i want the powershell let me maximize it
i guess let me clear this one first so it's a bit easier to read
and now what i have to do is pip install matte plot
lip and if i run this we have to install
quite a few different things this is going to take a second and we have
successfully installed map.lib 3.5.2 and if you are working on a mac this
would be pip 3 install matplotlib now that we have that let's return to
the code and in here let's comment out
all of this and we have to figure out how to import
mapp.lib and let me bring in the reference from
the site let's put it here this is good for reference
on the first line we have to import map.lib.pipelot
as plt when we're importing map.lib we are not importing all of it we're just
getting one subpart of it pipelot and we are renaming this to plt because typing
is hard so i want import mad plot
lib dot pi plot
as plt and now after the exercise
i have to create a plt dot plot and this one wants a list with a couple
of numbers in the example it's one two three and four
and once you have that you can already run this program and you're running this
with plt dot show meaning if i run this now
we are getting a graph the one you can see on the right besides the y labels
and in here you can change the numbers quite easily for example i could add 10
0 100 and if i run this again
we get a very different looking graph all that the plot method really wants is
the list of numbers and then it puts them into a line chart
and what we also see in the example is plt dot y
label and all this one really does is it adds
a label on the y axis so some numbers in this case on the example
and i guess let's copy it one to one we have some numbers
for the y axis to be a bit more specific
now if we run this we have some numbers for the y axis
we can also do the same thing for the x-axis if you really want to and this
you get with plt dot x-label and then we have some number for the
x-axis if i run this we can see at the bottom now we have
some numbers for the x-axis and that would be matplotlib or at the
very least a really basic introduction to map.lib
map.lib is a really complex module that can visualize data in a ton of different
ways so if you want to learn it it is going to take you quite some time
all right with that we have external modules so the last part for modules is
to create our own or at this part we are going to create our own custom modules
and the one question you might be having is why would you want to do that
and the answer primarily is organization that you are creating modules and each
module is in a separate file and that way you just never have too much stuff
in one file which really helps organizing your code
so far we just never really needed it but later on when we have thousands of
lines of code this becomes incredibly useful to not get lost on your own
program that being said you don't have to do it but it's a really good idea to
do that i guess let's implement all of this and that should explain it the best
all right here once again we have a completely empty python file
now since we are working with multiple files i want to be able to switch
between them and the best way for that is using tabs
so in sublime i'm pressing alt and then i can see all of the menu options
you could get the same result by pressing f11
and then you get this menu item here and you can select different things
and in my case i want to in view show tabs
and then i can see the different tabs i've opened right now only one
and let me return to full screen so it looks a bit cleaner and now this module
is only going to import the stuff from another module meaning i have to create
another python file with control n and this one i want to save so if i click on
save i can save this to whatever i want let's call this one my
module and this is still going to be a python file
and now i save this and now i have two files open that i can switch between
although right now both are completely empty and let's start in mymodule.pi
in here for the simplest possible example
i just want to create a test variable and this could have any value let's say
test and now this module i want to import in
my custom modules python file and this happens in the normal way
i first have to import my underscore module and this should not
be capitalized and if you run this and you don't get an
error this is looking pretty good and now that you have that you can use
this module like any other module for example in our case i can run my
module and then in my module i have a test var
let me copy it i can print this and i get test
this is also going to work with functions and with classes for example i
could create a test underscore function and then here we could even add some
parameters and let's say i just want to print
this is an imported
function with the
parameter and then parameter
and now this function i can also use inside of my main module
meaning i want my module dot test underscore function
and the argument i want to pass in here let's say is one two three
and if i run this now we are getting an error the name parameter is not defined
and oh the reason is that the parameter and this parameter here have different
names this one should be content
and now if we execute the code we get this is an imported function with the
parameter one two and three so this one is working just fine
finally what you can also do let me do it below the function
i can create a class called my class
added here you can run init
with self and give it a self.name let's call it my app
and we can call self.value i don't know 12.
and this can also have a method it's literally like any other class let's
call it do something it needs self and nothing else and then
here i just want to print hello so once again super simple class
that we now are able to import in the main file
actually what i can do if i hold ctrl and click on my module
i can see both files side by side which is quite handy
and while looking at this i realized that this has the wrong naming scheme
this should be my class in fact now looking at this this feels
like a really bad name let's rename it to test
and now i can call test and mymodule.test
and don't forget the brackets now i can run test dot do
something and if i run this we get hello
meaning this
module test here refers to
this class test and this do something refers to this do something here
and later on you are really going to appreciate having more files with less
code in each individual file it makes it much easier to work with
but i guess let's do an exercise and what i want you guys to do is to
create a some calculator function
that takes unlimited
arguments and returns the sum and create it here and run it
in the main file so pause the video now and
create this one function import it to the main file and then run
it there
all we have to do is create another function
and let's call this one sum calculator and in here i want to have one parameter
that i called nums but i want to be ready for unlimited
arguments so this i want to unpack and now inside of the function all i
want to do is to return the sum of these nums
and that is literally it now that i have that
i can i guess we can be a bit more fancy here let's say from my module i want to
import the sum cal q later and again this is working exactly the
same way compared to what we have seen before with the external or the python
standard modules and now that i have that some calculator
and i can add one two three four and five
run this and we don't get anything because we're
just returning something we are not printing it
so let's print it and there we go we get 15.
and with that we are pretty much good to go for modules although there is one
more topic we do have to cover that is going to be quite short though
when you are creating your own python modules there's one really important
concept you have to understand and that is called thunder main
all this one really means is when a python file is called it creates a
couple of internal variables and than the main is one of them it is
in fact the most used one essentially what it does is it gives a
name to the current python file and the one that we are executing is
always called thunder main but any imported file is called dunder
and then the file name and this is really useful to control
what code is being executed and more importantly to avoid executing code by
accident here is the example from the last video
and in my main file i want to print dunder
name both in my main file
and in the one i am importing
and if i run the code now i get done domain all the way at the end and all
the way at the top i get my module i guess let me comment out all of the
other print statements that is going to make it easier to read
now if i run this we get two print statements we have my module and main
and what happens internally is python first
runs all of this imported code here and what it gets at the end is print
name so it prints my module
and this my module is the same as the name my module up here
this is the name of the file and after that we are printing in the
main file then the name and then we are getting done domain
and the reason why this is called main instead of the file name we get up here
is that this is the file we are currently executing
if i just looked at my module so this one here and run this again
and we are getting main here because right now we are executing my module
which turns this one into the main file and this is being used usually with an
if statement and you're looking for if dunder name
is equal to thunder main only if that is the case let's say i
want to print the main file this
makes sure you're only running this code if this is actually the file you are
executing and most of the time when you have
multiple files like in this case all of the actual code is inside of this
if statement if you have other kinds of code let's
say for this one here for my mymodule.pi i would add the same if statement
this one here and then the print statement would be
inside of it if i executed my custom module i would
only get the main file this one here and inside of my module this one here
would not be executed and this way if you have this if
statement for every single file you have a lot of control about what is
getting executed when you are importing the file which can be incredibly handy
in this entire section we are going to cover some extra topics now i do want to
be clear here basically all of these parts are very
useful but not that common especially for beginners the longest video in here
are decorators and error handling as a beginner you are not going to encounter
them or use them basically at all meaning at least for now it's perfectly
fine to skip this entire section and return later
it is probably a good idea for you to practice basic python and then explore
these areas especially decorators can get really really complicated and if
you're just getting started you are not going to use them anyway so you might as
well skip them at the very least for the beginning
that being said i do want to cover them because i want to cover all of python
and first of all i want to cover two very simple topics that i would
recommend you to check out and those are called pass and input
all that pass really does is it tells python to not do anything
this does seem kind of pointless and basically you would only use it if you
have a function but no content yet so maybe you have a function with a good
name but you don't yet have good content for the function so you have to fill it
with something and you would use a pass for that
besides that we have input this is another function that can get user input
although you are hardly ever going to use it i'll talk about it in just a
second but it really isn't as useful as it sounds
so inside of a python file let's say i have a function that is really
important function
name with whatever parameters you have
and for this function you don't have content yet you don't really know what
to do with it or at least you're prototyping it but you do want to keep
the function by itself but if you're doing this without any content and run
the code you are going to get an error because python expected an indented
block after function defined on line one so python needs to have something in
here and for that you could just add pass and
now everything works just fine so pass is basically telling python to
not do anything and well not doing anything is something
you usually don't have to define though this past you hardly ever see anything
productive it's pretty much only there to cover some kind of content where you
don't have content yet it's a filler essentially
now besides that we have input let's say i want to get some kind of
user input and for that we would need input and now
in here we can use this kind of like print for example i could print to the
user press a
button and whatever the user is going to press
is going to be stored inside of this user input
however there is going to be a problem because if i am running all of this we
can see press a button however if i keep on pressing a button i keep on typing in
subtime the issue here is sublime does not
support input for that we would have to run this
python script inside of the powershell or the terminal and how this is going to
work let me print the user input at the end so we can tell
what's going on and really importantly do save the file
what i want to do now is to run this script inside of the powershell or the
terminal and let me put this on a separate screen
so here we have the powershell and here i have the folder with my python file
that i have just created and if you want to run this what you
have to do is you first have to type hyphen to run a python command
and then you need the file path towards this folder here let me show my mouse
actually
inside of the terminal you can add a ton of commands to navigate to folder
structure the thing is that's kind of complicated and you don't need it all
you really have to do is to drag the file in there and then you get the rest
automatically so this is all you really have to do just drag and drop the file
don't forget the python at the beginning but other than that
all you have to do is press enter and now you get press a button exactly
what we have specified inside of the python file and now i can press this is
my input
and if i now press enter i get this is my input
and after that the code finishes and we can add another kind of input for
example we could add clear in here and we are done
and that's really how you run files inside of the powershell or in windows
in general and welcome back in this part we are going to cover error handling and
well for this part we are going to handle some errors
which means obviously your code should not contain
any errors because that would crash your program and that would be bad
the issue is sometimes you can't really avoid having some errors
for example you might try to find a file and it just doesn't exist and you don't
notice in advance and as a consequence you want to have
the ability to anticipate and deal with errors
and fortunately python can deal with that quite easily there are quite a few
different ways to do it actually and let's jump straight into the code
and let's have a look at all of this alrighty here we have an empty python
file and let's just create an error just to get started i want to print one
divided by zero and if i run this we're going to get an
error we have a zero division error that we are dividing by zero and this is not
allowed because math doesn't like it so what could we do to overcome this or
rather how can we make python try some code snippet and then do something else
if we get an error and well the command is literally called
try and this works kind of like an if
statement except without any arguments we're just telling python try this line
of code here if it works cool if not we want to do something else and the else
here is called accept and inside of that i can print something
else let's literally write something else
and now if i run this we get something else
what happened here is that python first went with try and the code in there was
this print statement and this print statement included the
operation 1 divided by 0 which is not possible as
a consequence this here gave us an error and because of that
we are going to accept and inside of that we are printing something else
and this is what we got in the end as well
if i had valid code inside of the try statement let's say 1 divided by 1
we will get the result of this line of code here and accept would not be run
and that is the easiest way to deal with errors in python however we can both be
more specific and we can add more things towards this
and let's be more specific first and that is for this except statement we
can specify specific errors that we are looking for
for example what we are looking for right now is a zero division error
and if i run this we are getting the same outcome
however now if i add another print statement and i print a variable that
doesn't exist yet which if i run this
is giving us another kind of error specifically a name error
and we are right now only dealing with zero division errors so when python sees
a name error it doesn't know what to do with it
but well we can account for it by adding another except statement
and now we want to look for a name error and if
that is the case i want to print let's say does not exist
and now if we run this we get does not exist
and be aware what happens here python starts all the way at the top with try
and then it goes through these lines of code here and we are starting with print
a and this one doesn't exist and as a
consequence none of the stuff below is executed and we jump immediately
to this name error and in there we are printing does not exist which is what we
are getting down here now one important thing you may have
noticed is that let me actually get rid of it
this print here which should have given us
this accept statement is not being printed down here in the
console meaning that this here wasn't even
executed it's really important to understand as soon as try finds any
error any code after that is not being executed
which is why we only ever get one except statement or the result of one except
statement to be more specific and if you happen to be interested in
all the possible errors that could happen in python there is a whole
documentation online and in here you can find for example arithmetic error buffer
error lookup error assertion error lots of different things that could be
raised so if you are looking for some specific
errors that could come up this list here would be really useful what you want to
look for is build in exceptions there are two more things that we can do
one is else and the other is finally and let's start with else that one is
well it's basically an else statement that you should know from the if
statement let's say in here i can just print
let's say the else statement and if i run this right now this else
statement is not run because we do have an error this name error here
specifically but
if i run some code in here that does exist
let's say print try if i run this now
we get the code inside of the try statement and we are getting the else
statement as well but the else statement is only run
if the try statement doesn't have an error
the way you have to think about it is that this else is an else to these
except statements and finally we have well finally and
finally runs whenever all of this stuff finished and
it runs either way it doesn't matter if we have an exception or not
let me print finally
and if i run this now we get finally again and this is going to happen
let me run the zero division error again this finally even comes when we have
this division error here i guess i should rename these things a bit more
properly you cannot divide by
zero and now let's run this again this looks
better what is happening in the code right now
we first number one start with the try part up here
and inside of that on this line here we're getting an error
and this leads us to the exception error for zero division error
and in there we are printing you cannot divide by zero
which is this part here number two and finally
we are ending on finally which is number three
and this finally runs no matter what happens
and with that we have covered how to handle exceptions
although there's one really interesting topic and that is you can raise your own
error let me actually add comments here to
make this example a bit clearer this part here what we covered so far is
anticipating errors or to be more specific exceptions
what we can also do is raising exceptions
ourselves and what i want to do in here for the example is i want to create a
variable that must be a string
and for now let's give it a string let's
call it test string it really doesn't matter what the string here is
and now what i want to do is to run an if statement that if this variable
contains a string i want to continue as normal
if that is not the case i want to raise an exception or well call an error same
thing and for that we first of all need an if
statement and to check the type of a variable we
need is instance and in here i want to check my var must
be string and the second argument is the string type or the type we want to look
for which in my case is string and if that is the case the variable is
all good and let's say i want to print must be string
and let me comment out the earlier part and run this code and this is working
indeed because a var must be string is a string indeed or it contains a string
however now if that is not the case i want to raise an error and this you do
with raise and then the type of error you want to raise in my case i want a
type error and in here i can add a message as well
as the argument and in my case i want to write must be a string
if i run the code now nothing happens however if i change this string to
something else let's say an empty list now i get a type error must be a string
and that way with raise you can create your own errors to your heart's content
and along those lines there's another thing you can do to raise an exception
and that is called assert and assert basically means that you want
to make sure that your code only runs if a certain condition is true think of
assert as a stronger if statement that if this condition is false your entire
code stops with an error for example what you could do in here
let's do a simpler variable a is 5 and a always has to be 5. if a is not 5
i want to end all of the code immediately and this i do with assert
and in here i can just look for any kind of boolean statement meaning a is equal
to 5 and if i let me comment this part out
if i run this now we get nothing however if i change the value of a to 6
we are getting an assertion error and that is caused by this line here
and sometimes in your code you really want to make sure that a certain
condition is true especially if you work with something
more securely concerned this is something you really want to be using
extensively but well with that let me uncomment
all of this here as well if you understand these three parts you
basically know all you ever need to know about error handling it doesn't get that
much more complicated and that means we can do an exercise and
then call it a day and what i want you guys to do is to create a list and then
try to raise an index error and obviously account for this arrow as well
and type some kind of message with the print statement
also try to use else and finally and see how far you get
you might have to do some research online to find what an index error is
although i think it makes sense what it might be just try to guess
let me start by creating my list and in here i want to list with one two three
four and five the content really doesn't matter
and an index error basically means that you are trying to get an index that
doesn't exist for example i could get my list
and then get the index 99 which does not exist
i am getting a type error and the type error comes from here let me comment out
all of the earlier stuff so we can focus on one thing
now let's try this again and now we're getting an index error
and that is what i want to account for let me cut this one out and instead i
want to go with try and in here
i want to get my list 99 which i know does not exist right now
so i want to run and accept and i want to look for my index
error and if that is the case i want to print
that index does not exist and if i run this now
we get that index does not exist and no error message anymore
i guess with that we have covered the first two parts of the assignment
besides that i also want an else and finally let's start with else
and in here i just want to print that index exists
let's try it if i run it by itself we are getting that index does not exist
meaning this line here and we don't see else because else is only run if there's
no index error so
let's try to get the first index and let me print this one as well
now we get two and that index exists which is this print statement here and
this else statement and well finally we need finally and in
here i just want to print finished
and this one is the easiest it always runs we get finished either way if this
is working or if it is not
working and with that we have covered error messages it really is a fairly
simple topic and quite easy to cover in python
the main thing i suppose you have to learn is all the different types of
exceptions that you can have but if you play around with this a bit
it's getting quite natural so we are done with this one
hello there in this tutorial we are going to cover decorators which are is
somewhat more advanced topic in python so let's go over some theory first
in the most basic sense decorators are functions that decorate other functions
which does sound a bit cryptic but essentially what we do is we are
wrapping one function around another function
and let's do this a bit more visually to illustrate what's happening
this is a normal function and usually what you do is you just call it
somewhere and then you have something happening
what decorators do is we still have the normal function
but now we are putting another function around it
and then when we are calling all of this we are calling the decorator function
and inside of that decorator function we are calling the original function
and this is allowing us to execute code before and after the function
so when i'm calling this function here i could run code here and i could run code
here without making any changes to the original function
this function here would stay exactly the same all the
actual logic happens inside of the decorator
we are literally putting one function inside of another function and this
other function executes extra code that's the entire idea of a decorator
now why would you want to do this basically this way we can give extra
functionality to a function without changing it
a simple example here is we could write a decorator for a function and it makes
the function execute twice when called not the most useful function but we are
going to talk some more useful examples later on i just want to illustrate what
is happening now in practice you are seeing decorators in three different
circumstances let's go over them the most common one is you want to test
your code without changing it let's say you work in a team you have some really
complicated code and you want to test your code without making too many
changes a decorator would be excellent for that
the other example would be you are working in a team and you want to avoid
making unnecessary changes now those two points are pretty similar
you basically want to do something with your code without making too many
changes and both of these are also fairly
advanced if you are just learning python you are quite far away from either of
these which is why you may be struggling with decorators because you don't really
need them however there is a third case that you
probably are going to use and that is using a decorator inside of
a class because this allows you to run code when an attribute is accessed or
changed so for example let's say you have a
monster with health and every time that health is changed you want to run some
other function inside of the monster with a decorator doing this is fairly
easy although that being said decorators can be quite hard especially for
beginners because we are going to use some more advanced functionalities in
python that may be slightly confusing although i would really recommend you to
try to follow along because this is going to be really good practice to
understand functions and how to pass them around
in fact before we start with decorators we need to recap functions itself so
let's have a look at that here we have a completely empty sheet of
code and let's just get started with a really
basic function i want to define let's call it func
there are no arguments and inside of this function i just want to print
function just about the easiest function you can
write if i call this function i get function
so this really doesn't do all that much now there's a really important concept
you have to understand that right now we are calling the function here
and if we didn't do that so if i remove those brackets i could run this and
nothing would happen but what i could do is print the
function itself and now i get a function object
meaning this function here as the whole function not
what's being returned just the function itself and this is just going to be an
object if that doesn't tell you anything check
out my videos on object-oriented programming they should be quite helpful
but basically what this func is giving us is a simple
object that we can call and if we don't call it we are just getting a function
object still not particularly useful but what we can do with this function
object is pass it around like any other object like an integer like a string
like basically any other object we can pass it around for example what
we can do i can create another function
and this let's call it a wrapper because this one is supposed to take the
argument of the function and then i want to execute the function
itself meaning what i can do now i can call my wrapper function
and run this and i get function again
and what is happening in here i am calling this wrapper and i'm passing in
this function here what happens as a consequence
is this function is being passed as a parameter
into the wrapper function and inside of that function
we are calling this function and when we are calling it we are
printing the word function and now that we have that we could also
do something like print hello
and print
goodbye and if i run this now we are running the function inside of
another function and before and after we are calling it we are running some other
code and this is basically the main idea of a
decorator although it does get a bit more complicated
but we'll come to that in just a bit now there's one more thing that you can do
inside of a function and that is you can create a whole new
function so for example let me create another
function and let's call this one a function
generator and then here we have no arguments to
keep it simple and now inside of this function
generator i want to create a new function
and let's call this one new function i guess it's a good word
and in here i just want to print new
function and since this new function is just
going to be an object we can return the new function and what i can do with
that i can create a variable let's call it
new function and i want to get my function generator
and if i run this we can't see anything but now this new function is going to
have this new function in here meaning what i can do i can call my new
function execute it and we get new function
so just to go over this because it may be a bit confusing
this new function executes this one here
and what we are getting from this function generator
is we are defining a new function this one here
and at the end of the function we are returning this new function
and this we are capturing inside of this new function variable
and this new function variable now is just a function meaning we can call it
here and when we are calling it we are
getting this print statement that's really all that's happening here
the main thing you have to understand is we are basically passing around
functions with the return statement with that we have some function basics so now
we can actually start working on the decorator
and for that let me open up a new file and in here
i want to create an actual decorator now first of all for decorator we are
going to need a basic function we want to decorate
so for my function basics i want to copy this basic function here
which is just printing function by itself so if i run this we get function
literally the easiest function you can write more or less
and now for this function i want to create a decorator and this is
going to be another function that you can give whatever name you want let's
say i want to call this one decorator to keep things simple
and this decorator is going to accept one parameter which is going to be a
function so in just a bit we're going to pass this function
inside of this decorator what we are going to do with that inside
of this function we are going to create another function and let's call this one
the wrapper and this one right now doesn't have any
arguments but now inside of this function i want
to run the original function
and besides that i can do quite a few other things for example i could just
print the decoration
begins and let me write this properly and i can also write the decoration
ends and now after i have done that i can return this wrapper
and now what i can do i can create my
new function and this is going to be my decorator
and instead of this decorator i want to pass in my function
and once i have that i can just call my new function
and i get the decorator begins the function
and the decorator ends what is happening here let me go over
this this is probably a bit confusing we are starting with our basic function
and this function we are passing in here into the
decorator function and this is the one we have up here
and inside of this decorator function we are creating a whole new function this
bit here and inside of this function
we are calling the original function meaning this
one here and then around this function we are
doing some other stuff like we are printing these two statements here
and then at the end of all of this we are returning
this new function and this new function we are storing in the new function
variable and then we can just call it like any
other function and now we have extra functionality
around our original function now where this becomes really
interesting is let's say
somewhere later in the course i am running function by itself
which would just give me the word function
let me comment out these two lines here if i just run fung i get function and
nothing else and what i can do with decorators if i
uncomment those two lines and get rid of this new func
when i create the variable name for this i can just call it the same way like i
have called the original function so i can call both func
if i do that and run the code again i now have a new functionality for this
function because we are essentially overwriting
the original function name and that way our function
even with the same name has new functionality
and this is the basic idea of a decorator if we have this kind of system
we can have really complex code and still check our function without making
any changes to the code and since this is a reasonable common
operation python has a shorthand for it and let me comment out
this statement here and the shorthand looks like this i
first write an add and then the decorator function so in this case
decorator and now if i run all of this again
we are seeing the same outcome for the simple reason let me uncomment
it that this statement here
and this line here they are doing essentially the same thing
we are wrapping this function here inside of a decorator this one here
and let's go over this a bit more slowly i think that's going to be useful
here we have the function you have just seen
and you can wrap this in the traditional way by writing the function and then we
are putting the function inside of the decorator and then we are calling the
function i hope this is making sense if you're
confused about this i would recommend to pause the video now and just go over all
of these different statements and see how they connect
i guess i can go over it as well again we have this decorator here and inside
of this decorator we are passing in a function
and then we get this function here as a parameter
now inside of this function we are creating a whole new function and this
one is called wrapper and only inside of this function we are
calling the original function this one here and then around this function we
can do whatever we want like calling these two print statements here we could
also do lots of other things i'm going to cover that in just a second
and finally at the end what we are doing is we are returning this wrapper
function and this wrapper function we are storing right now in func
and then we can call it like any other function
and that way we're using the name of the function and overwrite it with this new
function that is being wrapped inside of the function
which means if i took out this line here the function would come back to its
original functionality and just print function
now the problem with that approach is that we are writing func three times one
two and three and if you want to call it a fourth time which is kind of annoying
so what python developers have done is to create a shorthand for this and this
is called a decorator and this one is looking like this
and basically
this line here where we have the name of the function a decorator and then the
function as an argument is the same as this add decorator those two lines are
doing the exact same thing meaning
when you are calling this function you have the same result
now obviously just printing two more statements isn't particularly useful so
let's actually do something more relevant to see why decorators can be
useful here we are back in the code and i want
to create another decorator and this one i want to call the duration
decorator and then here again as a parameter we
need the function and inside of that i want to create a
wrapper it doesn't need any arguments
and in here first of all i want to execute my function and then return the
wrapper and this is essentially a decorator that
doesn't do anything right now and what i want to do with it is to measure how
long it takes to execute this function here
and for that to work we need the time module
meaning i want to import time and now what i want to do inside of this
decorator i want to get my start time
and this i would get with time dot time and this has to run before i call the
function and after i have called the function
i want to get my duration and my duration is my time.time which is
my current time and from that i want to subtract my
start time and once i have that i can print
let's call it duration and this should be an f string
with the duration and now just to get some reasonable
numbers in here when i am calling the original function
i want to call time dot sleep and make it sleep for one second
and now with this duration decorator let me actually call it so duration
decorator i can now comment out this line here
and now if i run the code we get function and we get the actual duration
and from this line we know it took one point a tiny amount of time to execute
all of this and this now we could get without making
any changes anywhere else in the code we're just calling the function here we
have the wrapper up here and then we're adding this one line of code to add some
debugging functionality so this is something you could be doing if your
code is running very slow and you want to identify what is slowing it down
now another thing that i haven't covered yet is that you can combine different
decorators and this happens by just adding them with the different add
statements on top of each other and we already have another decorator so
let me call this original decorator and let's run all of this again
and now let me go through them i have decorator begins and decorator ends that
is what we are getting up here from this original decorator
besides that we have the duration of the decorator
and this is what we are getting from this print statement here
and the actual function so this print here
is this line meaning now even though we have a very
simple function by using decorators we can give it a ton more extra
functionality without making any changes to it
which is well the entire idea of a decorator if you understand this it can
be really useful in very specific circumstances although if you are a
beginner you probably just are going to add more stuff to this function although
well if you know decorators you don't have to
and this makes it much cleaner to work with your functions
but alright let's do another exercise on this
i want you guys to create another decorator that calls a function twice
and this decorator should be called with this decorator and this decorator as
well so that this function has three decorators in total
and let's see how far you get
again i have to create another function and let's call it the double
decorator and in here once more we need a function
and inside of this function i want to create a wrapper
it doesn't need any arguments again and now in here i want to call my
function twice which i just do by calling my function
twice it's very simple once it comes down to it
and once i have that i want to return the wrapper once more
oh and by the way i'm just calling this wrapper because i think it makes sense
you could call this whatever you want there's no naming restriction
and all right now what i can do i can add another decorator with the
double decorator and now if i run all of this we have to
wait a second and if i expand this
we have the code being executed once and then twice
and well this is working really nicely and here again our actual function is
really simple and we are just adding more and more stuff to it and that way
it gets more and more complex with that we have some very basic
decorators now there are some more things we can do
with them and what i want to cover for this part
is that you can have functions with parameters being decorated that part is
actually really simple and besides that decorators themselves
can also have parameters although implementing this gets even more
complicated because we are wrapping a function inside of a function inside of
another function so this we will have to explore in quite
some more detail but let's have a look at all of this
here i am back in a completely empty sheet of code and i want to create a new
function so define function and now i want to have a function
parameter it doesn't really matter what it is and
in my case i am just going to print that function parameter
and now once we have that i can call this function with whatever i want let's
say hello and if i run this i get hello a super
simple function and to decorate this
we kind of need the same thing we have done here it's not really that much more
complicated as a matter of fact let me actually copy
this decorator here and paste it in here
and now i want to decorate this function with the decorator
and just as a reminder this would be the same thing as calling
function is the decorator
with the function however now if i call this
i am getting the decorator takes zero position arguments but one was given
and this happens in this one as well as in this one
so we're getting the same error message that's usually a good sign at the very
least the problem python has is that this
function needs this parameter so when we are calling the function up here
we again need the parameter but on top of that when we call this function here
we are calling this wrapper and right now when we are calling hello we are
passing it essentially into this parameter here which doesn't exist yet
which is why python is so unhappy and to get around this we just have to
create the parameters meaning this wrapper here and this
function need the same parameters or well for
this wrapper it's a parameter for this function it's an argument
and let me name them properly here i want to have a wrapper parameter
and now if i run all of this again we should see a different error message
and that is that func is missing one required position argument func
parameter meaning
this one here and well i get this
argument from the wrapper parameter so now if i run this
we get hello and if i change this argument to something
this is still working and we could also do this the other way
the more traditional way and we will get the same outcome
and let me just go over what is happening here by using the traditional
style to make it a bit easier to explain we are again calling this decorator
function here and passing in the function itself
now inside of this decorator we are creating all of this here
and right now the wrapper has one parameter the wrapper parameter
and then inside of this wrapper function we are calling whatever code we want and
we also have the original function here and then we are passing the wrapper
parameter as an argument inside of this function
and once we have all of that at the end of the code we can just call the
function with something and then this something would be passed into the
parameter for the wrapper and then this would be passed into the
original function now what you see very often for the
rapper you don't have one specific argument instead people very often just
add arcs with a star and then double quarks
and then this you pass into whatever original function you have so if i run
this we get the same outcome and these are very simple unpacking operators this
one is for a list and this one is for dictionary or keywords
and the reason why these are used is because they allow
for this decorator to accept basically any kind of function with any kind of
parameter right now we only have one parameter but we could also have more
name parameters an unlimited amount of arguments it doesn't really matter if
you have this setup you can accept any number of arguments or named arguments
which means that this decorator works with literally any function without
limitation and all right with that we have basic
parameters what we can also do let me uncomment the
decorator let's try if this is working it does
what we can also do is create a decorator that is accepting
other arguments like a 10 for example but for that to work we need something
even more complex so let's do this in a separate file
all right and here once more we have an incredibly simple function if i call
this function we can see function and now what i want to do i want to
create another decorator and let's call this one a repetition
decorator and this one should accept one argument
by how many times i want to repeat this function here for example if i add a
five in here i want to repeat this code five times when it's being called or
rather i want to call it five times when it is being called
now for that to work we need some pretty extensive setup
and let me go through what this would look like i am first going to create the
actual decorator so repetition decorator but this one is not going to accept a
function instead it is going to accept this argument here so in my case i want
to call this the repetitions
and now inside of this i am creating another function and this
is the actual decorator and this decorator is going to accept a
function and now inside of this decorator
i want to create the actual wrapper and this one in my case has no arguments
and what i want to do is for let's call it r in
range repetitions
i want to run my function
and now what i have to do i have to inside of the decorator i want to return
the wrapper and then inside of the scope of this
repetition decorator i want to return
the actual deck curator
and now if i run this it is going to work five times and i can change this to
a 20 and we will call this function 20 times
now the question is why does this work so
let's go over it and let's do this in a traditional way
which i guess i haven't done yet but if we didn't use decorators and still
wanted to use this it would look like this
i'm still using my func variable name and now i want to call the repetition
decorator and now for this repetition decorator i
have to specify how many repetitions i want let's say 4 in this case
and after i have that i am calling whatever i get from this
and passing in my function and if i run this we get function 4
times now if you look at this this is probably
really confusing but to understand this you basically
have to understand the return statement and let's go through it one by one
first of all we are calling the repetition decorator and passing in four
that is this line of code here and this one by itself doesn't actually
do all that much all we are doing is creating a new function and returning it
so all we are getting from this repetition decorator with a 4 is this
decorator here a new function meaning this decorator here is going to
replace the entire decorator we have seen so far
and on this new decorator we are calling the new function
this one here meaning now we are passing this function
inside of here and this function is being captured inside of
this parameter
and once we have that we are basically back to a normal
so inside of this decorator we have a wrapper and this one just loops over the
range of repetitions that we get from up here
and then inside of that we are calling the function and then we are returning
the wrapper and then this wrapper is being stored
inside of the function and we can call this function
and then we are repeating it by whatever we specified in here
and well if i comment this out again and return to my decorator let's add four in
here and we still get four repetitions
and i would really recommend you to practice this in your own time although
if you're just starting don't worry too much about it just get used to functions
and classes by themselves and once you are a bit more comfortable start working
on decorators they are definitely one of the more advanced topics in python
although there is going to be another section and this is where you are
probably going to use decorators the most as a beginner and that is to use
decorators inside of classes so let's talk about decorators inside of
classes and there's one really important one it is called property
and what this allows us to do is it allows us to turn methods into
attributes and this is something we get from the property function that we can
use inside of python it actually comes with python
and i'm pretty sure all of this is going to sound really cryptic if i just
explain it theoretically so let's do all of this in code that
should be better all right here i have a completely empty python file and what i
want to do is to create a new class let's call it generic
and in here i want to create a dunder init method and this one itself and
nothing else and what i want to do in here is create
one attribute let's call it x and let's set a value for 10 it really doesn't
matter what it is and now i want to create an object from this class let's
call it generic and i just want my generic class
and now i can print generic dot x and i should get 10 and indeed i
do and now what i want to do is i want to
observe this x here meaning whenever i look at it so i retrieve the value or
when i change the value i want to run some other code and this by itself in
python isn't really that easy to do i guess what you could be doing is run
some kind of function that let's call it get x in here self
and in here i could return self.x and then besides that i could print some
other code let's say get x
and now inside of this print statement instead of x i want to get x
and don't forget to call it if i run this i get get x and the value so when i
get x i can run some other code and this is fine by itself but it's not
very elegant and again like we have seen with the
other decorators what happens if i already have a lot of
code let's say i have this generic x 10 times in my code and i don't want to
change all of these instances here i just want to change my class itself to
account for that that whenever we get x i want to run some other code and this
we can do but we need some special function in
python and this function is called property
and into this property function we can pass in a getter a setter and a
deleter and then we can assign all of this to
one attribute inside of our class let's say x right
now and then this x is what we are actually going to work with so now when
we are calling generic x this line here this x refers to this x here and then
when we are just looking at this x we are calling the getter method
when we are changing this x we are calling setter
and when we are deleting this x we are calling deleter
meaning now what you usually see with this the original attribute we have this
x here we are turning into a private method
with an underscore before it and now to python this x here and this x
are two separate variables but i as a programmer still know that
they're the same because of the naming convention here
and now basically what i'm going to do for this getter i am going to return
underscore x and with that we have a getter so this
method here is going to be this getter meaning whenever we are calling
this generic x we are calling this get a method
which is then returning this underscore x
and essentially what we are doing here outside of the class we are working with
x and this is what we are accessing but inside of the class we are using
underscore x and this is what actually keeps track of the value
and now basically what we have to do besides a getter we also need a
setter so let me change it and for the setter we need self and a new value
and when we are calling this let me run set x
and then self underscore x should be the value
and this we do not want to return and finally besides that let me copy it
one more time i want to have it deleter
this one doesn't need a value and what i want to do in here is delete
x and all we have to do for this one is to
run del and self dot underscore x and now i can run this
and let me make this a bit smaller now when i print generic x we get get x
and the value of x meaning we have run this method here
what i can also do before i'm printing x i can run
generic x is equal to 4
and now if i run this i am setting x and i'm getting x and
then i get the actual value of x and finally what i can do
i can also run delete and generic dot x and now if i run this i have set x get x
the value of x and delete x meaning now
whenever i for example get the value of x i can run
whatever other code i want and for example what i could do with
that i could import from date time that's not
how you spell that from date time import date time
and i want to know whenever i get x which i get by just printing
the date time dot now and now if i run this
i am getting the current time when i'm accessing x
and since we're just returning this underscore x you could even make changes
to whatever x you get depending on the time of day some other variables some
basically anything you want to look at which is why all of this is really
powerful and i would recommend to go over this in
your own time it's really useful but just to go over it really quickly
again i think that's going to be useful when we are initiating this class
we have underscore x this one here and this is the variable we actually
storing values in right now that is 10 but it really
doesn't matter what it is once we have that we are running this
line here and this one turns x into a property
and this property has a getter a setter and a deleter
and those are referring to this getter here this setter here
and this deleter and now from outside of the class
whenever we are accessing this x here we are running either of these methods
and these methods then influence self.x which is where we actually store
the value so this one here
and that way when we are accessing changing or deleting a value we can run
whatever code we want in there and i hope this is making sense this is
again something slightly more advanced that you probably want to practice on
your own time but what python developers also realized
is that this isn't exactly an elegant way of writing all of this
which is why this property works really well as a decorator
and let me copy the entire class to implement this as a decorator
and let me comment out all of this and basically how you would implement
all of this as a decorator for the getter
you would simply add the add property decorator
although then the getter you would rename to the name of the property which
in my case is this one here so i just want this to be x
now for the setter i want to get another decorator and this
one you would call with the name of the property in my case again x and now you
would add dot setter and then the actual method would also be
called x or the name of the property and finally
the same works for deleter so we need x dot deleter
and now the name of the method should also be the name of the property
so x in my case and now once we have that
i can get rid of this property here and now this code
does the same as this code up here meaning if i run all of this
we get the exact same result except now it's a bit easier to read i suppose
and this is something you are going to see reasonably often even as a beginner
because running some code when you're just changing a value or even when
you're just looking at the value can be really powerful
so understanding this here or at least being able to replicate it by yourself
is going to be something you do want to practice
but again this is all very advanced so if you're just learning python and all
of this is too much don't worry about it you are not going to use it for quite
some time and it would be much more valuable for
you to understand classes and functions by themselves so don't stress yourself
if this is too much but anyway this is all you need to know
to get started with decorators and i hope that was helpful
in this video we are going to cover eval and exec which are two fairly special
functions in python let's talk about them
both eval and exact are simply functions inside of python
the thing that makes them special is that both of them translate strings into
python code in practice this would look something
like this if i'm running eval
1 plus 1 this would return the operation 1 plus 1 which would give me a 2.
and notice here this one plus one originally was just a string nothing
else and with eval we are turning this string into an actual python operation
which can be incredibly powerful as a matter of fact you could even
create new variables from a string which i guess very occasionally can be
incredibly useful and while it overall gives you a ton of
flexibility however there's something really
important and that is you have to be extremely careful when
using exact or eval for the simple reason that if you handle
these functions badly it allows users to run their own code inside of your code
which if you for example run a database might end up with them stealing all of
your data for example you might have some kind of
input field and this field was originally designed to handle names from
users and then you use the eval or exec
function to update this kind of name to make sure there are no typos or
something like that a user instead of writing a name could
just add a ton of code and thereby accessing your database
and if that happens you probably are going to be in a lot of trouble
so be really careful when you're using these functions
they can end up horribly wrong but alright before we jump into code
let's talk about the difference between the two
eval is the simpler of the two functions it only evaluates code which means you
can run functions or simple operations but you cannot create new variables or
run if statements or stuff like that for that you would need exac this is the
more powerful one and it basically is capable of running
any kind of code and let's have a look at both
and let me start with eva i need to type eval and now in here i
can write any kind of simple statement for example 5 plus 10
and if i execute this we don't get anything because this only returns a
value it doesn't print it meaning i have to put all of this inside of a print
statement if i run this now we are getting 15.
and we could even run some kind of code for example what i could be doing
is create another string inside of the string
with the different quotation marks and let's call this one test
and on this test i can call the upper method and run this now and we are
getting test essentially what happens is that python just removes these quotation
marks and then runs all of this as normal python code
however there are limitations especially for eval for example what i couldn't do
is print eval if true then print
let's say test and if i run this
we are getting an error that we have invalid syntax
and the invalid syntax we are getting because if true or an if statement in
general cannot be run inside of eval
for that you would need exec if i run this now this is working just
fine and this is a more general theme that in eva we are quite limited in
terms of what we can do another example would be
i couldn't assign a new value to a variable
so in eva i couldn't do something like a equals 10
i would be getting a syntax error however if i use exec
this would work just fine and after running this code
we have a variable a meaning i can print a
and we get 10. the value of this 10 here
and that is the entire idea behind exec and eval
now most of the time especially as a beginner you are not going to use them
whatsoever because there are certainly more advanced things
however there's one good example that i think can be quite valuable
let me copy in four lines of code and i guess i can comment out the
earlier stuff what you're looking right now is i have my string and this is just
a string and on this string i'm running upper title lower and case fold
meaning if i run the code now i get all of these results
the issue here now is we have four lines of code for something
that is actually really really simple and using eval here could shorten all of
this quite substantially and this i think could actually be a really good
exercise try to express these four lines here
using an eval statement and if you want a tip this should happen
inside of a for loop try to figure this one out yourself
i first of all have to convert upper tidal lower and case volt into some kind
of string and in my case let me just copy it
it is looking like this and i want to cycle over this with a for
loop meaning i want to do for operation inside of this list
and now inside of this i want to run my eval function
and in here i need a string of my string
and on this i want to run each of these operations
and this i would do with an f string and inside of that i want curly brackets and
my operation and importantly we do want to call these
functions which means i want brackets
so for example we are starting with upper and this is
going to be inserted in here for the operation
which means we are ending up with my string dot upper and then we're adding
brackets to actually call this method and eval then basically removes the
quotation marks and turns all of this into valid python code
and the last thing we have to do is to actually print this so we can see the
result let me add the print statement and
comment out this earlier stuff and if i execute this now we get the
very same result and
this may be a bit arguable but i think this is much easier to read than these
four lines here but both approaches would be perfectly
fine and well with that we have eval and exec